<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Travel Guide</string>

    <string name="implementation_on_fragment_listener"> must implement OnFragmentInteractionListener</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="transaction_name" translatable="false">places</string>
    <string name="transaction_title_name" translatable="false">placeTitle</string>


    // Beaches Description
    <string name="beaches_gokarna_beach_desc">\tGokarna Beaches are the chief tourist attractions in the holy town of Gokarna. The name itself has been derived from Go (holy cow) and Karna (ears); hence, it has considerable mythological reverence as well.
\n\n\tPart of a largely Hindu domain, the tourists also pay homage to the famous Mahabaleswara temple, which is a renowned Shiva temple (a major Hindu deity), Maha Ganapathy temple, the Uma Maheshwari temples, and a host of other well-know temples for which this tourist spot is also famous.
\n\n\tGokarna is remotely populated with its nearest connection being Goa to its north and the city of Bangalore is located roughly around 275 miles to its east.
\n\n\tFor those looking at convenient air-travel, Dabolim in Goa is by far the nearest airport. From Dabolim, travel enthusiasts can either opt for train services or simply hire a cab to reach Gokarna in close to 4 hours.
\n\n\tOther nearby cities on international maps can be located in Madgaon also in Goa and Mangalore. For all the first timers, this tourist spot offers warm and pleasant weather conditions with an average Celsius temperature of around 30 degrees.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_karwar_beach_desc">\tKarwar, situated on the banks of river Kali, is the administrative headquarters of Uttara Kannada district in Karnataka. It is a beautiful sea side town, which is located on the Goa-Karnataka border and 519 km from Bangalore. Situated on the western coast, this scenic place is worth a visit.
\n\n\tKarwar gets it name from the word “Karwad” as the British had trouble pronouncing it during the colonial times. In 1862, British made this place their head quarters. Karwar was the sea trade center from the Arabian Sea and Arabs, Dutch, Portuguese, French and British have traded here.
\n\n\tIn Arabic, Karwar was called “Baithkhol “ meaning bay of safety. Ibn battuta passed through this tract. Many Indian commodities were exported to foreign countries were brought from the Deccan by routes as this port was considered safe during all seasons. The port of Karwar has five islands, Anjidiv, Kudumgad, Dev gad, Mogral and Shamshigudda protecting the port from heavy winds.</string>

    <string name="beaches_kaup_beach_udupi_desc">\tKaup Beach is one of the major beaches in the city of Mangalore. With its tropical climate and bevy of attractions that beckon tourists from across the country, Mangaluru is a port city that promises to keep uplifting your spirits every minute you spend in this city.
\n\n\tKaup or Kapu as the place is known in the local Tulu language is a village town located between Udupi and Mangaluru in the state of Karnataka. The region is predominantly known for one of the most serene and pristine beaches that you can find. Owing to the greenery surrounding the beach on all sides, tourists make a bee-line towards this place for a quick weekend trip away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
\n\n\tAlthough Kaup hasnt been explored on a full-fledged level, the beach attracts many tourists and there have instances of films being shot in the beach and the surrounding areas as well. Kaup beach is famously known to house an old lighthouse that was apparently built in the year 1901. The lighthouse is open for visitors during certain periods of time in the course of the day. It offers a delightful view of the entire beach and seashore that will surely take your breath away.
\n\n\tBesides the lighthouse, Kaup also has ruins of Jain Basadis that line across the stretch of sand, and these are definitely worth a visit. Kaup is the base for two Hindu temples dedicated to the Goddess Mariamman. The best time to visit Kaup Beach is from October to December.
\n\n\tThis beach is also popular with students who come from Manipal, a student town. The beach also has small shacks and eateries where one can sample a bit of the local cuisine.</string>

    <string name="beaches_malpe_beach_udupi_desc">\tMalpe Beach in Karnataka is one of the unexplored beaches in India. Located at a distance of 66 kms from Mangalore and about 6 kms from Udupi, the Malpe Beach is an undefiled virgin beach. The beach has a never-ending coastline, which is surrounded by three rocky islands on the western side. Earlier, Malpe was a port on the coast of Karnataka which is now an ideal destination for a holiday away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
\n\n\tMalpe is the first Indian beach with a 24/7 WiFi. It is also an important port and a fishing harbor in the state of Karnataka. Being the largest port in Karnataka, Malpe has a considerable population engaged in fisheries and tile manufacturing.
\n\n\tThe Malpe Beach has a pleasant weather and clean white sand which makes it ideal for a variety of water sports activities. It is a hidden treasure that lies in the State of Karnataka. The beach attracts water lovers to explore this virgin beach and indulge in some exciting activities. This beautiful beach is lined with palm trees and covered with a blue sky that provides a perfect picture for nature lovers. The beach is one of a kind, you can lie down and enjoy the sunset or indulge in the water sports activities that will set your adrenaline pumping! There are a variety of resorts and restaurants located on the beach which give you a breathtaking view and also provide a remarkable experience.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit Malpe beach is between October to January when the weather is pleasant and the skies are clear. Avoid the monsoons and the hot summer months.</string>

    <string name="beaches_om_beach_gokarna_desc">\tGokarna is famous for its beaches. The scenic beauty of the beaches encapsulated by the luscious greenery on one side bordering the western Ghats is a mind-blowing sight to watch for. The peaceful beaches are tourists delight. Every year thousands of tourists visit Gokarna for pilgrim as well as to soak themselves on these beaches.  Om beach is popular beach providing boating facilities to tourists.
\n\n\tOm Beach is shaped as two semi crescents joined together forming the shape of Om (Hindu Symbol) hence the name Om beach. Tourists can enjoy the banana boat, surfing, jet skiing etc. on this beach. The beach has a breathtaking view of the sunset.  For someone who loves the beach, Om beach is a must visit. The long stretch of white sandy beach adjoining the rocky terrain is excellent and appealing to the eyes.
\n\n\tThe beach is not always crowded yet for those who love to spend their precious lone time can find the place intimidating. The various sports and entertainment activities keep the people engaged here on the beach. The beach is perfect to indulge in parasailing, and other adventure sports to chill the vacation time.</string>

    <string name="beaches_padubidri_beach_desc">\tThe Padubidri beach is located in the Udupi district of Karnataka. This beach lies within the small town of Padubidri, which is famous for the Dakkebali ritual held once in two years.
\n\n\tA huge portion of the Padubidri population comprises of the Tuluva ethnic group.   The National Highway 17 (NH 17) passes through this little town and is situated along the Udupi –Mangalore route.
\n\n\tThe Padubidri beach is the perfect destination for the person who is looking for fun and adventure at a quiet seaside. Though not crowded like the more popular beaches along the coastline of Karnataka Padubidri beach is known for water sports and adventure rides.
\n\n\tThe beach is clean and well kept. This is also a perfect place for individuals and families who look forward to a pleasant evening watching the incredible sunset. </string>

    <string name="beaches_sasihithlu_beach_desc">\tAround 22 km away from Mangalore is the remarkable Sasihithlu Beach. It is located just two km before NITK Surathkal, Mukka. The beach has stunning white sand adding to the beauty of it and is indeed a picturesque location to admire. The blueish sea bordered with this white sand looks immensely enthralling like the Milky Way.
\n\n\tThe cool breeze and the silent waves are truly splendid and relaxing. The soothing waves caress the white sand in a calm and serene way providing a soothing relief. The island of Munda surrounded by the rivers Shambhavi and Nandini on one side and the Arabian Sea on the other side making the place an outstanding spot for tourists.
\n\n\tThe virgin beach is hidden away from the crowd making it an idyllic place to enjoy and rekindle the joy of being a kid again. Sasihithlu Bach is around 6km from Mukka on the NH 66 Road. It is adjacent to the scenic confluence of the backwaters of Shambhavi and Nandini that adds up the enchanting beauty. This stunning beach is near the Sasihithlu village and one must walk through the village and an array of acacia trees to reach the beach.
\n\n\tSasihithulu Beach is a profound location that is gearing up the publicity for hosting the Karnataka Surfing Festival and India Open of Surfing. The competition and surfing festival witness hundreds of surfers surfing and battling through the waves to win the prize money. The three-day festival is hosted on the marvelous beach with innumerable activities to witness including various live performances, food festival, kite surfing tournaments, paddle up race etc. are on the cards.  The competition is held for under 17, junior boys, senior men, and masters men.</string>


    <string name="beaches_panambur_beach_desc">\tMangalore is famous for its rugged coastline and the Western Ghats and as a historic trading center and port, Mangalore attracts many tourists who throng its beaches. One such beautiful beach is the Panambur beach.
\n\n\tLocated at a distance of just 13 kilometers from Mangalore, to the south of the Mangalore Port, Panambur beach is very accessible. The beach is named after the nearby port and it’s trade, because in the local vernacular, ‘Panam’ means money. This place is crowded during sunsets as the Konkan coast is famous for such views.
\n\n\tThe beach is often called Tanniru Bhavi and as it is adjacent to the mouth of the Gurupu River, it is very picturesque. Clean and well maintained unlike many other beaches along the Arabian Sea, Panambur Beach is very safe too, and this is why it mainly attracts tourists.
\n\n\tThere are many tourist attractions in Panambur, like camel rides and carnivals organized by the district authorities in order to entertain the visitors. The carnivals are particularly popular during the summer holidays as they help in entertaining the local children.
\n\n\tThere are boat rides and boat races, kite flying contests held during the kite festival, air shows and sand-sculpture contests that keep the holiday crowd happy and entertained.
\n\n\tThe best season to visit Panambur is between October and February, after the rains and before summer starts. Summers can be hot and humid here.
</string>


    <string name="beaches_someshwara_beach_desc">\tKarnataka has a number of beautiful beaches along its 320-km coastline. Someshwara beach is located near Mangalore, and it is a pristine beach famous for its view of sunsets. Someshwara beach is located in Ullal at the confluence of the Netravati River and the Arabian Sea. The golden sands, greenery along route from Mangalore, and the coconut palms along the beach make this beach a must-visit destination on the traveller’s itinerary.
\n\n\tSomeshwara beach is located 9 km from Mangalore city. The beach is close to Byndoor and Ullal towns.  Mangalore is well connected to the rest of India by road and rail. The nearest airport to Someshwara beach is Mangalore. Mangalore has a variety of hotels to suit every budget, and accommodation can be arranged at short notice.
\n\n\tMangalore has a hot, humid climate the year around and receives heavy rains for 4 months of the year. The best time to visit is November to February when the humidity is at tolerable levels.
\n\n\tBuses ply at regular intervals from Mangalore, Ullal, and Byndoor to the Someshwara Bus Stand. The beach is about half a kilometre from Someshwara bus stand. Autorickshaws are available from these towns and from Mangalore to Someshwara beach. The access road to the beach is rocky and it is advisable to walk down to the beach.
\n\n\tThe beach is undiscovered by tourists and therefore in a pristine condition. The endless golden sands are ideal for walking or sunbathing. Someshwara beach is famous for large rocks on the beach called Rudra Shile. During high tide, the sight of waves dashing against the rocks evokes a feeling of awe for the power of Nature.
\n\n\tTravellers to Someshwara beach can travel moderate distances to see the best beaches in Kundapur. Ullal beach, Tannirbhavi beach, Suratkhal beach, and Uchil offer views of the sea and sand to rival those at Someshwara beach.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_ullal_beach_desc">\tKarnataka, with its 320 kilometer coastline, has many popular beaches. Among the many beaches in Karnataka, Ullal Beach is arguably one of the best. Stretched out in a hue of blue and green, this beach is a prime tourist attraction of the state.
\n\n\tUllal is a fishing village and is located approximately 12 kilometers away from Mangalore on the south banks of river Nethravathi, and about 360 kilometers from Bangalore. The place has several 16th Century cathedrals and churches adorning its landscape.
\n\n\tIt is mainly the serenity and calmness of the beach that attracts tourists here. Ullal Beach is also known for its neat sea shore and tranquil beauty. The long stretch of golden sands and cool breeze adds to its beauty. It is set in about 14 acres of casuarinas groves.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit the beach is between October and February. There are several beach resorts, cottages and restaurants available in the vicinity and these can be taken up for accommodation purposes. You need to fix your stay in advance as this is a prominent tourist destination and finding the right rooms can be a problem during the last minute.
\n\n\tMangalore is well connected with major cities like Bangalore and Mumbai, so getting to Ullal is quite easy. Three highways, namely NH 17, NH 48 and NH 13 pass through Mangalore city. The nearest bus stand is just 1 km away at Ullal, and the Thokkottu bus stand lies 4 kilometers away.
\n\n\tThe Mangalore Airport-IXE lies 30 kilometers from Ullal Beach and this is the nearest airport. Mangalore is also linked to all the major cities through rail, so you can take a train to the Mangalore Central Railway Station, which is 13 kilometers away from Ullal. Taxis or cars can be arranged from Mangalore to Ullal and these will help you reach faster.
\n\n\tWhether it is the tempting sea food, water sport facilities, miles of golden sand or simply the solitude that you love, this exotic beach has it all. The unmatched tranquility and the beautiful combo of sand and the sea enthrall and beckon tourists to this beach.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_bhatkal_beach_desc">\tBhatkal beach is one of the most beautiful beaches, located near the famous Murudeshwar temple in the Uttara Kannada region. As there are many historic and important temples near the Bhatkal beach, it attracts tourists from across the country, and they mainly come to visit the beach and its nearby temples on pilgrimage. The famous Jog falls is also close by, attracting visitors in droves.
\n\n\tBhatkal, located just 60 kilometers from Mangalore, has a rich past as it was an important port for trade during the reign of the Vijayanagar Kingdom, in the 16th century. There is also a beautiful fort behind the temple which is said to have been repaired by the erstwhile Sultan of Mysore, Tipu Sultan.
\n\n\tThe beautiful Murudeshwar temple is a fine example of the architecture of the Vijayanagar Kings and attracts tourists from around the country, as a piece of the Atmalinga that was torn apart and scattered by Ravana in the Ramayana is believed to have landed here. As the temple is surrounded on three sides by the Arabian Sea, there is no dearth of sun and sand here in Bhatkal.
\n\n\tThe beach in Bhatkal is picturesque with sloping coconut trees, serene waters and crystal white sands. It is a trekker’s paradise as the rugged coastline offers plenty of trekking options to those who would like a stroll on the beach and those who would like a challenge, as the hills and hillocks along the rocky shores offer plenty of obstacles to even experienced trekkers and hikers.
\n\n\tIt is an ideal spot for a beach vacation as there are many hotels and resorts dotting the hillside and the beachfront, offering accommodation to suit any budget. The rocky slopes of the Western Ghats that slope down steeply towards the Arabian Sea present nature at its rugged, raw and beautiful best.
\n\n\tBhatkal Beach lies at a distance of just 16 kilometers from the town of Bhatkal and about 60 kilometers from Mangalore. It is well connected by rail and road and so is very accessible. The nearest airport is in Mangalore about 75 kilometers away. Other places to visit nearby are the temples at Honnavur, Shirur, Hadavalli and Kumta and the Jog falls. It lies about 500 kilometers from Bangalore.
\n\n\tThe time to visit Bhatkal Beach would be between August and March, avoiding the summers and the monsoon. Bhatkal is also famous for its fresh sea food and spicy curries and some sweets that are unique to this area. A visit to Karnataka would be incomplete without a visit to Bhatkal Beach, so take up the trip and soak in the sun.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_murudeshwar_beach_desc">\tThe Murudeshwar Beach at Mangalore is another beach with a major tourist attraction from the upcoming beaches in south India. Although it is famous mainly as a religious city that is home to the famous Murudeshwar temple, it is also acquiring an increasing number of pan India and foreign visitors with a beautiful beach in the offing.
\n\n\tThis temple is a natural wonder with aesthetically carved designs. Its other religious tourist attractions are a temple that houses the famous Pranling, which is an ancient preservation for centuries now. A few other temples, notably the Kanduka Giri, bring immense mythological value to this venue. A rather recently constructed Shiva statue near the beach stands huge at 15 meters in height, and it is another major tourist attraction.
\n\n\tThe beaches are located amidst a perfect blend of natural blue waters being lapped by a beautiful landscape of mountains and hillocks in the background. The ambience is made near perfect with the tall coconut trees, which are so common of the south Indian beaches. Other vegetation in the forms of rare areca groves brings the beauty that is restricted only to an area like Murudeshwar. The waters here are cool and bed gentle waves for swimming, but strong currents do frequent the shores during high tides.
\n\n\tThe religious mood of the place is well complimented by the active sea and its constantly splashing waters at all times of the day. Being a much sought-after tourist destination, Murudeshwar is well connected from Bhatkal and arrangements have been put in place for both intra-state tourists as well as foreign travelers. Other than the temples and natural beaches, Murudeshwar has restricted areas of interests.
\n\n\tA visit to Murudeshwar temples and beaches will gradually lead you to the third important facet – that of the simple local gourmet. The coastal lands abound in coconut and hence sweets prepared from local coconut and other flavors of rice and fish curry are sure to leave you insatiated and wanting for more. A plentiful combination of jackfruits, local mangoes, and cashews completes the list. Small temple cottages of modest comfort will be available for resting at nights.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_kurumgad_beach_desc">\tBeaches provide inspiration to every person and they are generally major tourist hotspots regardless of their location, thanks to their natural beauty. A beach that is calm and quiet can rejuvenate you when you’re down and the beach in Kurumgad is one such place where you can loosen up and lose your worries.
\n\n\tThe Kurumgad beach is just the place where nature lovers would love to go to as it sports unspoilt stretches of sand. The beauty of the beach is very much intact. Lying amidst popular destinations like Goa, Bangalore and Panaji and present in the Uttara Kannada region, quite close to the Karwar Beach, this is definitely a place to visit for those who like to relax on white sands, away from work and other common trivialities.
\n\n\tThe sight of this beach is typical of the western coastline with a numerous number of palm trees and a unique greyish sea colour. This place is sure to attract both the young and the old alike as adventurous youngsters can opt for water sports in this place while older people can opt for a calm walk along the coast.
\n\n\tThe activities that you can embark on in this poetic beach are abundant. The trip to the beach is through a boat ride from the Sadhashivgad jetty which is on the backwaters of the river Kali at Karwar. This is mainly because the Kurumgad Island, in which the beach is present, lies 4 km from the mainland and 1 km from the Devbagh Beach at Karwar.
\n\n\tThe beach is known for its other popular games including swimming in the attractive seas, fishing, and beach volleyball along the coastline, snorkelling, tidal pool and boat rides. A visit to the abandoned light house and the view from the top could be an unforgettable experience for many.
\n\n\tReaching the Kurumgad beach is simple as it is accessible by road, train and air. The nearest airports to Karwar are Goa, Belgaum and Mangalore. The nearest railway station is at Shirwad, which lies just 5 km from Karwar. It is also well connected by roads from Goa, Bangalore, Mangalore, Dandeli, Hubli and Belgaum.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit the beach would be between September and May in order to prevent getting caught during the rainy season which extends from May to September on the western coastline. Accommodations will be available in plenty as there are about 20 resorts and budget hotels in Karwar. The local cuisine here is mainly Karwari and this cuisine mainly features seafood items and other delicacies.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_surathkal_beach_desc">\tSurathkal is a quiet suburb in Mangalore. The principal claim to fame is the Surathkal Engineering College and the beach. The beach is clean and unspoilt by tourist traffic.
\n\n\tMangalore has a long stretch of shoreline with unspoilt beaches. The South Kanara district also has a legacy of educational institutions offering quality education. Surathkal, which is a suburb of Mangalore, has been lucky on both counts ‑ it boasts of a beautiful beach and also one of the best engineering colleges in India.
\n\n\tSurathkal beach is located 12 km from Mangalore city. The beach is close to the college. Mangaluru is well connected to the rest of India by road and rail. The nearest airport to Surathkal beach is Mangalore. Surathkal has only one hotel that will suit the budget traveller. It is preferable to stay in Mangalore and plan a day excursion to Surathkal. Mangalore has a variety of hotels to suit every budget and can accommodate travellers on a limited budget at short notice.
\n\n\tMangalore is located on the coast and has a hot, humid climate the year around. Monsoons are heavy and last for 4 months of the year. The best time to visit is during November‑February when the heat and humidity is tolerable.
\n\n\tBuses ply at regular intervals from Mangalore to Surathkal. Auto rickshaws are available from Mangaluru to Surathkal. Surathkal beach has a curving shoreline and has a lighthouse at the end of the beach. The lighthouse is situated on a rocky hillock and offers an uninterrupted view of the countryside and sea around. The lighthouse is open to visitors between 4.00 pm and 5 pm.
\n\n\tThe traveler should definitely stay back to see the sunset from Surathkal beach. The mornings bring in fishermen from the neighbouring hamlets that launch their fishing boats into the sea.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_maravanthe_beach_desc">\tMaravanthe Beach is located 12 km from Kundapur, which is 50 km north of Udupi and 105 km north of Mangalore; and it is a scenic beach that is a must-see for every tourist visiting Karnataka.
\n\n\tThe National Highway (NH17) passes at a close distance of 100 m from the shoreline. While traveling on the highway along the beach for a kilometer stretch, you can see the Arabian Sea on one side and the Kodachadri Hills forming a backdrop to the Sauparnika River on the other.
\n\n\tThe beach has white sandy shores covered with flora and there are plenty of private cottages and hotels, which are located on the shores. The golden sand, clear blue sky, swaying palm trees, and the endless shore provide an undoubtedly attractive tourist destination. The serene and unspoiled beach is at its best during the sunsets.
\n\n\tWater sports at Maravanthe Beach are famous and one of the favorite activities among visitors. You can laze in the sun or take a drive along the shore. You can go scuba diving and snorkeling and get a glimpse of the coral reefs and marine life that is abounded with deep-sea creatures. The water is safe for swimming as the tides are gentle. Other beach activities include beach walk, meditation, and yoga.
\n\n\tThe nearest airport is the Mangalore airport. From the airport, you can travel by bus or hire a taxi to reach the beach. The nearest railway station, Kundapur, is 18 km away, and Mangalore is at a distance of 110 km. Take a bus or hire a taxi to reach the beach. You can reach Maravanthe via Kundapur accessible by all cities of Karnataka. By road, Maravanthe Beach is 450 km from Bangalore, 130 km from Gokarna, 275 km from Goa, and 50 km from Udupi.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_tannirbhavi_beach_desc">\tThis is the perfect place for the peace and nature lover. Well, Tannirbhavi is the quietest and offbeat location that people generally fail to visit. The place has all remained desolate and has always been kept apart from other places, just because of the isolated region.
\n\n\tWell, it’s pretty safe here. If you are looking to experience a peace of mind, with the utmost serenity, then this is the righteous place that you must never afford to miss.
\n\n\tThe beach offers you an unruffled state, just enjoying the sunset in the evening. The only route to visit the beach is by road; it is quite close to Gurupura River or from the Sultan Battery.
\n\n\tTannirbhavi Beach is one of the popular beaches in the city. The coastline with golden sand and cool, fresh air is rejuvenating, and people are drawn to the natural beauty of the location. Proper seats and other facilities make the beach a frequently visited attraction, and it is crowded often on weekends and public holidays. Entering the sea is not advisable, but one can try their hand at one of the water sports at the beach. There are lifeguards to keep an eye and rescue in case of an accident, however, visitors are advised to be careful while entering the water.
\n\n\tThe beach only lately gained a lot of popularity with the installation of modern facilities like proper washrooms, parking spaces, lifeguards and several eatery stalls. A couple of concrete benches and sheds have also been installed and tall light masts are placed, for the safety and convenience of the tourists.
\n\n\tLocation: Tannirbhavi Beach, Kasba Bengre, Mangalore, Karnataka. Timings: Monday to Sunday, from 6 am to 10 pm.
</string>


    // Hill Stations Description
    <string name="hills_kudremukh_desc">\tPopular and named after a mountainside that resembles a horse face, Kudremukh is famous for its biodiversity and scenic beauty. A popular hill-station among the Bangalore crowd, Kudremukh is actually a hill range in the Chikmagalur district of Karnataka. Kudremukh Peak is a paradise for trekkers and naturists alike, with its mountainous paths and floral and faunal diversity.
\n\n\tWith its rolling meadows, grasslands and dense forests, this place is a biodiversity hotspot. Kudremukh is an enchanting place to visit, still retaining much of its natural beauty despite persistent threats from various sources to its ecology.  Varaha Parvatha, another mountain range nearby at a height of 1458m above sea level is a part of the UNESCO World Heritage Site.</string>

    <string name="hills_madikeri_desc">\tGenerally covered as a part of trips to Coorg, Madikeri is a hill town in Karnataka with vast coffee plantations, lush forests and misty hills, all culminating into a breathtaking view. Located in Kodagu District around 6 hours from Bengaluru, Madikeri is a perfect weekend getaway. There is no pollution, no noise to hurt your ears and the cool breeze that accompanies you throughout makes your trip memorable.
\n\n\tThe most famous place of Madikeri is Rajas Seat- a famous viewpoint from where you can grab all the striking beauty of Madikeri at one go. Madikeri fort and various water cascades are among the other must-visits of the place. Spend a couple of days in the beautiful homestays and Airbnb for a rejuvenating experience.
\n\n\tMadikeri, apart from being a refreshing summer retreat, is also famous for its coffee plantations, which are one of its kind in India. No wonder why Madikeri is also famous as Karnataka Coffee Capital. Renowned for its coffee plantations, this is one of the best places for coffee lovers. To get the real feel you can stay at one of the homestays situated on the coffee estates. You can also take Plantation Tours and help out in berry picking on the fields.</string>

    <string name="hills_agumbe_desc">\tLocated in the Shimoga district of Karnataka, Agumbe is a small village often referred to as the Cherrapunji of South India. This biodiversity rich region has the highest rainfall in south India and the second highest annual rainfall in India.
\n\n\tAgumbe is an enriching experience as this hill station is blessed with picturesque beauty and trekking trails. It is one of the last surviving lowland rainforests. Agumbe served as the setting for Indias very famous fictional town Malgudi in the TV serial Malgudi Days.
\n\n\tIt is home to some rare species of medicinal plants like Myristica, Listsaea, Garcinia, Diospyros, Eugenia and more, hence it got the nickname "Hasiru Honnu" which means green is gold. Being home to an extensive rainforest and the wide variety of flora and fauna, Agumbe houses the Agumbe Rainforest Research Station.
\n\n\tThis is Indias oldest weather station which exclusively monitors any changes made in the rainforest areas. Interestingly, Agumbe is also called as the "Cobra Capital" because of the high number of Cobras found here. Agumbe provides great options for trekking, beckoning the adventure enthusiasts to visit this offbeat destination hidden in the lap of nature.</string>

    <string name="hills_nandhi_hills_desc">\tLocated around 60 kilometres away from Bangalore, Nandi Hills is one such tourist spot that has gradually been discovered by visitors over the years and has now become a well-known weekend getaway.
\n\n\tFeaturing beautifully carved arches and majestic pillars with intricately painted walls and ceilings, Nandi Hills is scattered with shrines and monument and is surrounded by mesmerizing views, making this place no less than a hidden paradise.
\n\n\tSituated at a height of 4851 feet above sea level, you can see a convoy of weekenders from Bangalore during early hours catching the glimpse of sunrise.</string>

    <string name="hills_shivagange_hills_desc">\tShivagange, a hillock situated 56 km from Bangalore, is a combination of temples and scenic beauty that makes it both a pilgrimage as well as an adventure spot. From a distance, the hillock looks like a Shiva Linga, with a spring flowing nearby thats locally called Ganga, thereby naming it Shivaganga.
\n\n\tIt is also given the name Dakshina Kashi (Kashi of the south) since its home to various temples (Gangadhareshwara temple, Olakala Teertha, Nandi Statue, Patala Gange, etc.) The stone carving of Nandi ( the bull) is another primary attraction.
\n\n\tThe hilly feature of the place attracts a lot of adventure sports seekers, providing them opportunities for trekking and rock climbing. All in all, it is a popular getaway for travellers with both religious and adventurous inclinations</string>

    <string name="hills_savandurga_hills_desc">\tSituated 60 kms to the west of Bangalore, Savandurga, considered to be one of the largest single rock formations in the whole of Asia. It comprises of two hills, Billigudda (white hill) and Karigudda (black hill) and has a temple situated at the foothill and a pond nearby. Most trekkers choose Billigudda due to its gentler slopes. The weekend travellers from Bangalore frequent it for trekking, camping and rock climbing.
\n\n\tArkavathi River flows nearby and moves towards Manchanabele Dam. Savandurga hills make for a tranquil and picturesque trek and overlook a beautiful lotus pond. Its one of the top places for slab climbing in the world and a lot of climbers and adventure seekers visit here often.
\n\n\tAnother popular activity here is bird watching. The avifauna here is magnificent and enthusiasts can spot the endangered yellow-throated bulbuls. Leopards and sloth bears are also spotted here.</string>

    <string name="hills_yana_desc">\tDo you fancy visiting a village that is full of green? If the answer is a yes, Yana is the place to be. Lush green backdrops, beautiful hillocks and dense forests, the place has all that a nature lover could ask for. Call it a hill station or a village, Yana is situated within the Kumta forest of the Uttar Kannada district of Karnataka. It is known for its unique karst rock formation. These laterite rocks are the ones that challenge the adventurous traveler.
\n\n\tAs per Hindu mythology, the place is closely associated with the legend of the demon king Bhasmasura. The king had been granted a boon by Lord Shiva that he could turn anyone into ashes or bhasma by placing his hand over their head. He wanted to try this on Lord Shiva himself.
\n\n\tSeeking help from Lord Vishnu to stop this act, Vishnu disguised himself into Mohini, a beautiful young lady who mesmerized the demon king by her beauty and challenged him for a dance. During the dance, she cleverly posed with her hand on her head. The king copied the step and ended up getting reduced to ashes.
\n\n\tThe rocky landscape, to be precise, lies well within the beautiful Sahyadri mountain range of the well-known Western Ghats. The rocks of the village that were earlier a tough trek now comprise of relatively well-laid roads to take you up. To the adventurous soul, this place serves as the perfect trekking spot with lesser tourists than popular spots. Although the number of tourists visiting has been increasing each year, it still retains the peace and calm of its surroundings.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport is Goa International Airport, which is about 210 kilometres away. The next one is in Hubli. Bangalore’s Kempegowda International Airport is around 480 kilometres away.
\n\n\tBy Rail: If you want to reach Yana by rail, there is no railway station at Yana. However, there are some stations in the vicinity. Board the trains at Kumta Railway Station, Ankola Railway Station or Harwada Railway Station. The main and biggest one is Madgaon Railway Station which is 112 kilometeres away.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you want to take to the road, try reaching Yana from nearby towns like Ankola and Kumta.
</string>

    <string name="hills_siddara_betta_desc">\tSiddara Betta is one of the most visited places near Madhugiri. Surrounded by rocky hills, temples and caves, the tourist place is located at a distance of 100 kms from Bangalore in Tumkur. This place is most visited by trekkers and adventurers as well as pilgrims who come to Siddara Betta for the Shrine of Lord Shiva which is placed inside the caves.
\n\n\tThe majority of tourists visiting Siddara Betta are pilgrims who come to see the Shrine of Lord Shiva. The place is also known for the high medicinal value of its herbs. Siddara Betta in Kannada means ‘Hill of Saints’, it is so called because, in older days, many Hindu Saints performed penance and meditation here. Although it is no more in practice, currently there is an Ashram situated at the base of the hill and Saints do visit there.
\n\n\tThere are man-made stones which cover the entire way up to the hill, which makes it an easy climb for trekkers. It is surrounded by lush greenery and is extremely picturesque once you reach the top. Siddara Betta is a famous trek location for adventure enthusiasts. The rocky terrain and caves add to the thrilling trek experience. The path of the trek includes caves and many uneven boulders. Although the trek up to the temple is pretty easy.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport is Bangalore, which is at a distance of 100 kms. From here one can reach the Betta by road.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Bangalore is connected with a railway line with most cities. From Bangalore, you will have to take the road to Siddara Betta.
\n\n\tBy Road: The place has a well-connected road network. It is closer to Tumkur and can be reached by taking the Bangalore Pune highway. Buses operate up to Koratagere and Siddara Betta is only 12 kms from there.
</string>

    <string name="hills_coorg_desc">\tSet amidst the beauty and tranquillity of hills, vegetation, and deep valleys, Coorg is a perfect getaway from the hustle and bustle of city life. The area is spread over 4102 sq km. The place is also called Kodagu. It has an abundance of opportunities to make your holidays enjoyable and also have a calming effect on you.
\n\n\tThe place started to gain importance back in the 2nd and 6th century, when it’s northern part was controlled by the Kadambas from Goa. Kodagu witnessed a terrible war in the 11th century, fought between the Kadambas and the Gangas. Over the next few centuries, the place came under the control of different dynasties like the Hoysalas, the Cholas and also the Vijayanagara Empire. It was in 1956 that the place was declared as a district and it became a part of Karnataka.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest domestic airport is Mangalore, located 160 km away. Bangalore is 265 km away from the district and it is better to travel from Bangalore to Mangaluru and from there to Coorg.
\n\n\tBy Rail: While the place doesn’t enjoy good railway connectivity, there are closest stations to it like Mangalore, Hassan and Mysore. Mysuru is 95 km away. Hubli to Coorg railway distance is 344 km. Bangalore has a distance of 247 km.
\n\n\tBy Road: There are buses that take you to Coorg from major cities like Bangalore and Mysore. Mysuru has road distance of 130 km from the district of Coorg. You can also hire cabs if travelling with family.
</string>

    <string name="hills_brahmagiri_hill_desc">\tDo you have a long weekend coming up and want to head out somewhere, but don’t know where? How about going trekking on Brahmagiri hill and falling right into the lap of Mother Nature?
\n\n\tThe sanctuary derives its name from the highest point, the Brahmagiri peak, which is 1607 m in height. It covers an area of about 181 Kms.
\n\n\tBrahmagiri, at 1608 m above sea level, is a hill range on the Western Ghats bordering Kerala and Karnataka. It is situated on the border between Wyanad District of Kerala state on the south and Kodagu District in Karnataka on the north side.
\n\n\tDecember to February is the best time to visit the hill and one should avoid the monsoon. The hill is at an approximate distance of 270 km from Bangalore. If you’re trekking from Kerala, you have to begin at Thirunelli and whilst trekking from Karnataka, you have to begin from Iruppu falls. Permission from the Thirunelli Forest Range Officer and Srimangala Forest Range Officer has to be taken while trekking. The nearest towns to Brahmagiri hill are Kutta, Srimangala and Gonikkoppal. Taking a guide along is compulsory and his charges will range around INR 200.
\n\n\tThe top of Brahmagiri Hill  is well forested and has a lot of wildlife. Mammals in the Sanctuary include Lion-tailed Macaque, Elephant, Gaur, Tiger, Jungle Cat, Leopard Cat, Wild Dog, Sloth Bear, Wild Pig, Sambar, Spotted Deer, Nilgiri Langur, Slender Loris, Bonnet Macaque, Common Langur, Barking Deer, Mouse Deer, Malabar Giant Squirrel, Giant Flying Squirrel, Nilgiri Marten, Common Otter, Brown Mongoose, Civets, Porcupine, Pangolin.
\n\n\tFrom Bangalore via bus: KSRTC bus service provides several options to go to Gonikkoppal. From Gonikkoppal, you can select from a host of bus services to reach Srimangala. KSRTC services only one Rajahamsa bus to Srimangala from Bangalore. From Srimangala, you will have to travel 10 km before reaching Iruppu falls from where your trekking journey will begin.
\n\n\tFrom Bangalore by car: Drive through Mysore Road to reach Srirangapatna. After driving for a while, take a deviation from Hunsur and proceed to Gonikkoppal. On the way to Gonikkoppal, you will have to take another deviation towards Nagarhole/Srimangala/Iruppu. Past Ponnampet, Hudikeri and Shettigiri, you will reach Srimangala from where you have to head towards Iruppu and begin your trek.
\n\n\tFrom Kerala by bus: Reach Kutta and take a Kerala SRTC bus to get to Kattikulam. From Kattikulam you can take a private bus or a Kerala SRTC bus to Thirunelli from where your trek can commence.
</string>

    <string name="hills_charmadi_ghat_desc">\tCharmadi Ghat trek is a dream come true. Charmadi is a beautiful region within the Chikmagalur district of Karnataka. It is known for its picturesque views and scenic landscapes owing to its location in the Western Ghats. Trekking is a pleasure at the terrain of Charmadi that is home to lush forests, evergreen shrubs, streams, and waterfalls. Easily approachable by major cities, it qualifies as one of the best weekend trek getaways.
\n\n\tCharmadi Ghat trek is all about being amidst a lush nature trail. However, owing to the misty atmosphere and little or more rains (during the monsoon months), it is advisable to start the trek early and wind up before nightfall. Trekking at Charmadi Ghat is a trekker’s dream come true. It has trails that are doable by both amateur and higher level trekkers. The best way to go about trekking here would be to take the help of a guide. If you are a skilled trekker, you could take up the climbs leading to either one of the peaks – Ballekallu and Kodekallu. Stay the night at a campsite or forest department guesthouse.
\n\n\tHead to the various coffee estates found within Charmadi Ghat trek. You could even stay over if you check in advance. These estates provide a comfortable homestay-like environment and help you imbibe the aromas of the coffee plantations all around.
\n\n\tBy Air: The closest airport to Charmadi Ghat is Mangalore Airport, which is about 87 kilometres and Kempegowda International Airport is roughly 300 kilometres.
\n\n\tBy Train: You can board a train from the closest Railway Stations of Mangalore, Bangalore, and Hassan.
\n\n\tBy Road: To reach the Ghats by road, board the buses plying to Dharmasthala. The trek spot is just 10 kilometres from there.
</string>

    <string name="hills_ramanagara_hills_desc">\tRamanagara as we know it today would probably never have the same appeal if Sholay was not shot there. The film was iconic and the iconic status rubbed off on Ramanagaraor Ramgarh as it is known in the film.
\n\n\tSholay was not, however, the first film that showcased the earthy appeal of the area. David Lean’s film, “A Passage to India” put the rough-hewn boulders in the limelight with small door-like grottoes to make them look like caves. Whether being in a legendary movie’s shooting locale appeals to you or not, there is a lot more that the picturesque locale has to offer.
\n\n\tThe hilly landscape and the wide open spaces of relatively untouched nature makes Ramanagara a beautiful escape from the hustle and bustle of the concrete jungle we live in. Yatirajagiri, Shivaramagiri, Somagiri, Revannasiddeshwara Betta, Krishnagiri, Sidilakallu Betta and Jalasiddeshawara Betta are the seven major hills in Ramanagara.
\n\n\tSome of the earliest rock climbing efforts in South India were concentrated around this area. The compact hills and seemingly vertical rock faces make for great technical climbs. With bolts put in by local climbers, climbing should not be too challenging.
\n\n\tRamanagara gets its name from Ramagiri Hills or Ramadevara Betta. Along with Ramadevara Betta there are other hills Rama Siddeshwara betta, Shivar-amagiri, Kaakasura Betta, Kapotagiri, this hill resembles a lingam when viewed from the east, Ganesha from the west, a serpent from the north and Lord Hanuman from the south.
\n\n\tBy air: The nearest international airport is the Bengaluru International airport which has been recently renamed as the Kempegowda International airport. The Mysore Airport is a smaller airport with flights between Mysore and Bangalore and Chennai. The Mysore airport is also known as the Mandakalli airport.
\n\n\tBy road: Ramanagara is located approximately 50 kilometers south west of Bangalore. The newly carved out district of Ramanagara is well connected to Bangalore and Mysore via the six lane expressway between the two cities. Government and private buses regularly ply tourists and locals between Ramanagara, Bangalore and Mysore. Taxis and rental cars are also readily available.
\n\n\tBy rail: Ramanagara is well connected to the rest of South India by the Railway network system. Just like the highway connection, the railways also connect Ramanagara to Bangalore and Mysore. Autos, taxis and buses are easily available from the railway station in Ramanagara.
</string>

    <string name="hills_sharavathi_valley_desc">\tSharavathi Valley Trek – only a true adventure enthusiast can appreciate it. Sharavathi Valley forms a beautiful part of the Western Ghats. To be precise, it lies in the Shimoga district of Karnataka. The ecological scape is no short of a paradise on earth. Gorgeous waterfalls and streams form a part of the evergreen valley as it is lined by deciduous trees. Its backwaters have led to the formation of different islands.
\n\n\tIt is equally rich in its fauna and tigers, spotted deer, sloth bear, jackals, the endangered lion-tailed macaque, king cobra, pythons and wild pigs are found amongst many others. The months of October through February should work out to be the best, with the temperatures maxing out in the month of April.
\n\n\tSharavathi Valley gets its name from its river’s place of origin. River Sharavathi originated in Ambutheertha of the Thirthahalli taluk. Legend has it that Lord Ram used his Ambu or bow and shara or arrow to shoot at the ground, as his wife, Sita, was thirsty. Due to the impact, water oozed out of the ground, also referred to as thirtha, and quenched Sita’s thirst. The 128-kilometre long river forms the famous Jog Falls along the way and joins the Arabian Sea at the Honnavar region.
\n\n\tBy Air: The closest airport to this place is Kempegowda International Airport, which is about 350 kilometers away. The next closest one is Mangalore Airport which is around 140 kilometres approximately.
\n\n\tBy Rail: To reach Sharavathi Valley by rail, you can hop onto the train at Bangalore Railway Station or Mangalore Railway Station.
\n\n\tBy Road: Driving down from Bangalore would be a good idea via Sagar. The other option is to take a bus till Sagar. Once you reach Sagar, Gubbagodu is just 20 odd kilometers from there.
</string>

    <string name="hills_mullayanagiri_desc">\tChikmagalur district in Karnataka has many peaks appropriate for trekking. The Western Ghats extend to form the Baba BudanGiri range. Mullayanagiri at 1,930 m above sea level is the highest peak in this range and falls in Chikmagalur district.
\n\n\tChikmagalur is famous for its coffee estates. The entire area receives very heavy rainfall, making the trekking routes extremely difficult to traverse in the monsoons. The winters are severe with frequent mists reducing visibility along the treacherous inclines. The best period to go trekking in Chikmagalur is between September and February.
\n\n\tChikmagalur is around 280 km from Bangalore by road. The base for the trek, Sarpadhari, is further 15 km away. The entire trek is around 5 km and should take about 4 hours.
\n\n\tChikmagalur is well connected to Bangalore by road. While traveling in a group, it is advisable to book bus tickets and accommodation in advance. Chikmagalur has hotels providing modest facilities for the traveler on a budget.
\n\n\tAn overnight journey brings the trekker to Chikmagalur in the early hours of the morning. Buses ply after 8.00 am from Chikmagalur to Sarpadhari. The road runs amidst coffee estates and dense forests for about half an hour. Sarpadhari is a small hamlet from where a well-trodden path takes one to the peak. ‘Sarpadhari’ means serpentine path, and it is indicative of the arduous nature of the trek.
\n\n\tAbout halfway up the hill, there is a cave. The walls of this cave are multi coloured due to mineral deposits. The cave runs a good distance into the mountain and is infested with bats. The trek continues further up the hill. An ancient Shiva temple perches atop the peak. The view from the peak is breathtaking
</string>

    <string name="hills_kumara_parvatha_desc">\tThe Western Ghats is full of beautiful hills and mountains to trek on. While some of them are easy to moderate, the others are challenging. One such adventurous trail lies in Coorg. The Kumara Parvatha Trek is believed to be tough. Home to lush vegetation, it exposes the Pushpagiri range of the Western Ghats. At 1,712 metres, Kumara Parvatha is clearly a high peak and ranks number six in Karnataka.
\n\n\tThe best months to trek here are between October to January and June to September. The trek unfurls scenic landscapes as you tread up. Gear up for a tiring trek and get ready to take a mix of both moderate and difficult trails. There are two routes to take.
\n\n\tThe starting point of this 16-kilometre stretch could be Bidalli from the Somwarpet region or Subramanya from the South Kannada side. It is a moderately steep trek. Although some parts are muddy, the path is well marked with signage.
\n\n\tLeeches are commonly encountered here, thus, it is advisable to stay weary of them and check your socks regularly. As you begin the trek, you will reach a dense forest. On crossing this, the twin peaks of Shesha Parvatha and Marigundi will reveal themselves.
\n\n\tCamping is something that cannot be done at the Parvatha. As an alternate, you can camp at the forest department office or mantapa nearby. Booking to stay at Bhatru Mane can be made in advance. Sunset points lie close to it and can easily be accessed from the spot. After a long trek, the next stop for you to rest will be at Kallu Mantapa. To put it simply, the trail follows the route from Shesha Parvatha to Kumara Parvatha. The best way to go about it would be to get all camping and trekking permissions in advance, and having booking for the night halt made earlier.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport to Kumara Parvatha is Mangalore Airport, which is about 155 kilometres away and is the best way to reach there. The second closest is Kempegowda International Airport which lies approximately 272 kilometres.
\n\n\tBy Train: If you plan to board a train, you can take the one at Mysore Railway Station or Hassan Railway Station as these are the closest to the Parvatha. Besides that, Bangalore Railway Station has trains reaching close to Kumara Parvatha. From there, you can take a cab to reach the Parvatha.
\n\n\tBy Road: Drive down from Hassan, Mysore, Mangalore or Bangalore or simply hop onto the buses plying regularly from these bus stations to Pushpagiri Wildlife Sanctuary.
</string>

    <string name="hills_kodachadri_desc">\tA hill called Kodachadri in the district of Shimoga is a lesser known trekking destination. This peak in the Western Ghats winds through thick forests and is the natural habitat of a variety of wildlife.
\n\n\tKodachadri is a mountain peak in Shimoga District that has an altitude of 1343 m above the mean sea level. It is situated near the Mookambika National Park, and it is the natural habitat of the Malabar Giant Squirrel, the Malabar Langur, the Emerald Pigeon, Bison, Tiger, King Cobra, and Python.
\n\n\tKollur, which is located near Kodachadri, is an ideal spot from where you can reach the hill. You can reach Kollur from Bangalore or from Shimoga. From Kollur, trekkers can travel to Nagodi village, which is at the base of the peak. An alternate route is to travel overnight to Nittur. The trek is a 12-km route from Nittur from Kodachadri gate.
\n\n\tThe trek takes 8-10 hours to complete and should be undertaken only by experienced trekkers with fitness levels at their peak. The best time to undertake this trek during the October-February time period.
\n\n\tIt is believed that Adi Shankaracharya meditated on Kodachadri peak. To commemorate this, the Sarvagna Peeth is located at the site. The Kodachadri trek is possibly the toughest of popular treks in Karnataka but the view from the peak makes the effort worthwhile. A cover of verdant jungle stretches in all directions, and on a clear day, one can catch a glimpse of the azure Arabian Sea from the top. The view of the sunset and sunrise from the peak is breathtaking.
\n\n\tThe route also passes by Lingamanakki reservoir and the Arishinagundi falls. Hidlumane Waterfalls are a further 10 km away and can be reached on foot. It is advisable to take the help of a local guide to reach the falls.
</string>

    // Monuments Description
    <string name="monumnets_gol_gumbaz_desc">\tThe erstwhile capital of the Adil Shahi dynasty, Bijapur or Vijaypur remains as quaint with Gol Gumbaz gazing at the sky as the echoes of its timelessness reverberate through the air. The resting place of Mohammed Adil Shah and his wives, mistress, daughter and grandson, Gol Gumbaz is among the greatest examples of the Adil Shahi architecture with one of the biggest domes in the world.
\n\n\tBuilt in 1656 it took 30 years to complete the construction of Gol Gumbaz. The mausoleum was designed by Yaqut of Dabul. Situated in the northern Karnataka, Gol Gumbaz marks the splendour of Adil Shahi rule in the Southern India. The seventh ruler of the Adil Shahi empire, Mohammed Adil Shah started the construction of the tomb right after he became the Sultan in 1626. He wanted the mausoleum to be bigger and grander compared to the memorial of his father, Ibrahim Adil Shah. Although the construction of Gol Gumbaz started during the reign of Mohammed Adil, it got disrupted due to the sudden demise of the Sultan.
\n\n\tStyled on the Dravidian architecture amalgamating the Islamic influences, the very name Gol Gumbaz stems from ‘Gola Gombadh or Gol Gomata translating to a circular dome. Made of dark grey basalt stone, its chamber is among the biggest in the world measuring 18,000 sq ft and the whispering gallery allowing people to hear their most hushed tones courtesy the acoustics of the space. It is said that you can hear a word echo for about 12 times across the other end of the dome. The 144 ft high roof with a 156 ft cube on either side beneath has eight arches traversing the two squares interlocking together that work as the base for the dome. There are four octagonal towers placed at each corner comprising a staircase. And each tower has a gallery on the top floor. The podium sits pretty in the centre hall with steps on the two sides.
\n\n\tThe precinct of Gol Gumbaz comprises a mosque, garden, tavern and a museum. A cenotaph graces the podium in the middle separating the main grave underneath. The entrance to the mausoleum will greet you with a piece of meteorite which is said to have been fallen during the rule of Sultan and is believed to safeguard the tomb from lightning.
\n\n\tGol Gumbaz Situated in Bijapur in Karnataka, it takes around 10 hours to reach Gol Gumbaz from the capital city, Bangalore. Hampi is 214 km from Bijapur while Badami is 122 km. Bijapur has no airport and to visit Gol Gumbaz you will have to get down at the Belgaum Airport which is 200 km from the site. Or you could take a Bangalore to Bijapur train which will be a journey of 668 km.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_mysore_palace_desc">\tThe history of Mysore palace goes back to 14th century when the first structure was laid out. It is said that the very first Mysore Palace of Wodeyars, royal family of Mysore, was built with wood which unfortunately was struck by lightning in the year of 1638. Hence, a new palace with many added features, extensive pavilions and buildings was built reconstructed by Kantirava Narasaraja Wodeyar.
\n\n\tThe present building of Mysore Palace was completed in 1912. Mysore Palace mesmerizes everyone with its magnificent architecture. Known as Indo-Saracenic, a beautiful blend of Hindu, Islamic, Rajput, and Gothic architectural style which the palace represents has been alluring watchers since time immemorial.
\n\n\tPrivate Durbar (Ambavilasa Palace) is another place to see at Mysore Palace. Used by the Kings for private meetings, it also presents a spectacular architectural beauty with mesmerizing interiors. Beautifully carved rosewood doorway ornamented with ivory, hall decorated with stained glass ceilings, golden columns, captivating chandeliers with floral motifs, pietra dura mosaic floor makes this one of the most beautiful rooms of the palace.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_vidhana_soudha_desc">\tInfluenced by the House of Commons in London, the Vidhana Soudha is spread over 60 acres of land. It is popularly known as the building that houses the State Legislature Assembly and the Secretariat of Karnataka. The foundation stone of Vidhana Soudha was laid down by the first Prime Minister of India, Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru, in 1951.
\n\n\tIt has been described by many dignitaries in many different ways over the years. Inaugurated on October 10, 1956, Vidhana Soudha is the original seat of power in the state of Karnataka. The construction of such a building was due to the immense amount of nationalist sentiments that were growing amongst people soon after India gained its independence. During that time, the administrative offices were based out of Attara Kacheri, built by the British in 1868.
\n\n\tIt is due to this that plans were made for Indias own structure of legislature. However, the plan was mooted during K.C. Reddys tenure, who was the first Chief Minister of Karnataka. Regardless, soon after that, Nehru laid its foundation stone down, followed by Hanumanthaiah, who completed the construction of the Vidhana Soudha.
\n\n\tHanumanthaiah was Reddys successor and wanted to shed light to the nationalist sentiments. And so, he asked B.R. Manickram, the chief architect of the project to build the structure right opposite to the Attara Kacheri, that too at a slight elevation. Ultimately, the house of the legislature and secretariat was built, spreading over 5,00,000 square feet, with a total cost of INR 1.84 crore at that time.
\n\n\tVidhana Soudha is located around 34.8 kilometres from the Bangalore Airport. The best way to reach this iconic structure from the airport is by taking the public bus service by BMTC to Ulsoor, which takes around an hour and a half. This is also the cheapest mode of transportation to Vidhana Soudha from the airport.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_philomena_church_desc">\tWith the fame of being one of the largest churches in India, this majestic church captivates everyone with its architectural excellence. It also boasts of being the second largest church in Asia. Dedicated to Saint Philomena, St. Philomenas Church is not only known for its architectural beauty and religious significance; it stands as an exemplary of secular viewpoint and the religious harmony which existed in Mysore. This can be seen from the fact that this church was built by Mysore ruler for the European residents in the city.
\n\n\tBuilt in 1840, earlier it used to be called as the St. Joseph Chavez, which was later changed to its present name. Initially a small church, it gained its present form in 1933 during the reign of Maharaja Krishnaraja Wodeyar IV. In 1843, Mysore King Mummadi Krishnaraja Wodeyar built the church so as to cater to the needs of the European people who were residing in Mysore then. However, with the increase in the number of European residents in the city a need for bigger church aroused.
\n\n\tYou can visit the church till 6 in evening as the timings of St. Philomenas Church are from 05.00 am to 06.00 pm. It is always better to visit in evening as then you can watch the church is being illuminated. Every Sunday and on festival, special masses are organised while everyday masses are conducted in morning and evenings. On 11th August, annual feast is organised at the church.Photography is not allowed inside the church hall.
\n\n\tThis church is situated about 2 km away from the Mysore Palace. Quite close to the city bus stand with a distance of only 3 km between them and hence St. Philomenas Church is easily accessible. Located on the Ashoka Road of Mysore, it can be easily accessed by road. Tourists can either hire a taxi or just take an auto rickshaw to the church.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_mena_basadi_desc">\tThe Badami cave temples are a complex of Hindu and Jain cave temples located in Badami, a town in the Bagalkot district in northern part of Karnataka, India. The caves are important examples of Indian rock-cut architecture, especially Badami Chalukya architecture, and the earliest date from the 6th century. Badami was previously known as Vataapi Badami, the capital of the early Chalukya dynasty, which ruled much of Karnataka from the 6th to the 8th century. Badami is situated on the west bank of a man-made lake ringed by an earthen wall with stone steps it is surrounded on the north and south by forts built in later times.
\n\n\tThe Badami cave temples represent some of the earliest known examples of Hindu temples in the Deccan region. They along with the temples in Aihole transformed the Malaprabha River valley into a cradle of temple architecture that influenced the components of later Hindu temples elsewhere in India.
\n\n\tBadami, also referred to as Vatapi, Vatapipura, Vatapinagari and Agastya Tirtha in historical texts, the capital of Chalukya dynasty in the 6th century, is at the exit point of a ravine between two steep mountain cliffs. Four cave temples in the escarpment of the hill to the south-east of the town were carved into the cliffs monolithic stone face. The escarpment is above a man-made lake called Agastya Teertha, created by an earthen dam faced with stone steps. To the west end of this cliff, at its lowest point, is the first cave temple.The largest and highest cave is Cave 3, which is further to the east on the northern face of the hill.The fourth cave, Cave 4, is a few steps down further east.
\n\n\tThe Badami cave temples are located in the town of Badami in the north-central part of Karnataka, India. The temples are about 88 miles (142 km) east of Belagavi, and 87 miles (140 km) northwest of Hampi. The Malaprabha River is 3 miles (4.8 km) away. The cave temples are 14 miles (23 km) from the UNESCO world heritage site Pattadakal and 22 miles (35 km) from Aihole – another site with over a hundred ancient and early medieval era Hindu, Jain and Buddhist monuments.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_bidar_fort_desc">\tAmongst the most formidable forts of the country, it is situated in the eastern part of the town and has within it ruins of palaces, mosques and other buildings which had been built of trap rock. Stone and mortar were used to build the fort-walls. The fort is entered from the south-east by a zigzag passage protected by three gateways. The entrance gate has a lofty dome, the interior of which had been painted in bright colours.
\n\n\tBidar was the capital of Bahmani Kingdom in the 14th century. Bidar fort was built by Ahmad Shah Wali Bahman. Bidar Fort was renovated in the 15th century by Sultan Ahmad Shah-I as he shifted his capital from Kalaburagi (Gulbarga) to Bidar.
\n\n\tBidar Fort is open daily from 9 AM till 5 PM.During summer peak temperatures in Bidar may reach upwards of 40 degree Celsius. Plan your visit with adequate water, an umbrella for cover and sunscreen.
\n\n\tBidar Fort is 700 kms from Bengaluru. Recently opened Bidar Airport is the closest airport (11 kms from Bidar Fort) which has once a day flight from Bengaluru. Hyderabad airport is the next best option, 150 kms from Bidar. Bidar city railway station is 3 kms from Bidar Fort. Buses and trains are available from Bengaluru to reach Bidar.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_saavira_kambada_basadi_desc">\tSaavira Kambada Basadi is a magnificent thousand pillar temple at Moodabidri. The temple town is also popularly known as Jain Kashi’ of India since it is dotted with many Jain temples. Let’s find out more about Saavira Kambada Basadi.
\n\n\tKarnataka has a vibrant cultural heritage, encompassed in its beautiful temples and breathtaking towns. One of these heritage cities in Moodabidri, a temple town has a curious connection with the number 18 – it houses 18 temples, with 18 roads that connect the different villages in the vicinity, adorned with 18 lakes, and also the home to 18 Jain Basadis.
\n\n\tThe town, which is located around 37 kilometres away from Mangalore, gets its name from the abundance of bamboo cultivation in the area. In Kannada, ‘Mooda’ means east while ‘Bidri’ means bamboo.
\n\n\tSaavira Kambada Basadi is known for its magnificent pillars that are the hallmarks of this ancient place of worship. The temple is also called Tribhuvana Tilaka Chudamani Basadi which means the ‘crown jewel of the three worlds’.
\n\n\tWhile the temple was first designed in the year 1430 by the then local chief Devaraya Wodeyar the current design was introduced in the year 1962. The construction took around 31 years to get completed, and the result is the beautiful structure that we see today.
\n\n\tBy Air: At a distance of 37 km, Mangalore is the nearest airport to Moodabidri. Tourists from far off places can land at Mangalore airport and avail the many taxi services to travel to Moodabidri.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The closest railway station is Mangalore and has a lot of trains to and from different cities.
\n\n\tBy Road: There are bus and taxi services available from major cities Bangalore, Mangalore, Udupi, etc., which can be availed by tourists to visit the temple town.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_bangalore_palace_desc">\tA hub of posh boutiques, enterprising micro-breweries and sprawling tech parks, Bangalore is also a city with many personalities, shaped over time due to its multi-layered history. Folks who seek to experience the classic royal charm of Bangalore can head over to one of its older landmarks, the sprawling Tudor-inspired estate of Bangalore Palace. The palace was built in the year 1887 by King Chamaraja Wadiyar and is today open to the public who come to witness the lavish and elegant splendour of one of South India’s most enduring dynasties.
\n\n\tThe area where the palace is now located originally belonged to Reverend J Garrett, who was a school principal in the cantonment town.  It was purchased in 1873 by the guardians of Chamaraja Wadiyar and construction began in 1874. John Cameron, the person behind Lalbagh was enrolled for the landscaping of the palace and surrounding areas. Initial construction was completed in 1878 and subsequent additions and renovations have been carried out since.
\n\n\tThe palace features mainly wooden interiors and is surrounded by gardens. The architectural style is a mix of Tudor and Scottish Gothic with many physical elements inside imported from Britain. It is believed that Chamaraja Wadiyar found inspiration in Windsor Castle and other structures of Normandy and England.
\n\n\tSome of the defining features of the two-level granite structure include the fortified towers and the turreted parapets, quintessential elements of Tudor buildings. Roman arches greet visitors at the entrance. The facade of the building boasts many different shapes and projections. The vine -covered walls make the palace look like it was lifted out of the English countryside.
\n\n\tBy Air: The drive to the palace from the nearest airport, the Bangalore International Airport, should take an hour, via Bellary Road covering around 30 kilometres.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The closest railway station to the palace is the Bangalore City Railway station. It is just 4 kilometres away and the journey would take around 20 minutes with regular traffic.
\n\n\tBy Road : Bangalore Palace is in the Vasanthnagar area of the city and the main roads around the grounds are the Palace Cross Road, Bellary Road and Sankey Road. Mekhri Circle is one of the major intersections near the Bangalore Palace. There are many bus routes that ply around this area. The area is commonly referred to as Palace Grounds and some of the BMTC buses which ply out of the central bus terminal include 287, 287B, 287C, 287D and 287E. Auto-rickshaws and private cabs are also easily available.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_stone_chariot_hampi_desc">\tEvery tourist place has that one spot which earns it galore and admiration. For Hampi, the small, dainty temple village set in Karnataka, it’s the iconic stone chariot. It’s the leading man in the army of exquisite beautiful sights that Hampi has to offer and depicts Karnataka tourism an icon itself.
\n\n\tThe chariot is actually a shrine dedicated to Garuda, built inside the Vittala Temple Complex.  The massive sculpture of Garuda, Lord Vishnu’s escort once was seated atop the chariot but it is empty at the present date. The Hampi Chariot has earned its name among the other three famous stone chariots in India- One in Konark, Odissa, and the other in Mahabalipuram (Tamil Nadu).
\n\n\tThe chariot was built by King Krishnadevaraya of the Vijayanagara Empire during the 16th century, who got fascinated with the Konark Sun temple chariot while fighting a battle in Odissa. The chariot is meant to represent the beauty and artistic perfection of the Empire. An interesting folklore emanates from the Hampi chariot as villagers believe that the world would come to a halt when the chariot moves from its place. It has come to have a sacrosanct presence and is internationally recognized as a world heritage site even by the UNESCO.
\n\n\tBy Air: Hampi doesn’t have an airport and hence visitors will have to use the Bellary Airport which is roughly 64 km from Hampi and visitor can take a vehicle to cover up the last few miles.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The nearest railway station is Hosapete which is situated at a distance of 10km from Hampi and has a good connectivity in and around Karnataka.
\n\n\tBy Road: Hampi has good road connectivity and people travel usually from big cities like Bangalore and Mysore to Hampi via private or public buses or by hiring cars.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_gommateshwara_desc">\tBahubali, also known as Gommateshwara, is a famous Jain Saint who is worshipped by people from Jain community throughout the world for his admirable teachings about life that mainly deal with forgoing the two evils, Ego and Desire.
\n\n\tBahubali was the son of Sunanda Devi, the second wife of Rishaba, and was the second of the hundred sons born to the king. Rishaba, the king of Podanpur, gave up his desire to continue his life as a king after a small incident which involved a dancer giving up her life while dancing for the king in spite of her unhealthy condition.
\n\n\tBahubali spent several years of his life in meditation by giving up the bare necessities for every human such as clothing, food and water. Even with such resolve towards meditation, Bahubali was not able to attain supreme knowledge and power as there was one thing which was stopping him – his ego.
\n\n\tHe did not wish to meet his father and brothers as he felt that he had to bow down to them to take monastic vows. Concerned about their brother, Sundari and Brahmi, his sisters, met him and gave him the advice to let go of his ego, as it was stopping him from attaining the ultimate knowledge.Realising his mistake, Bahubali shed his pride and ego and attained the supreme knowledge of life and truth.
\n\n\tBahubali is known worldwide as a symbol of sacrifice, and with his experience, he enlightened the world, letting people know the way that a man had to take to live in peace and harmony. He advocated that all men must let go of his desires and ego. Presently, there are five monolithic statues of Bahubali in Karnataka, out of which the statue at Shravanabelagola is the tallest.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_chitradurga_fort_desc">\tChitradurga was called by many names and was termed Chitaldrug during the British reign. Afterwards, the name was changed to Chitradurga. The place is an ultimate feast for your eyes and soul too. It is situated in the valley of the River Vedavati and showcases picturesque landscape. The place was named after a lifted hill shaped like an umbrella found here.
\n\n\tThe place is popular for stone fortresses. According to the Indian mythological book Mahabharata, an evil named Hidimba and her sister Hidimbi used to live here. The sister of this evil was good at heart and he was simply an atrocious one.
\n\n\tWhile Pandavas were in their course of exile, Bhima encountered this monster and killed him. He then married Hidimbi and had a magical and powerful son named Ghatotkacha who also played a role during the Great War against Kauravas.
\n\n\tBetween 17th and 18th century the fort came into existence. There were many different rulers, ruling Chitradurga and transforming the fort. But the credit for expanding the fort goes to Hyder Ali and his son Tipu Sultan because during their reign the fort was transformed into a much better version. There is a citadel, temples, storage place for grain and oil and also facility for rainwater harvesting too. Masjid was added to the fort during Hyder Ali’s reign.
\n\n\tBy air: There are two airports near to Chitradurga, the first one is the Hubli Airport which is approx 186 km away and the second one is the Bangalore International Airport which is 197 km away. Buses and trains are available from there to reach the place
\n\n\tBy rail: The place possesses its own railway station named Chitradurga railway station. The station is connected to major cities of the country. It will be more feasible to come down to the city like Bangalore and then take a train from there to Chitradurga. There are taxis available at the station.
\n\n\tBy road: The city bus stop shows connectivity from all the major cities. One can easily take a bus and reach this place. Both KSRTC buses and private buses are available. Taxis are available from there to take you to a hotel or for sightseeing.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_kittur_fort_desc">\tKittur Fort is one of the major historical monuments in Karnataka and one of its famous tourist attractions. The fort is located in the town of Kittur that is situated at a distance of about 50 km from Belgaum and around 32 km from Dharwad. The small town of Kittur gained fame and recognition due to the presence of Kittur Fort and its immense historical significance.
\n\n\tKittur Fort is also known as Kittur Chennamma Fort as it is closely associated with Rani Chennamma, the brave ruler who ruled over her estate from the fort. With its old palaces, monuments and statues Kittur exudes historic attraction for tourists from all over the country and beyond. But it’s most famous attraction is the Kittur Fort that stands as evidence of one of the first freedom struggles of the country that was led by Rani Chennamma. Kittur Fort also has a palace within it that is popularly known as Rani Chennamma’s palace.
\n\n\tThe Kittur Fort was built by Allppa Gowda SarDesai, the fifth ruler of the Kittur dynasty during his rule from 1660 to 1691 A.D. He also constructed a grand palace inside the fort that served as his residence. The fort was constructed by using black basalt rock that was found in plenty in the surrounding areas of Kittur.
\n\n\tThe Kittur Fort was the place from where Rani Chennamma had carried out an armed rebellion against the British rulers in response to their undesired interference in tax collection in her estate. The remarkable fact is that she fought this war in the year 1824, thirty-three years before the uprising of armed 1857 that is considered in history as the first war of India’s independence.
\n\n\tThe armed rebellion of Kittur started on 3rd December, 1824. The heroic Rani Chennamma fought bravely against the British rulers but the Kittur Fort fell in the hands of the British forces on 5th December, 1824 after a fierce fighting of three days. Rani Chennamma was captured and sent to a jail in Bailhongal.
\n\n\tThe Kittur Fort was built over an area of about 23 acres. It is surrounded by a moat that was earlier fed by water from a lake lying close to the eastern wall of the fort. The walls on both sides of the fort have low height. The fort mainly comprises of the Kittur palace, a watch tower, water cisterns and an archaeological museum. The museum was added to the premises of the fort much later to preserve the relics of the Kittur fort, the Kittur palace and the antiques found in and around Kittur.
\n\n\tBy Air: Kittur is a small town that has no airport of its own. The nearest airport is located at Belgaum. The Belgaum airport operates flights to Bangalore and Chennai. From Belgaum visitors can avail local means of transport to reach the Kittur Fort.
\n\n\tBy Train: Kittur is not directly connected by the rail network. The nearest railway station lies at Dharwad. The Belgaum Railway Station is one of the oldest stations in this region. Both the stations are connected to major towns and cities across Karnataka and the nearby states. Moreover, there are plenty of local transport options available from Belgaum and Dharwad to reach Kittur.
\n\n\tBy Road: There are a number of buses that are available from several places like Bangalore, Goa, Mumbai, Belgaum, Dharwad and many other nearby towns and cities for reaching Kittur. Karnataka State Road Transport (KSRT) buses and a few other private buses are available from these places for Kittur. Apart from the buses, local means of transport like taxis and hired vehicles are also available for reaching the Kittur Fort comfortably.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_devanahalli_fort_desc">\tDevanahalli shot to popularity when the Bangalore International Airport landed right in its midst. A quaint town with roots deep in history was suddenly in the midst of six lane highways and land prices that would make even the hardiest faint.
\n\n\tSignboards strategically placed point tourists in the direction of the fort and the temples nearby. A deceptively narrow lane leads up to the entrance of the actual fort. Signboards in Hindi, Kannada and English declare the fort as being the birthplace of Tipu Sultan.
\n\n\tSpread over an area of 20 acres, the fort is a magnificent reminder of the power that the rulers held since the 15th century. The fort’s history begins with a small family of refugees who fled from Kanchi (Conjeevaram at that time). Their leader, Rana Baire Gowda dreamed up a harmonious settlement in the region where the current fort stands. His illustrious son Malla Baire Gowda was responsible for founding the towns of Doddabllapur, Chikkaballapur and Devanahalli.
\n\n\tThe area where the fort stands today passed from one royal patronage to another through time, from the Gangawadi to the Rashtrakutsa to the Nolamba and then subsequently to the cholas, Pallavas, Vijaynagar and Hoysala rulers. The land saw several royal patronages till the fort was constructed from mud by Malla Baire Gowda with the consent of Devaraya, the ruler of the area that was known as devnanadoddi at that time.
\n\n\tThe fort as it stands today is a frame-worthy picture of a period long lost in the sands of time. The walls, the bastions and the entryways have seen numerous eras and people of all kinds walk through them. Simply experiencing the sudden calm within the walls of the fort is reason enough to visit.
\n\n\tThe Fort is approximately 35 kilometers away from the center of Bangalore city.  One can either take a rick, hire a taxi or take public bus service to reach the place.
\n\n\tThe location is ideal for picnic seekers as it is en route to Nandi hills and is also close to Doddaballapur and Chikkaballapur. The historic picture postcard temples and the fort itself lend themselves to a wonderful day trip away from the hectic pace of the city.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_madikeri_fort_desc">\tMadikeri Fort is a historical landmark of Coorg. The fort stands in the center of the Madikeri town, still preserving the remnants of a bygone era within its proud walls. Some of the elevated structures inside the fort present astounding view of the surrounding areas. Needless to say, the fort is one of the most famous tourist attractions of Coorg.
\n\n\tThe Madikeri Fort was constructed in the later part of the 17th century by Muddu Raja, the then king of Coorg. Since then the fort has seen many changes.
\n\n\tHowever, this imposing structure has stood the test of time and has become a standing witness of Coorg’s history. Today the fort premises house the Madikeri Deputy Commissioner’s Office.
\n\n\tMadikeri Fort is a unique fort that houses among other structures a temple, an Anglican Church, a prison and a museum. The fact that a Church stands within the walls of the fort signifies the dominance of the British people over the fort. The St. Marks Church was built by the British in 1855 by removing a temple of Virabhadra from the inner fort and making place for the construction of the church. It was built in the Gothic style with stained glasses windows.
\n\n\tMadikeri is a small town of Karnataka but it is well connected to other cities and towns in the state and beyond by the road network. As such, reaching Madikeri is a simple matter. As the fort is located in the centre of the town, it is also easily reachable from any part of Madikeri.
\n\n\tBy Road: Madikeri is situated near the Karnataka State Highway 88 that runs from Mysore to Mangalore. So, it is well connected by the road network. There are several public buses that connect Madikeri to a number of places in Karnataka and Kerala. There are frequent KSRTC buses that connect Madikeri to Bangalore, Mysore, Virajpet, etc. Visitors can also reach Madikeri by private cars and hired cabs.
\n\n\t:By Rail: Madikeri does not have a railway station of its own. The nearest railheads are located at Hassan, Kasaragod, Kanhangad, Kannur and Thalassery (each of which is situated around 115 km away from Madikeri). Mysore and Mangalore are at a distance of 140 km but are good alternatives to reach Madikeri through the train route.
\n\n\t:By Air: The airport at Mysore is the nearest one as the small town of Madikeri has no airport. Mysore is connected to Mumbai, Delhi, Kolkata, Chennai, Hubli, and Dubai via Bangalore. The Mangalore International Airport at Mangalore can also be assessed to reach the town of Madikeri.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_gulbarga_fort_desc">\tThe Gulbarga Fort is found in the Gulbarga district in North Karntaka, built in 1347. The Gulbarga fort is one of the finest examples of the ancient Islamic architecture in Karnataka. The fort was originally built by Raja Gulchand. As Gulbarga gained prominence as the Bahmani capital, the fort was fortified by Alauddin Bahmani with a deep moat and massive walls. But according to Wikipedia the fort was built by Al-ud-din Bahmani of the Bahmani Dynasty after he cut off his ties with the Delhi Sultanate.
\n\n\tThe fort is built with well planning the canal is made around the fort so that it becomes difficult to the enemy. Krishna River and Bhima River flow very close to the fort. Predominantly black soil is found in this area,and is situated in the drought prone region. The fort contained 15 towers and 26 guns of which one was 8 metres long.
\n\n\tThe place has a huge sprawling complex housing the tomb of’ Bande Nawaz’, the great Sufi Saint, who came to Gulbarga in 1413. His tomb’s walls have paintings and a mosque built by the Mughuls is near the tomb. It was built in the Indo-Saracenic style. The paintings on the walls and ceiling have a fusion of Turkish and Irani influence.
\n\n\tThe Khandar Khan’s mosque and Hirapur mosque (1585) built by Chandbibi are some other monuments here, and the tomb of Sultan Hassan and Firoze Shah are imposing structures. The state Archeology Museum here has Buddhist plaquest brought from Sannati.
\n\n\tIn the 6th Century the Rashtrakutas ruled over the area. But later the Chalukyas ruled over the place for almost two hundred years. But at the end the Hoysalas took over. Muhammad bin Tughlug occupied the Deccan in the early 14th Century.
\n\n\tThe revolt of the Muslim officers appointed from Delhi resulted in founding of the Bahmani Sultanate in 1347 by Hassan Gangu, who chose Gulbarga (named as ‘Ahsenabad’ during this period) to be his capital. The capital of the Bahmani Kingdom was Gulbarga, with its headquarters at the Gulbarga Fort.
\n\n\tThe Bahmanis ruled over most of Deccan until the late 15th Century and early 16th Century, then the kingdom was divided into five independent states.  After India became independent in August 1947 ,the fort and Gulbarga district became a part of Bangalore rule.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_buddha_vihar_desc">\tBuddha Vihar is located in Gulbarga on a sprawling 70 acre land. It is the nations largest and one of its kind. It is adjoining the Gulbarga University in the city outskirts.It is built by the Siddartha Vihar Trust at a cost of more than Rs 8 crore, is considered to be one of the biggest in the entire South India.
\n\n\tNearly 1,500 tonnes of cement, 250 tonnes of steel, 5 lakh bricks and 200 cubic metres of sand have been converted by artisans and craftsmen into this beautiful structure that is built. The main structure stands on 32,450 sq ft of land on 170 pillars with 284 blocks. Each one of these reflect the Ajanta and Ellora sculptures and art.
\n\n\tThe ground and first floors of the vihar have the sanctum sanctorum where two exquisitely carved idols of Lord Buddha are installed. A six-foot idol of Lord Buddha carved from glossy, black stone sculptured by sculptor Ashoka Gudikara of Bidadi in Ramanagaram district is installed in the ground floor. Buddha Vihar will be one of its kind spiritual centre in the country. The building will be a symbol of ancient history and social movements in the region. It serves as a great tribute to Buddha,Basava and Ambedker,who struggled and dedicated their lives for the needy in the society.
\n\n\tIt is not only a great tourist centre and also a centre of creativity and research.This is centre is doing a lot of research on Buddhism.
\n\n\tThe beautifully sculpted panchloha idol with a gold coating is the biggest of its kind in South India. A gold-plated smiling idol of Lord Buddha along with his favourite disciples, Anand and Kashyap, has been brought here from Bangkok,and it was brought to India in 2004.
\n\n\tThe intricately carved doors in rosewood and teakwood are designed by artisan Kaiser Ali, connected with the royal family of Mysore.The complex consists of a museum, where another idol of Lord Buddha is installed, an auditorium, guesthouses, and a dining hall.
</string>

    // Religious Description
    <string name="rel_kudala_sangama_desc">\tKudala Sangama (Kudalasangama Koodalsangama Koodalasangama) is in Bagalkot District of Karnataka. It is a famous pilgrim place for Veerashaivas. Here is the confluence of two big rivers Krishna and Malaprabha. The holy samadhi, Aikya Mantapa is situated here. The Mantapa is under water, but is well protected. There is a temple dedicated to Lord Sangameswara, worshipped in the form of a ling. The temple is an ancient monument built in the Chalukyan style architecture. Distance between Kudala Sangama and Bengaluru, Karnataka is 445.7 km and travel time is around 7 h 10 min via NH50 and NH48.
\n\n\tThis place is closely associated with the 12th century poet and social reformer Saint Basaveswara. Basavana Bagewadi is another important place in the locality. Bagalkot Railway Station and Belgaum Airport are the nearest railhead and airport respectively.
\n\n\tA true visionary of his time and a revolutionary who started a new religion, Lingayatism (also known as Veershaivism), which literally means The brave followers of Shiva. Basavannas ultimate aim was to make this fundamental right available to each and everyone. Basavanna, keeping welfare as the ultimate aim, expedited programmes to take religion to the people by preaching and writing religious literature in Kannada. His samadhi is at Kudalasangama.
\n\n\tKudalasangama Pin code is 587118 and postal head office is Hungund. Kudalasangama STD code is 08351. Nearest railway station to Kudalasangama is Almatti which is 15 km away. Distance from Kudala Sangama to Bagalkot, Karnataka is 52.3 km and travelling takes around 1 h 13 min via NH367.
</string>

    <string name="rel_iskon_bangalore_desc">\tIskon located in the Rajaji Nagar in Bangalore, and a venture of the International Society of Krishna Consciousness, ISKCON Temple in Bangalore is a shrine to Lord Krishna. This splendid architecture was first erected by Sri Madhu Pandit Das and inaugurated in the year 1997 by the then President of India, Shankar Dayal Sharma.
\n\n\tIt houses a number of prayer halls, dedicated to Sri Sri Radha Krishnachandra, Sri Sri Krishna Balarama, Sri Sri Nitai Gauranga, Sri Srinivasa Govinda and Sri Prahlada Narasimha.
\n\n\tThe International Society for Krishna Consciousness was initiated in the year 1976 by Krishna devotees from across the world. The ISKCON Temple in Bangalore was first established in 1998 under the Karnataka Societies Registration Act, 1960.
\n\n\tThe construction of the temple began in 1990, and around 600 skilled artisans were employed for the purpose. The construction finally ended in the year 1997.  On the same year, the Temple was inaugurated by the ninth President of India- Shankar Dayal Sharma.
</string>

    <string name="rel_murdeshwara_desc">\tMurudeshwara is a holy city dedicated to Lord Shiva, situated in the southern state of Karnataka, on the coast of the Arabian Sea. This city mainly prides itself on having the second tallest sculpture of Lord Shiva in the whole world.
\n\n\tMurudeshwara is easily accessible by bus, train and by air. The nearest airport is Mangalore airport, which is 133km away from the city. All the trains that connect Mangalore and Mumbai pass through the Murudeshwar Railway Station, which makes it conveniently accessible by frequent trains. Other nearby cities like Kochi, Bangalore and Mumbai are connected to Murudeshwara through very efficient bus service.
\n\n\tThe romantic sunsets on the Murudeshwar Beach are truly something worth witnessing when you are in the area. The beaches of the Arabian Sea such as the Aligadda Beach and Murudeshwar Beach allow tourists to enjoy water sports and other adventures along their shores. A unique activity you can enjoy in Murudeshwar Beach is scuba-diving, which is sure to leave you with lifelong memories. One must definitely visit the majestic statue of Lord Shiva that towers over the city at a height of 123 feet. A visit to the Murudeshwar Temple and Raja Gopura is also a spiritually rewarding experience for visitors.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit Murudeshwar is between October and May when the city comes alive with fairs, events and festivals. The festival of Mahashivaratri is performed here with great spirit and fervour during February and March and is a spectacle worth witnessing. You can choose from a multitude of hotels and accommodations for a comfortable stay when you are visiting here.
</string>

    <string name="rel_sri_krishna_udupi_desc">\tUdupi is a wonderful holiday destination in Karnataka located about 60 km away from Mangalore. One of the unique things about this city is that it is surrounded by the Western ghats on one side and the Arabian Sea on the other. After Bangalore and Mangalore, Udupi is the most important city in Karnataka.
\n\n\tUdupi is famous for its scenic beauty, mouth watering cuisines, pristine beaches and untouched forests. One of the best things to do in Udupi is explore the wonderful green forests and get a glimpse of some of its rare inmates. The intricately carved temples are visited by devotees and history buffs all year round. Udupi has a rich cultural heritage with a history that is over 700 years old.
\n\n\tUdupi has some of the most beautiful places to visit in Karnataka such as the famous Krishna temple which is visited by devotees all year round. Other popular places to visit here are St. Marys Island, Bramhvar, Barkur, Maple Beach, Kudlu Falls and Anantheshwar Temple.
\n\n\tUdupi city is not only famous for having some good temples and beaches, but you can also do some fun activities in this city. You can try the banana boats on Maple beach or ride the speed boats and enjoy a trip to St Marys island. Apart from boating, you can also do trekking, river rafting, water sports, pilgrimage, and many other outdoor activities. Udupi is also a great place to shop for Kanjeevaram sarees and other silken goods.
</string>

    <string name="rel_darmasthala_manjunatha_desc">\tShri Kshetra Dharmasthala, the land of righteousness and piety, is one of south Indias most renowned religious landmarks with a history as old as 800 years. Manjunatheshwara, the chief deity of the spiritual abode, has taken the form of a shivalinga and made immaculate, the temple town of Dharmasthala since and forever. Lord Manjunatheshwara, is being worshipped in a very unusual yet exceptionally inordinate manner in Shree kshetra dharmasthala, as this Shaiva temple is beseeched by Vaishnava priests and administered by Jain descendants.
\n\n\tDharmasthala, the abode of dharma, is the quintessence of humanity and faith. As the name suggests, the word dharma in its truest sense means righteousness, it is the embodiment of the worlds most divine emotions in spite of ones cast, creed or religion.
\n\n\tAnnappa swamy betta located 1.5 km west of the new bus stand and half a kilometre from the Shri Manjunatha temple, in the southeast direction is the hill of Annappa Betta, which is also known as Badinede Betta; this shrine is dedicated to Shri Annappa swamy and is home to the shrines of the four Dharma Daivas. A peep through the window of the inside of a dwelling, one can see a swing, believed to be used by one of the Daivas Generally the hill is visited, after having visited the main temple. Entry of children and women is restricted to this hill owing to the legend and lore of the temple.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kukke_subramanya_desc">\tSri Kukke Subramanya shrine in Dakshina Kannada district of Karnataka is one place almost every Hindu devotee in the Southern part of India would be familiar with.  And not just being familiar, many would either have visited or would have planned to visit the temple at least once in a lifetime for the powers Lord Subramanya here is known to possess and bless a devotee with. Come, lets learn about all that the shrine is known for and more.
\n\n\tThe Kukke Subramanya Temple is dedicated to Lord Subramanya, Son of Lord Shiva. According to legends, Lord Subramanya is considered the Deva Senapathi – the commander of the army of the lords and is worshipped as the lord of snakes.
\n\n\tThe temple Sri Kukke Subramanya is located in the Subramanya town of Sullia Taluk in Dakshina Kannada district. Easily accessible by rail and road, this small town is located about 105 km from Mangaluru while the temple is situated amidst a scenic location thats relatively unexplored and neat in comparison to a lot of other pilgrimage venues.
</string>

    <string name="rel_chamundeshwari_mysore_desc">\tIn India, just as a persons name usually has a symbolic meaning, names given to places also have a meaning behind them. Chamundi Hills in Karnataka are named after the Goddess Chamundeshwari.
\n\n\tThe hills lie at a height of about 1000 meters above sea level and are 13 km east of Mysore. The Chamundeshwari Temple dedicated to the Goddess after whom the hills are named is the highlight of this place.
\n\n\tAccording to popular legends, many years ago, a buffalo demon named Mahishasura was wreaking havoc in heaven and earth.  He had been gifted a boon by Brahma that he could be killed by no man.
\n\n\tFor this reason, Mahishasura was slowly winning every battle he started. The Gods found a loophole to Brahmas boon and goddess Durga was given divine powers to make her stronger than Mahishasura.
\n\n\tGoddess Chamundeshwari is a form of Durga. With her new powers and a lion as her vehicle, she fought Mahishasura atop a hill for ten days and finally killed him.
\n\n\tIn her honor, the hill was named as Chamundi Hill. This day is celebrated throughout India as Dasara and symbolizes the victory of good over evil.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kotilingeshwara_temple_desc">\tThe Kotilingeshwara Temple lies in a very small village named Kammasandra in the Kolar district. The temple is extremely famous because of the largest and the tallest Shivalinga present in Asia. More than 2 lac devotees visit this temple every year.
\n\n\tMaha Shivaratri is a special occasion and a large number of devotees make it a point to be there on this auspicious day. The temple can be easily reached from the gold fields of Kolar.
\n\n\tThe Shivalinga is 33 mts and is the tallest in the World. It has an accompanying Basava statue which is 11 mts tall and is surrounded by a large number of Shivalingas spread across the area. The project involves an establishment of one crore shivalingas hence it is named Kotilingeshwara and currently, there are about a hundred lakh shivalingas.
\n\n\tThis temple has been constructed by Swami Sambha Shiva Murthy in the year 1980. The first linga was installed in 1980 and since then there have been many lingas present in the temple. There is also a huge and tall Nandi installed beside the linga. The Nandi is 11 mt tall and sits over a huge platform.
\n\n\tWithin the premises of the temple, there are about eleven other temples for different deities. The first of them includes the temple of Lord Vishnu, Lord Brahma, and Lord Maheshwara temples. This is followed by a temple of Lord Kotilingeshwara.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport to Kolar is located at Bangalore.  From the airport, travelers can hire cabs or rely on public transport to reach Kolar.
\n\n\tBy Rail: There is a well-connected rail network from Bangalore, Mangalore, Hassan, Kolar and Hubli.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you want to reach the temple by road, you need to head through Kolar. Kolar is at a distance of 2.5 hours from Bangalore.
</string>

    <string name="rel_sringeri_sharda_peetham_desc">\tThe town is also known as Sringeri Sharda Peetham and it has a 1200 year- old temple located there. It is believed that Adi Shankaracharya chose the site to stay and teach his disciples and impressed with his place, he stayed here for twelve years. He then also established mathas in North India, East India, and West India. Adi Shankaracharya has constructed four temples in all the four directions – these include Kere Anjaneya Temple in the West, Kala Bhairava Temple in the East, Durgamba Temple in the South and Kalikamba Temple in the North.
\n\n\tSringeri is a town located in the Chikkamangaluru district in the state of Karnataka. The hill town is situated on the banks of the River Tunga and is located at a distance of 107 km from Mangalore and 336 km from Bangalore. It can be easily reached from Mangalore through Karkala.
\n\n\tSringeri holds significance in Karnataka due to the first matha, which was established by Adi Shankaracharya. The first of the four peetha was established here. Located amidst the Western Ghats, the name of Sringeri is derived from Rishyashringa-giri which is a nearby hill and is believed to have contained the rich heritage of Rishi Vibhandaka and his son Rishyashringa.
\n\n\tSringeri is well known as a learning center due to the many temples and maths. Many students come down here to learn Vedic philosophy. A variety of options for accommodation are available at Sringeri.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport is Mangalore International Airport at a distance of 105 kms.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The city Shimoga which is at a distance of 95 kms from Sringeri is well connected to Bangalore through the rail route. Sringeri is at a distance of 86 kms from Chikkamagaluru which is connected to Bangalore through a rail line via Kadur.
\n\n\tBy Road: The town can be reached from Mangalore or Chikkamagaluru by a well-connected road network. Udupi is also at a distance of 80 kms. Various private and KSRTC buses ply from Bangalore as well as Sringeri to Shimoga.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kalasa_temple_desc">\tKalasa, the temple town of Karnataka, is a must-visit. There are many temple towns in Karnataka, associated with events from centuries ago, providing a glimpse into the spiritual soul of the region.
\n\n\tThese revered sites also showcase the architectural heritage of Southern India which boasts so many styles and design philosophies, representing the many dynasties and cultures that have inhabited the land. One of these temple towns is Kalasa, located in the picturesque Chikkamagaluru district in Karnataka close to the famous peak of Kudremukh.
\n\n\tSitting on the banks of the River Bhadra, the main attraction of Kalasa town is the Kalaseshwara Temple, dedicated to Lord Shiva. The intricately carved main tower of the temple is one of the defining features of the town as pilgrims from all over the region come to offer their prayers throughout the day. The town is surrounded by the scenic Western Ghats, from where its lifeline, the Bhadra originates.
\n\n\tThe legend behind Kalasa is steeped in some of the most important events of Hindu mythology. It is believed that when Lord Shiva and Goddess Parvathi married in the Himalayas, the attendance of the entire pantheon of deities caused a change in the earths rotation.
\n\n\tLord Shiva requested the great sage Agasthya to travel south and balance the shift of the earth, promising him that he would be able to witness the wedding from where he resides. The town is believed to be the spot where Sage Agasthya resided during the wedding of Shiva and Parvathi. The marriage is celebrated by devotees to this date.
\n\n\tBy Air: Mangalores Bajpe airport is closest to the town, around 115 kilometres away. The Mysore airport is around 175 kilometres away from the town. The rest of the journey is by road.
\n\n\tBy Train: The closest train station to the town is in Bantawala, 114 kilometres away.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you are landing in Mangalore, then the road trip north via the NH 169 and SH 66 is around 115 kilometres and would take close to 3 hours. From Bangalore, the place is a 6-hour road trip via NH75. The 310 kilometres route passes through the town of Hassan. The trip by road from Bantwal railway station via the NH 169 and SH 66 would take close to 3 hours.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kollur_mookambika_desc">\tKollur located in the Kondapur Taluk in District Udupi, Karnataka, is a small temple town. Situated in the Western Ghat foothills, the town is famous for its Mookambika Temple, a popular Hindu pilgrimage. Also known as Kollapura, the town is 38 kilometers from Kudapur Town. Situated on the banks River Sauparnika, the place is encircled by dense forest and is in the shape of a Sri Chakra.
\n\n\tThe town is one of the seven mukti places or pilgrimage centers created by Lord Parashurama. The remaining six pilgrimages are located in Kodeshwara, Gokarna, Udupi, Kumbasi, Sankaranarayanan and Subrahmanya. As per a popular belief, penance was performed on this holy place by Saints in ancient times.
\n\n\tMookambika Temple, one of the major temples in the town, is dedicated to supreme goddess Devi Durga and is a significant place of Shakti worship. The goddess is depicted here in the form of a Jyothirlinga, implying the confluence of Both Shiva and Shakti.
\n\n\tThere are many legends associated with the temple. A demon named Mookasuran, residing in this area wanted to gain powers using his penance. Goddess Parvati was worried to know this and killed Mookasuran with her Chakra on Shukla Ashtami. Since then Goddess Parvati is also known as Mookambika Devi.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport to the town is Bajpe Airport in Mangalore, which is nearly 106 kilometres away and the best way to reach here. Hubli Airport is the second nearest airport located nearly 170 kilometres away.
\n\n\tBy Train: If you plan to come to the temple town by train, you can take a train till Bijoor Railway Station or till Byndoor Mookambika Road Railway Station. Both the railway stations are located nearly 20 kilometres away from here.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you plan to come to the town by road, you can easily drive down from Mangalore, Bangalore, Mysore and Udupi. You can even take KSRTC buses plying regularly to Kollur from these cities.
</string>

    <string name="rel_goravanahalli_mahalakshmi_desc">\tWhen it comes to tourism, Karnataka is the fourth most popular holiday destination in India. One of the reasons, this state is so popular is because of its ornate temples like the Sri Mahalakshmi Temple in Goravanahalli. As the name suggests, this temple is dedicated to Goddess Mahalakshmi, the wife of Lord Vishnu and the Goddess of prosperity and wealth.
\n\n\tThe main idol of Goddess Mahalakshmi in the temple is believed to be self-manifested. According to local historians, in the early 1900s, a villager named Abbayya came into possession of this idol. He worshipped the idol at home and was blessed with wealth and prosperity. His home soon came to be known as Lakshmi Nivas in honor of his charity work. Abbayya brother’s Thotadappa also worked alongside Abbayya and worshipped the Goddess Mahalakshmi. One night the Goddess visited him in his dreams and asked him to build her a temple. Thus Thotadappa built a temple for the Goddess and began worshipping the idol in this shrine. After Thotadappa’s death, Chowdavya began performing the poojas for Goddess Mahalakshmi.
\n\n\tThe Sri Mahalakshmi Temple in Goravanahalli is a beautiful example of the typical South Indian architecture in the 1900s. The temple features a large, multicolored Gopuram with smaller arches on both sides. The temple also has verandahs on either side.  The main deity is housed in the Garbhagriha or the sanctum sanctorum. Other deities such as the Nag Dev and Marikamba are also housed in the temple.
\n\n\nThe temple is open to the public all through the year. Tuesdays and Friday are considered especially auspicious. If you would like to attend the Pooja, Abhisheka and Kumkuma Archane are performed at 8 am to 9.30am and the Maha Mangalarathi is performed at 9:30 am, 12:30 pm and at 7:30 pm. The temple is closed between 12.30pm and 5.30pm. Lakshadeepotsava is the most important festival at this temple.
\n\n\tBy Air: The Bangalore International Airport caters to domestic and international tourists and is a mere 80 kms from the temple.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The closest railways station is located 36 kms from the temple at Tumkur. A number of trains stop here on a daily basis including the Jan Shatabdi Express for Hubli, the Ranichennama Express and the Golgumbaz Express.
\n\n\tBy Road: KSRTC and Private Buses ply regularly between Bangalore and Gorvanahalli.</string>

    <string name="rel_siddaganga_mutt_desc">\tSree Siddaganga Mutt is an ancient and one of a kind Gurukul, situated in Tumkur, amidst the beautiful and serene landscape. It is about 63 km from Bangalore. The mutt’s aim is to provide service to the needy and to the poor, and this has been successfully carried out.
\n\n\tThe Sree Siddaganga Mutt offers education to more than 8000 poor children, between the age five to 16 years, with free food and shelter and is exempted from discrimination, and is open to children of all faiths and communities. The mutt also has a school for the blind with more than 100 blind children and offers free education, food and independent hostel facility.
\n\n\tOne of the befitting things we can see in the mutt is the annual prayers of the students of the mutt. All these students participate in the prayers without any disparity of caste or creed. The prayers are held both in the mornings as well as in the evenings, during which time the swami is present and guides the students.
\n\n\tSree Siddaganga Mutt is an ancient and one of a kind Gurukul, situated in Tumkur, amidst the beautiful and serene landscape. It is about 63 km from Bangalore. The mutt’s aim is to provide service to the needy and to the poor, and this has been successfully carried out.
\n\n\tSree-shivakumara-swamiji-dr-abdul-kalamThe Sree Siddaganga Mutt offers education to more than 8000 poor children, between the age five to 16 years, with free food and shelter and is exempted from discrimination, and is open to children of all faiths and communities. The mutt also has a school for the blind with more than 100 blind children and offers free education, food and independent hostel facility.
\n\n\tOne of the befitting things we can see in the mutt is the annual prayers of the students of the mutt. All these students participate in the prayers without any disparity of caste or creed. The prayers are held both in the mornings as well as in the evenings, during which time the swami is present and guides the students.
\n\n\tThe Sree Siddaganga Mutt was established in the 15th Century A.D. by the Sri Gosala Siddeswara Swamiji, who belongs to the Shunya Simhasana, a spiritual academy from the days of social reformer Basaweshwara. The present head of the mutt is Dr. Sree Sree Sree Shivakumara Swamiji, who is now 104 years old. He is the driving force in this ashram.
\n\n\tHe was born in Veerapura near Magadi Taluk. He took full responsibility of the mutt in the year 1941. He is also the founder of the Sree Siddaganga Educational Society. The tireless efforts of the swami have resulted in the development of free boarding for the children to its present size.
\n\n\tThe most economic route for reaching the Siddaganga Mutt is to avail local transport facilities. There are plenty of buses and taxis plying from Tumkur. Travelling in KSRTC bus from Bangalore to Tumkur will take about two hours in a car. Strolling around the ashram, meeting the swami and seeing the discipline in the mutt will definitely be a unique experience for everyone visiting the mutt. The mutt and the temples within can be visited anytime during the year, as the weather is quite pleasant.
</string>

    <string name="rel_badami_banashankari_desc">\tBanashankari Amma Temple is a famous temple located in Cholachagudd near Badami, in the Bagalkot district of Karnataka. This is a temple dedicated to Goddess Parvati, the consort of Lord Shiva.
\n\n\tThe Banashankari Amma Temple was originally built by the Chalukyas during the 7th century. The Goddess Banashankari was their family deity. According to an inscription, this image of the Banashankari Amma was installed by Jagadekamalla I in 630 AD. This temple was later renovated by the Marathas in the 18th century. Its modern structure now reflects the Vijayanagara style of architecture more than the original Chalukya style.
\n\n\tThe Skanda Purana says that an Asura named Durgamasura lived in this region. He used to harass the people and made their life unbearable. The Devas were moved by their plight and prayed for a way to kill the Demon. Goddess Parvati answered their prayers. She came down to earth as Shakambari and killed Durgamasura after a fierce battle. Shakambari stayed on in the region to protect the people. She came to be known as Banashankari or Vanashankari. Vana means forest in Sanskrit, and Shankari means the consort of Lord Shankara. As the temple was situated near a forest, she was called Vanashankari, which later became Banashankari in the local language.
\n\n\tThis temple is situated just five kilometers from Badami, another famous religious and tourist spot. It is easy to reach Badami by bus from any part of Karnataka. Badami also has a railway station. The nearest airport is located in the city of Belgaum.
</string>

    <string name="rel_godachi_veerabadra_temple_desc">\tGodachi is a small village in the Ramdurg Taluq of Karnataka. This place is located in the Belgaum district and it has many beautiful temples including the Shri Veerabhadra temple. A famous fair is held here every year.
\n\n\tGodachi is a small village famous for the Godach Fair or Jatre held during the months of November-December every year. The Godachi Jatre is held in honor of Shri Veerabhadra, the prime deity in the main temple here – the Veerabhadra temple.
\n\n\tVeerabhadra was created by Lord Shiva to destroy Daksha’s Yagna. The Veerabhadra temple is a in a combined style of Chalukya and Vijayanagara Architecture. The doorway is built in the Chalukyan style, while the Garbhagraha or the sanctum reflects Vijayanagara Style of temple building.
\n\n\tGodachi is 12 km away from the Taluq headquarters Ramdurg. The nearest railway station to Ramdurg is the Badami railway station.
\n\n\tGodachi Jatre or fair is held in November or December, during the month of Karthik in the Hindu calendar. Traditionally, temple festivals and fairs in India have not only been religious celebrations, they also served as social and commercial gatherings and Godachi Jatre is also one such occasion.
</string>

    <string name="rel_savadatti_yellamma_desc">\tThe Yellamma Devi Temple is located in Saundatti taluq, five kilometers away from Saundatti town. Saundatti itself is 70 km away from Belgaum city.
\n\n\tThe Yellamma Devi temple is located on top of a hill near Saundatti. Saundatti is an ancient town which was the first capital of the Ratta dynasty. The Renuka Devi Temple, or Yellamma Devi Temple (as it is more popularly known), is the most famous pilgrimage spot in Saundatti.
\n\n\tThe Yellamma Temple attracts people from all over Karnataka and neighboring states. During the Yellamma Jatre, especially the one held during the month of Margasira, the number of attendees normally crosses 10 lakhs. The Jatre is also known for the practice of dedicating girls to the Devadasi system.
\n\n\tYellamma Devi is associated with Renuka, the wife of Jamadhagni and the mother of Parashurama, whose story is told in the Puranas. Here, she is worshipped as Renuka Devi or Yellamma Devi.
\n\n\tYellamma Devi is also identified with the Goddess Kali. Kali is known as the punisher who destroys evil-doers, but she is also the kind mother who showers love and blessings on her devotees. It is in this aspect that she is worshipped here. A Jain inscription in the temple, in Sanskrit and Kannada, refers to the Rashtrakuta kings Krishna and Vikramadithya.
\n\n\tThis temple was constructed in 1514 by Bommappa Nayak. It is built in a combination of Chalukyan and Rashtrakuta styles. There are smaller temples for Ganesha, Mallikarjuna, Parashurama, Eknaath and Siddheshwara in the temple courtyard. The Government now takes care of the temple management.
\n\n\tHubli and Belgaum are the nearest airports, while Dharwad is the nearest railway station. Saundatti is connected to these places by KSRTC buses.
</string>

    // Gardens Description
    <string name="gard_alamatti_garden_desc">\tLav Kush Garden is one of the most beautiful gardens at Almatti. They are beautifully maintained and depict huge sculptures which are made by using cement and steel of lav Kush and Krishna. There is natural pavement along the paths with waterfalls and water channels alongside. The Garden has a beautiful lawn, hedges, flower beds, ornamental plants and shrubs.
\n\n\tIn Front of the Sita Mata Temple are two ponds which are believed to never dry up and always have water in them ( also known as Kush Kanda).
\n\n\tThe garden attracts children by viewing different childhood activities of Lava and Kush like playing in their cradle with mother Sita, taking education with their Gurus etc.
\n\n\tThe garden has a gorgeous view point and panoramic view of the Almatti Dam.Lav Kush Garden is open daily from 6 AM to 7 PM. Entry is free during early morning and late evening 6 to 9 AM and 6 to 7 PM. A nominal fee applies during the day time.
\n\n\tLav Kush Garden is located 6 kms from the Almatti Dam. Lalbagh can be accessed using private vehicles/taxis to reach Lav Kush Garden.Almatti Dam, Badami Cave Temples, Fort Bijapur are some of the other interesting spots to explore near Lav Kush Garden.
</string>

    <string name="gard_hospet_garden_desc">\tHospet, being a tourist center, is flocked by crowds of people from all over India as well as abroad. The Department of tourism of Karnataka ensures the development and well maintenance of recreational parks and gardens. If you plan a trip to Hospet, you must not miss visiting the beautiful parks and gardens there. There are also excellent wildlife spots in and around Hospet which would be a delight for wildlife enthusiasts.
\n\n\tHospet is home to many wildlife sanctuaries because of its natural environment and wide range of forests. If you are a wildlife lover, there is plenty of wildlife to be watched in Hospet and its surrounding areas.
\n\n\tThe Daroji Bear Sanctuary provides room for various sloth bears to live freely in their natural habitat. Daroji Sloth Bear Sanctuary is located near Kamalapur which is just 12 km from Hospet. This area near Kamalapur has been the abode of bears since centuries and it has been declared as the Daroji Sloth Bear Sanctuary.
\n\n\tThe Daroji Sloth Bear sanctuary also serves as a home for hyenas, pangolins, wild boars, jackals, black-naped hares, porcupines, and leopards. Bird spotting is also very popular here and you can spot endemic bird species like painted spur fowl and yellow-throated bulbuls. You can also find dry land bird species such as sand grouse, quails, sirkeer malkohas and stone-curlews in this sanctuary. The opening hours of the sanctuary are from 9.30am to 6pm and the entrance fee is Rs.25. It is a good idea for you to visit this sanctuary during July to March as it is the best time for sighting wildlife. However, sloth bears can be sighted all through the year during all months, including extremely hot summer months.
\n\n\tOther popular places good for sighting wildlife are Muneer park, T.B Dam zoo and Chakra Vana park.
</string>

    <string name="gard_lalbag_bangalore_desc">\tLalbagh is one of the oldest botanical gardens in India and is also a major tourist attraction in South India. Located in South Bengaluru, the Lalbagh Botanical Garden is not only one of the largest botanical gardens in India, but also the first of its kind, with planned routes, glasshouses and ornamental flowers growing throughout the property.
\n\n\tThe garden itself is spread over an area of 240 acres and its construction was commissioned by the famous ruler Hyder Ali. It was finally completed by his son- Tipu Sultan- who designed the gardens keeping in mind the beautiful gardens of Sira in Tumkur District in Karnataka.
\n\n\tLalbagh is home to exotic flowers that were imported by the Sultan from countries like France, Persia, Arabia, Afghanistan, etc. Therefore, flowers that were previously never seen in India were first witnessed in this historical garden. Trees that were imported by Tipu Sultan from all over the world can still be found growing here.
\n\n\tThe bi-annual flower show at the Lalbagh Botanical Garden is a spectacle to behold. People travel from far and wide from India and even from abroad to witness millions of flowers, thousands of plants and the incredible artistry that goes into making the figurines and flower structures.
\n\n\tThe show takes place twice a year- once during January in the same week as the Indian Republic Day, and another time in August, during Independence Day. Each year, a different theme is chosen and flower arrangements are made according to the theme.
\n\n\tPlants and flowers are imported from all over the world and over 20 lakh flowers are used each year to make semi-permanent structures in various characteristic shapes and designs. The show takes place inside the striking Glass House which is located on the premises of the Botanical Gardens and goes on from 9:00 am in the morning until 6:00 pm in the evening.
\n\n\tLalbagh Botanical Garden is located at a distance of 38.8 km from Kempegowda International Airport in Bangalore. There are frequent bus routes that ferry between the two places. You can also book a taxi or hire a car which will take you to Lalbagh after a short 45-minute drive through the city of Bangalore.
\n\nThe best time to visit the Lalbagh Botanical Gardens is during winter, which lasts from November to March in Bangalore. Even though the gardens remain open throughout the year, it can get pretty stuffy and hot during summer.
</string>

    <string name="gard_cubbon_park_desc">\tAn oasis of green amidst a buzzing urbanscape, Cubbon Park is a scenic tourist attraction in the IT city of Bangalore. The park with a thriving ecosystem with more than 6000 trees, is justly regarded as the ‘lungs of the city. Besides being home to multitudes of vibrant flora and birdlife, Cubbon Park is also where you will find a handful of the citys most alluring structures including the Attara Kacheri, Seshadri Iyer Memorial Hall, and the grand State Archeological Museum.
\n\n\tThere is a wealth of historical and archaeological specimens preserved in these buildings, touching upon important turning points from the countrys past. Its as enjoyable to leaf through the pages of history inside these museums as it is to take a relaxing walk or a jog in the park along the picturesque tree-lined avenues. There is one other attraction in the park that tourists of every temperament are bound to enjoy— the huge Cubbon Park Aquarium, also famous as the Bangalore Aquarium.
\n\n\tAmong a diversity of vibrant water life in this aquarium, you can find the majestic-looking Siamese Fighting Fish, a variety of gouramis, predators like red tail shark and more. Its absolutely captivating to walk inside the aquarium, as if you have stepped inside the aquamarine belly of the sea— certainly a big highlight for nature enthusiasts!
\n\n\tCubbon Park should be the first place on your sightseeing tour in Bangalore, especially if you are in the company of kids. For the amusement of children, the park has a toy- train track passing through. Every 10-20 minute theres a biofuel-run locomotive on the line, ready to give visitors a memorable joy ride.
\n\n\tFind a KSRTC bus plying between the airport and M.G. Road or Kasturba Road. Alternatively, you can hire a cab to Kasturba Road from the airport. The closest access points to the park are- Hudson Circle, Ambedkar Veedhi, and State Central Library.
</string>

    <string name="gard_mysore_zoo_desc">\tShri Chamarajendra Zoological Gardens or more commonly known as Mysore Zoo is one of the oldest zoos in the world. Established in the year 1892 by the Royals of the Mysore, this Zoological Gardens was formed from a part of Maharaja Chamaraja Wodeyars summer palace area.
\n\n\tLocated within an area of 157 acres (64 hectares), Mysore Zoo is the second most visited place in Mysore after Mysore Palace. It is currently an abode to 1,450 specimens of animals and birds consisting of 168 species belonging to more than 25 countries.
\n\n\tThe Zoological Gardens is proud to have a collecting of big cats like Cheetah, Jaguar, Tiger, Lion and small cats like Leopard Cat, Jungle Cat, Common Palm Civet and Small Indian Civet. It is the only zoo in India to exhibit a Gorilla. Other Primates include Baboon, Capuchin Monkey, and Marmoset, a variety of Lemur, Chimpanzee and common Indian Langur.
\n\n\tThe Zoological Garden is also abode to large mammals like Elephants belonging to both Asiatic and African region, Black and White African Rhino, Gaur and Hippopotamus.
\n\n\tThe Zoological Gardens is also proud to own flightless birds like Emu, Rhea, Ostrich, and Cassowary. There is also a huge collection of Terrestrial birds, aquatic birds, deers, antelopes, ducks, and reptiles.
</string>

    <string name="gard_dandeli_national_park_desc">\tDandeli, a small sleepy town in the western ghats of North-West India in the state of Karnataka is really proud of beholding the magnanimous wild land under the tiger project.
\n\n\tThe Dandeli Wildlife Sanctuary what the name of the reserve is; actually locating in Uttarkannada district of Karnataka which is abundantly rich in wide varieties of flora and fauna. Being spread over an area of 834.16 sq.km, this reserve is reputed as the largest sanctuary in Karnataka. The sanctuary is also counted amongst the most attractive tourist spots in Karnataka.
\n\n\tNumerous tourists from Karnataka and all over the India come and visit the sanctuaries every year to witness the wildlife while having jungle safari, or from a boat. The calm and blissful serenity all across the reserve with a diversified varieties of floras and faunas are the added attraction to the area.
\n\n\tThe formation of Dandeli National Park is actually a joint venture with the adjoining Anshi National Park and together they were granted the status of Project Tiger Reserve. In the year January 2007, the area was together named as Ansheli Dandeli Tiger Reserve by including the area of 340 sq km. Today, the area of Dandeli National Park by adjoining the areas of Anshi National Park together with six other adjacent protected areas in the states of Goa and Maharashtra forms the most uninterrupted protected forest area of over 2,200 sq km.
\n\n\tThe area of Dandeli that exhibits the wide ranges of flora attraction is actually plush with the southern evergreen forest. The tourists can find wide ranges of plant life, magical herbs, and shrubs. Dominant species are Mango, Jamun, Hirda, Behda, Bamboo, Shrub, Teak, Jamba, Ficus, Herbs, Climber, Grass, and Fern can also be visible here to complement the captivating landscapes.
\n\n\tBy Air : Belgaum (110 km,), Hubli (75 km,) and Goa (150 km.), Bangalore (3481 km.)
\n\n\tBy Rail : Alnavar (32 km.) Londa (48 km.), Dharwad (57 km.), Karwar (117 km.) and Hubli
\n\n\tBy Road : Dandeli is well connected to Bangalore, Mumbai, Goa, Belgaum, Karwar and Dharwad and Hubli by road. Several buses ply to Dandeli every day. Pick up and drop facility from closest destination is available on request.
</string>

    <string name="gard_nagarhole_national_park_desc">\tNagarhole National Park also knows as Rajiv Gandhi National Park is located in the two districts of Karnataka, namely Mysore and Kodagu. Nagarhole a combination of two Kannada words ‘Nagara’ signifying ‘Cobra’ and ‘Hole’ signifying ‘River’, justifies its name completely as several streams serpentine through the rich tropical forest of this national park.
\n\n\tSpread in an area of 247 square-miles, the park was initially a hunting reserve for the royals of Wodeyar dynasty, one time rulers of Kingdom of Mysore. The park was established as a wildlife sanctuary in 1955 and was upgraded into a national park in 1988. The park was declared as the 37th Tiger reserve in 1999. This national park may soon become a World Heritage Site, as it is into consideration by UNESCO World Heritage Committee.
\n\n\tCounted as one of the well-kept national parks of India, Nagarhole is a delight for lovers of Indian Tigers and Asiatic Elephants. Dotting with captivating flora and fauna; this park has numerous varieties of wildlife present in it.
\n\n\tSloth Bears, Leopards, Tigers, Wild Dogs, Sambar, Four-Horned Antelopes, Spotted Deer, Barking Deer, Elephant and Wild Boars are some of the easily spotted animals of this park. One can even become witness to a large variety of amphibians and birds here.
\n\n\tThe River Kabini revolves around the park creating an aqueous edge with the Bandipur National Park. This combined area forms the largest conterminous forest cover towards this part of the world. This entire forest cover is abode to the largest herbivorous density in Asia and largest Asiatic Elephant density in the entire world.
\n\n\tThe vegetation in this park predominantly comprises of moist, tropical and mixed deciduous forest, with some portions being the dry deciduous type. Rosewood, Sandalwood, Teakwood and Silver Oak are some of the more commercially important and easily available trees in this area.
\n\n\tDry deciduous trees include Indian Kino Tree, Crepe myrtle, Grewiatilaefolia, Crocodile Bark and Axlewood. Apart from these Cotton tree, Golden shower tree, Kadam, Tick clover, Ficus, India gooseberry, Tadasalu (Grewia tilaefolia) Horse nettles, Lantana, Bonesets, Mathi (Terminalia tomentosa), Honne (Pterocarpus marsupium) Nandi (Lagerstroemia lanceolata), and Clumping bamboo etc. can also be found germinating here.
\n\n\tOctober to May is the best season to visit Nagarhole National Park. The park usually remains closed during June to September, which is the rainy season here.
\n\n\tBy Air: The closest airport to the national park is in Mysore at a distance of 96 kms. The nearest international airport is located in Bangalore, which is at a distance of 236 kms. One can reach Bangalore from all the major cities across India. It is well connected with several international cities as well.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Mysore Railway Station located 80 kms away from Nagarhole  National Park is the nearest railway station. The nearest railway head is located in Bangalore at a distance of 220 kms. Bangalore is well connected with all the major cities across India. And one can take either a taxi or bus to reach the national park from here.
\n\n\tBy Road: The sanctuary is located at a distance of 96 kms from Mysore city, 93 kms from Madikeri and 236 kms from Bangalore city.
</string>

    <string name="gard_ranganathittu_bird_sanctuary_desc">\tThe tiny 0.67 square kilometer Ranganathittu Bird Sanctuary is a haven for nature lovers and bird watchers. Located in the Mandya district of Karnataka, Ranganathittu is regarded as one of Asia’s most significant nesting and breeding ground for birds. A large number of exotic migratory species visit the sanctuary annually.
\n\n\tRanganathittu is located on the banks of the Kaveri River. In fact, it was formed when a dam was built across the Kaveri river in the 18th century. This resulted in the creation of six islets on the banks of the river. Fed by the monsoon rains, the river is rich in aquatic insects. This along with the relative isolation of the area, attracted birds and soon Ranganthittu became a favored nesting and breeding site for birds.
\n\n\tWhile the sanctuary is known for its birds, there are enough species of animals to interest wild life enthusiasts. The sanctuary is home to animals like the Flying Fox, Bonnet Macaque, Indian Mongoose and Mugger Crocodiles.
\n\n\tThe birds that can be spotted include the White Ibis, Lesser Whistling Duck, and Wolly-necked stork, Asian Open Bill Stork, Common Spoonbill and the Painted Stork. These birds fly in from far-away lands and are found at the sanctuary during the migratory season.
\n\n\tMost of these birds can be seen in the sanctuary from December onwards. They breed and stay here until their little ones are ready to fly out. The permanent members of the park include the colorful peacock and kingfisher.
\n\n\tA spot of bird watching combined with a picnic on the river bank is an ideal way to have fun at the sanctuary. A boat ride along the river bank is also a great experience. As you drift along the six main islets that comprise the sanctuary, you can catch a glimpse of several rare species of birds.
\n\n\tThe sanctuary is located 19 kilometers from Mysore city and is close to the historic town of Srirangapatna. So a visit to Ranganathittu can be combined with a spot of history-gazing or with a visit to the beautiful city of Mysore.
\n\n\tThe sanctuary is located on the Bangalore-Mysore highway and can be reached easily from both cities. The nearest railway station is Mysore. Accommodation at the resort is rather limited and most visitors prefer to stay at Mysore.
\n\n\tThe best time for a visit to Ranganathittu would be between June and November, when there are plenty of nesting birds here. If you want to catch the migratory birds, then you would have to time your visit in the winter months.
</string>

    <string name="gard_bannerghatta_national_park_desc">\tThe Bannerghatta National Park is hailed as one of the most famous and prominent of all national parks in India. This man-made park is home to several species of birds and animals and it attracts children and adults alike through its varied wildlife.
\n\n\tSpread across a sprawling area of over 104.27 sq. km, the Bannerghatta National Park was established in the year 1971. The park has been famously hailed for housing a wide variety of birds and animals and is especially known for its tiger and lion safari. Boasting of an exquisite variety of flora and fauna, the park is a treat for animal lovers and children.
\n\n\tThe park encompasses ten reserve forests of the Anekal Range under the Bangalore Forest Division. Situated at a distance of 22 km from the city of Bangalore, the park houses a zoo, conservatories, and a museum.
\n\n\tFeast your eyes on a wide array of wild animals including the likes of Leopards, Lions, Zebras, Bengal Tigers, Panthers, Porcupines, Rhinoceroses, Elephants, Spotted Deer’s, White Tigers, Bison, Panthers, and Bears.
\n\n\tThe park authorities have divided the park into separate sections for herbivores and carnivores. Private safaris can be organized as well, but authorities have to be contacted with regards to this aspect.
\n\n\tThe park is normally closed on every Tuesday. It is open through the rest of the week from 9:00 AM to 5:00 PM. Although the park has a tropical climate throughout the year, the best times to visit is between September and January.
\n\n\tBy Air: Bangalore airport is the nearest point from the park.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Bangalore railway station is the closest point from the park.
\n\n\tBy Road: The park is located an hour’s drive away from the city of Bangalore. There are regular buses that connect the various areas of Bangalore to Bannerghatta National Park.
</string>

    <string name="gard_bandipur_national_park_desc">\tBandipur is a beautiful tourist spot and considered as one of the best wild life sanctuaries in the country.  India’s one of the best known tiger sanctuaries is Bandipur National Park.
\n\n\tThe park includes rocky hills and valleys drained by rivers Kabini, Nugu, Moyar and numerous small streams. The enchanting Nilgiri Mountains and their cloud-covered peaks form a picturesque backdrop for the park. Bandipur National Park’s altitude between 680 – 1,454 metres and is situated south of the Kabini river at the foothills of the Western Ghats.
\n\n\tMonsoon from June to September and best time to visit is open throughout the year but preferably in monsoon when wildlife is plenty and forest is green.
\n\n\tBandipur National Park lies at the heart of an extensive forest at the confluence of the Western Ghats and Nilgiri Hills. It was created at 800 kms site in the Bandipur Reserve Forest in 1931.
\n\n\tBandipur Tiger Reserve was constituted in 1973 by carving out 880 kms from the Wildlife Park, has boasted constant rise in Tiger population. Also famous for Sandal wood trees and rare species of Flora.
\n\n\tThe Maharajas of Mysore used the Bandipur forests as a private game reserve. The late Maharaja Jaya Chamaraja Wodeyar, the founding Chairman of the Indian Board of Wildlife was a keen wildlife enthusiast. With its location under the shadow of the Western Ghats, Bandipur is easily one of the finest habitats of the Asian Elephant and Gaurs in their natural surroundings.
\n\n\tTiger, Leopard, Elephant, Gaur, Sambar (deer), Chital, Sloth bear, Mouse deer, Wild dog, Wild boar, Barking deer, Four horned Antelope, Hyena, Gaur, Panther, Sloth bear, Crocodiles, Mouse deer, Python, Osprey are some of the animals.
\n\n\tGrey Junglefowl, Pompadour Green Pigeon, Honey Buzzard, Red-headed Vulture, Grey-headed Fish Eagle, Brown Hawk Owl, Bay Owl, Malabar Trogon, Nilgiri Flycatcher, Malabar Pied Hornbill, Little Spiderhunter, Plain Flower pecker are some of the birds.
\n\n\tReptiles like King Cobra, Common Cobra, Python, Adder, Viper, Rat Snake, Water Snake, Marsh Crocodile, Lizard, Chameleon, Monitor Lizard, Frog, Tree frog, Toad and Tortoise are seen in this reserve.
\n\n\tHow to reach: After driving to Mysore one has to take the route to Ooty.
\n\n\tDistance: From Bangalore 220 km, Mysore 80 km, Ooty 80 km.
\n\n\tNearest Town: Mysore and Ooty.
\n\n\tNearest Railway: Mysore.
\n\n\tNearest Airport: Mysore Airport.
</string>

    <string name="gard_anshi_national_park_desc">\tPlan a holiday to Anshi National Park to experience the astounding scenic beauty of this park. An animal lover will surely fall in love with Anshi National Park, which is set amidst the beautiful mountains of the Western Ghats.
\n\n\tAnshi National Park is located in a pristine part of the Western Ghats and is known for the richness of its flora and fauna. It is located at a distance of 60 km from Karwar in Uttar Kannada district. The park spans across an area of 340 sq. km and is believed to be India’s most endangered Wildlife Park.
\n\n\tThis place boasts of about 197 rare species of birds. Tourists interested in bird watching activity must visit Anshi National Park in Karnataka as the forest has a variety of rare bird species. The perfect time for bird watching is in the spring season when the trees are at full blossom.
\n\n\tIt has the rare distinction of being the only park in Asia where Black Panther is found naturally. Anshi National Park has a variety of species of mammals and reptiles. The forest comprises both rain forests and deciduous forests. A huge array of flora and fauna is found in the Anshi National Park, and it is an ideal home ground for species such as elephants, tigers, deer, black panthers, and wild boars. Not only this, there are variety of reptiles in the forest.
\n\n\tJust outside the south eastern boundary of the Park is the Chenna Basaveshwara Temple, which is a popular tourist attraction. If one is planning to stay in the park then unfortunately they will have to change their mind and stay at Dandeli or Dharwad because accommodation is not possible inside the park. If people want to stay inside the park, they should plan for trekking as camps are available for trekkers.
\n\n\tAnshi National Park can be reached by rail, road, and air. Karwar railway station, which is 55 kilometers away, is the nearest one. The nearest airport is Dharwad, which is 106 km from the park. Regular buses from Dandeli to Bangalore, Pune, Panaji, Dharwad, Belgaum, Karwar, and Mumbai are available. Bangalore is roughly around 590 kilometers from Anshi National Park.
</string>

    <string name="gard_daroji_sloth_bear_sanctuary_desc">\tDaroji Sloth Bear Sanctuary is the only place where one can spot these Sloth bears, who are the honey-lovers endemic to India. The sanctuary is located in Ballari District. The Sanctuary has a rough terrain and during the visit, tourist can spot animals like jackals, wild boards, mongoose, black-naped hares, leopards etc.
\n\n\tThe major attraction is the sloth bear that is abundantly seen in these scrub-covered topographies. The sanctuary maintains a good number of sloth bears who are hidden in the caves in the green-covered hillocks.
\n\n\tThe sanctuary provides a watch tower view to the location where these bears are normally seen in the forests, opposite to the Karadikallu Gudda. The view from the watch tower is amazing and one can enjoy the overall terrain from the top using a binocular.
\n\n\tIt is a spectacular watch to witness animals living in the natural habitat. The big black bears that come out the shady bushes and go hunting on their own to curb their sugar cravings are an ideal watch during the visit to the Sanctuary.
\n\n\tDaroji Bear Sanctuary is abundantly filled with sloth bears, which shelter themselves in the rock-strewn areas hidden under the bushy forests. The bears are fond of sugar and hence most of the areas are covered in sugarcane, Ber fruits, Mahuva and even other crops. The sanctuary is in close proximity with the inhabitants in that area. The bears are experts in climbing trees too. The bears usually hunt in the late evening and then rest throughout the day
\n\n\tThe sloth bear has a long and dark coat like covering of hair around them. Their forelimbs are longer than the hind ones. Since they have small ears and eyes, their sense of hearing and vision is quite poor, but with an impeccable nose for smelling.
\n\n\tThe Sanctuary is spread over 82.7 square km and is exclusively for the preservation of the giant sloth beat, which are now swept away from the phase of earth. The Sanctuary comes under the governance of Kamalapura wildlife subdivision of the Karnataka Forest Department.
\n\n\tThe area in Bellary, between the Daroji in the Taluk of Sandur and Ramasagar located in Hospet, contained many sloth bears. With lots of illegal mining coming up in the forest area, the continuous human appearances threatened the existence of the bears. Hence this Sanctuary was put up and the area where they were abundantly found were declared as the Sanctuary.
\n\n\tBy Road: The easiest way to reach the sanctuary is by road from Bangalore -Chitradurga which is around 199 km and then from there to Hospet close to 135 km. From Hospet to Kamalapura and to the sanctuary takes almost 12 and 10 km respectively. The historic hamlet, Hampi is hardly 20 kms away from the sanctuary.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Nearest railway station to Daroji Sloth Bear Sanctuary is Hospet which is around 22 km away.
\n\n\tBy Air: Hubli is the nearest airport and it lies 143 km away from Hampi. Belgaum airport lies around 720 km away.
</string>

    <string name="gard_jayamangali_blackbuck_desc">\tThe Jayamangali Blackbuck Reserve is located in the Tumkur district of Bangalore. It is located next to Maidenahalli, which is a small village in the Madhugiri Taluk. This reserve is the only notified protected area in the entire district of Tumkur. The area of the reserve is 798 acres with the largest population of blackbucks. Apart from blackbucks, the area consists of Acacia and Eucalyptus plantation.
\n\n\tIn the year 1992, the jurisdiction of this area was handed over from the Department of Revenue to the Forest Department. The forest department fenced this area to protect the reserve and started a nursery. A watchtower was erected to keep a watch over the protected region.
\n\n\tIn 1997, the area was proposed to be declared as a Conservation Reserve. This was finally declared in the year 2007. Out of the proposed 893 acres, an area of 798.33 acres was declared as the conservation reserve and that is how this reserve was born.
\n\n\tThere are more than 80 species of medicinal plants in this area. The reserve has the second largest population of blackbucks in Karnataka.  In the year 2002, a population of 800 blackbucks was recorded. Apart from blackbucks, the area has 67 varieties of butterflies and mammals that include small Indian civet, bats, Indian wolf, rodents, Indian hare, jungle cat, Indian gray mongoose and many more.
\n\n\tThere are 26 species of reptiles and 14 types of snakes. There are 125 bird species in the reserve as well. Many of the species found here are typical of the hot climate and arid region. The reserve is a delight for wildlife enthusiasts.
\n\n\tThe climate gets extreme during different seasons. The temperature goes as low as 8 degrees Celsius in winters and as high as 43 degrees in summer. Monsoon period is from June to October.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit the Conservation Reserve is post monsoon until winters. The temperature during summer is very high and can go up to 40 degrees Celsius. The best time during the day is early morning or late evening.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport is in Bangalore, which is at a distance of 163 kms.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The nearest rail junction is in Hindupur at a distance of 20 kms and in Tumkur which is at a distance of 68 kms.
\n\n\tBy Road: The nearest town is Madhugiri which lies at a distance of 23 kms. Madhugiri can be reached from Bangalore via Tumkur by road. From Bangalore, one can head to Dobbespete to reach Tumkur and from Tumkur, head to Koratgere to reach Madhugiri. There are no lodges or hotels in the area.
</string>

    <string name="gard_ranebennur_blackbuck_desc">\tRanebennur Blackbuck Sanctuary lies in the Haveri district in the State of Karnataka. It is a well-known sanctuary for Blackbuck spotting. It lies at a distance of 301 kms from Bangalore and at a distance of 8 kms from the Ranebennur town.
\n\n\tRanebennur Blackbuck Deer Sanctuary is very well connected with the road network and is easy to reach. It has a total area of 119 sq km and is densely covered with Eucalyptus plantations and a shrub forest.
\n\n\tTourists are allowed to enter in 104. 13 kms of area and the remaining 14.87 kms is the core area of the sanctuary. It is home to the wolf and the endangered Great Indian Bustard. Apart from the great Indian bustard, fauna in the sanctuary include black Drongo, sirkeer cuckoo, peafowl, cuckoo, bay-backed shrike and large grey babbler.
\n\n\tThere are about 6000 Blackbucks in the sanctuary. Ranebennur Blackbuck Sanctuary was declared a wildlife sanctuary in 1974 with the sole aim to protect Blackbucks. It is also an ideal destination for bird watching.
\n\n\tThe vegetation in the sanctuary comprises of Neem trees, Acacia and open grasslands. There are plentiful blackbucks to be seen. Post the establishment of the sanctuary, there has been a constant increase in the population of blackbucks.
\n\n\tOther mammals residing at the sanctuary include fox, langur, wild pig, jackal, hare, porcupine, common mongoose and Pangolin. One can also spot hyenas in the Harinigudda area of the sanctuary.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit the Ranebennur Blackbuck Sanctuary is from October to March. There is a rest house run by the forest department on the sanctuary boundary.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport is at a distance of 119 kms from Haveri in Bellary.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Haveri is well connected by rails and has a good connectivity with all the metros that include Bangalore and Mysore  It has regular trains plying from the metros. Haveri is at a distance of 7 hours from Bangalore.
</string>

    <string name="gard_bankapura_peacock_sanctuary_desc">\tBankapura Peacock Sanctuary is a well-known peacock sanctuary located in the State of Karnataka. It is one of the lesser known destinations in Karnataka. The Bankapura peacock sanctuary is located inside the Bankapura Fort, which lies in Bankapura of the Haveri district. It has an area of 139 acres of land and is only 2.5 kms from the Pune Bangalore highway. It is at a distance of 22 kms from Haveri towards Hubli.
\n\n\tThe sanctuary is well connected by road network. This sanctuary has high significance for being the second sanctuary in the country that is exclusively involved in the conversation and breeding of peacocks. The Department of Veterinary Studies conducts various research and studies at the sanctuary.
\n\n\tBankapura Peacock Sanctuary is located on a cattle breeding farm which has an area of 90 acres out of the total 139 acres in the sanctuary. Fodder is grown exclusively for the Khillari cattle and it has become an ideal peafowl habitat. Maize, jowar and horse gram are grown for the cattle.
\n\n\tEucalyptus plantation is widespread across the area and a shrub forest is also found here. It is estimated that there are more than 1000 peacocks and peahen in this sanctuary. It has become easier for breeding because of the minimal human intervention. Peacocks have a large area of 4 kms to royally walk inside the mound.
\n\n\tYou will also be able to see a variety of other birds apart from peacocks. These include Indian robin, blue tailed bee eater, tailor bird, robin, Nightjar, woodpecker, winged kite, grey hornbill, spotted dove, great-horned owl, parakeets, paradise flycatcher and many more.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport to the sanctuary is Bellary which lies at a distance of 119 kms from Haveri.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Haveri is conveniently connected with metros by rail. There are regular trains from Mumbai, Bangalore, and Chennai. It takes about 7 hours to reach Haveri from Bangalore by train.
\n\n\tBy Road: There is a well-connected road network that links Haveri to the other cities. It is located on the NH-4 which heads towards Mumbai. The sanctuary lies at a distance of 22 kms from Haveri towards Hubli.
</string>

    <string name="gard_kokkare_bellur_pelicanry_desc">\tIf you are looking fora place to escape from the city grind for a day in the months of December March, then Kokkare is an absolute heaven. The village is 83 km from Bangalore, off the Mysore Highway by around 12 km. Getting here can be a bit tricky; so make sure to check the signages on your way here.
\n\n\tThis place is famous for its Spot Billed Pelicans and the Painted Storks that can be sighted here in vast numbers during season time. This scenic village has paddy fields, cattle, water, and lots of exotic birds. The village is in the Maddur Taluka of the Mandya district of Karnataka.
\n\n\tKokkare village is on the banks of the river Shimsha, and it is a very beautiful sight to see the birds in their natural habitat when they arrive in the nesting season over here. The river Shimsha flows ahead and meets the river Kaveri.
\n\n\tThe place is not a traditional sanctuary; the visiting birds here live and mingle freely with the humans. Seeing a Pelican here is as common as seeing a crow or a sparrow.
\n\n\tThe Spot Billed Pelican is an endangered species, and hence, the government makes sure that this region takes various measures to protect the natural habitat to encourage the continued migration of the birds.
\n\n\tThe trees that the birds nest on are the Ficus and the Tamarind trees. There are many agricultural fields and sugarcane plantations. The other birds found in this region are Little Cormorant, Black Ibis, Grey Heron, Black crowned Night Heron, and Indian Pond Heron. Also, Ring Necked Parakeets (Rose Ringed Parakeets) have also been sighted here.
\n\n\tThe route to take to get here is as follows: Bangalore – Bidadi – Ramanagara – Channapatna and before reaching Maddur, you will come to a place named Rudrakshipura. From here, you have to take the inner road for around 12 km till you reach your destination.
</string>

    // Water Falls Description
    <string name="water_jog_falls_desc">\tOne of the highest waterfalls in India Jog Falls is one of the major attractions in Karnataka. Created on Sharavathi River, Jog Falls is also known by alternative names of Gerusoppe Falls, Gersoppa Falls and Jogada Gundi.
\n\n\tJog is located in Shimoga District of Karnataka, 30 km away from Sagara, 104 km from Shimoga, and 379 km away from Bangalore.
\n\n\tJog Falls is formed by the Sharavathi River, gushing down from a height of 253 meters. The river originates at Ambuthirtha in Thirthahalli taluk, flows north-west through the Western Ghats forming the Jog Falls before joining the Arabian Sea at Honavar.
\n\n\tFor a Tour to Jog Falls, the best time to visit is between the months of August and December.
\n\n\tBy Air:The nearest airport is at Bangalore.
\n\n\tBy Rail :You can take a train to Sagara from Bangalore, from where you can get into buses to Jog.
\n\n\tBy Road: You can reach Jog Falls directly by availing of buses to Jog from Bangalore. Alternatively, from Bangalore you can take a bus to Sagara, from where local bus to Jog is available.
</string>

    <string name="water_gokak_falls_desc">\tGokak falls is a waterfall known for its beauty. It is at a distance of 60 Kms from Belgaum and 10 kms from Gokak town. Located right on the main road is a celebrated tourist center in the district. This falls has a height of about 170 feet.
\n\n\tThe river Ghataprabha after winding a course of a long route takes a leap of 52 meters, over a rocky bed 170 feet down. The falls is famous for its spread and shape.Except in width and colour of the water, the general features of the fall, its height, shape and rapidity above are much like those of ” Niagara”.
\n\n\tThe waterfall is horse shoe shaped at the crest, with a flood breadth of 177 metres (580 ft). During rainy season the thick reddish brown water sweeps far over the brink of the cliff with a dull roar that can be heard from some distance.
\n\n\tElectricity was generated here for the first time in the country in 1887. The generating station can be reached on the ropeway. Recommended only for the extra courageous! A walk down either bank of the rocky gorge rewards you with ancient Chalukyan monuments waiting to be explored.
\n\n\tGokak gets its name due to the Goki trees found in abundance in these areas. July to September is the best season to visit the place.
\n\n\tIt is 10 kms from Gokak falls there is a village named Godachinamalki a trek of 2 Kms from here takes you  to a beautiful falls the stream flows in a slow rhythm until the first drop of about 70 feet as one treks to the spot, one comes across a long line of tiny falls that add up to make the big jump.
\n\n\tThe area being a rocky bed facilitates the creation of numerous lovely cascades to give the look of a royal bath in a palace complex.
\n\n\tThe main falls dips again a little further by another 50 feet before joining the Ghataprabha. This is truly rejuvenating falls, unspoilt and devoid of noisy crowds.
</string>

    <string name="water_godchina_malki_falls_desc">\tThe Godachinmalki Falls is a waterfall located on Markandeya river in Belgaum district, Gokak Taluk, Karnataka, India. It is 15 kilometers away from Gokak and 40 kms from Belgaum. It is located in a deep green valley.
\n\n\tGodachinmalki falls, also known as Markandeya falls, is located in a rugged valley, which is approachable from Godachinamalaki village by walking as well as by vehicle through an irregular forest route for about 2 kilometers and there are two routes to reach the falls from Godachinamalki, one is vai Malebail road by crossing bridge at godachinamalki and another one is vai Gurusiddeshwar Temple(Hatti Siddeshwar). It can also be reached from Nirvaneshwara Matha near Yogikolla, only by foot.
\n\n\tTo reach Godachinamalki Falls from Belgaum vai Ankalagi, Pachhapur and Mavanur, frequent bus facility is available from Belgaum and Gokak and nearest railway station is Pachhapur, which is about 8 kilometers and good train facility is available from Belgaum to Miraj, all most all trains stops in Pachhapur railway station . There are actually two falls formed here. The Markandeya river takes a first fall from a height of about 25 metres and flows into a rocky valley. After a short distance from the rocky valley, it takes the second fall from a height of about 20 metres. Within 10 km distance Gokak falls is located from Godachinamalki vai Melmanahatti and Maradimath. Later Markandeya river joins Ghataprabha river near Gokak. Within a 6 km radius there are two dams; one built across Ghataprabha river (Hidkal dam) and another one (Shirur Dam) across Markandeya river.
\n\n\tBest time for visiting this place is during the month of July-October (Rainy Season). There is no entry fees. There are no specific timings, a daytime visit in recommended.
</string>

    <string name="water_abbey_falls_desc">\tIf your idea of enjoying the monsoon is dancing in the rain, you ought to do so in the most natural setting possible. Being amidst the lush green environs of the scenic Abbey Falls can only add to the spectacle of monsoon and make you literally dance in joy. As one of Karnatakas amazing natural attractions, Abbey Falls in Coorg is a destination that you just cannot miss exploring during the monsoon. But this doesnt mean that its not worth visiting in the other seasons. After all, as they say, a thing of beauty is a joy forever.
\n\n\tNestled near Madikeri, Abbey Falls stands surrounded by a blanket of greenery. It is also known as Abbi Falls. To reach the waterfall, you will have to drive up to its entrance and then cover a short distance on foot.
\n\n\tAs you make your way to the waterfall, you will be greeted by lush plantations of spice and coffee. The roar of the water along with the aroma of the plantations is a delight in itself. The brilliant view of the waterfall from the hanging bridge running opposite to the waterfall is a sight to cherish. Guarded by tall trees with pepper vines for a company, Abbey Falls sparkles as if a stream of white pearls is running down a green wall at a great speed. But if you happen to be standing on the hanging bridge right after the monsoons, the voluminous waterfall will leave you soaked by its spray of water.
\n\n\tA number of small streams come together to form the sizzling cascade at Abbey Falls. The cascade gushes down a height of 70 feet to form a pool below that joins the River Cauvery. During the monsoon season, as the streams widen and the level of water increases, the rush down the cascade becomes thicker and lovelier to watch.
\n\n\tSince the Abbey Falls is at its peak form during the monsoon season, it is the best time to experience its beauty. So, July to October is the ideal time to plan a trip to the Abbey Falls. But if you want to avoid the rains, you can plan your trip at any time of the year.
\n\n\tIf you are planning to spend a couple of hours at the spot, you need to carry some light food items with you. There is no food stall located near the Abbey Falls. But on the way to the waterfall, you will come across a few roadside stalls selling tea, water, and snacks.
</string>

    <string name="water_barachukki_falls_desc">\tBarachukki and Gaganachukki are two waterfalls situated near the island town of Shivanasamudra in the Mandya district of Karnataka.
\n\n\tThe waterfalls are created by river Cauvery that runs down a 75 metre gorge before it divides into two branches that flow around the island of Shivanasamudra. The two branches (eastern and western branches) flow through deep ravines on either side of the island before plunging in two different places a few kilometres apart to form the Barachukki and Gaganachukki waterfalls.
\n\n\tThe waterfalls are located at a distance of about 139 km from Bangalore and about 60 km from Mysore.
\n\n\tThe eastern branch of the waterfall is known as Barachukki while the western branch is known as Gaganachukki. Barachukki and Gaganachukki waterfalls are together known as the Shivanasamudra Falls.
\n\n\tShivanasamudra literally means Shivas Sea. These two waterfalls are considered to be among the best 100 waterfalls of the world.
</string>

    <string name="water_benne_hole_falls_desc">\tBenne Hole Falls is one of the most spectacular waterfalls in North Karnataka. North Karnataka is said to have a number of waterfalls and one such picturesque waterfall is Benne Hole waterfalls. The name Benne Hole is because of the white creamy look of the waterfall. In Kannada, Benne is butter and hole refer to big stream, hence the name.
\n\n\tThe waterfall is formed by the tributary of the river Aghanashini, which flows through the dense forests of the Devimane Ghats region in the Western Ghats. The waterfall falls from a height of 200ft forming an alluring treat to ones eye.
\n\n\tBenne Hole Falls is known for trekking and the 2km trek to the top of falls is both arduous and a herculean task. One has to be adept and know the intricacies of trekking to reach the top. The view from the top of the falls is breathtaking and worth the hardships faced during the trek. Along with trekking, the tourist also can look out for some exotic birds. Some of the exotic birds found in Benne Hole waterfall area are grey jungle fowl, wooly necked stork, jungle owlet, coppersmith barbet, orange minivet, black headed oriole, common kestrel and plum-headed parakeet.
\n\n\tThe waterfall is located at about 26 kms from Sirsi. One has to first reach a village called Kasage, which is about 21 kms from Sirsi and from there the falls are about 5 kms away. The first 3 kms can be covered by jeep and next 2 kms by walk.
    </string>

    <string name="water_chunchanakatte_falls_desc">\tChunchanakatte Falls is part of the river Kaveri, Krishnaraja Nagar taluk of Mysore district. It is famous for the Kodanda Rama temple on the banks. It is believed that Goddess Sita took a bath in this holy waters at Dhanuskoti thus rendering a turmeric tinge to the water.
\n\n\tBrahma Rathotsava (car festival) is held on January 15th of every year. A holy dip in the river could be considered but one must take caution of the high current during monsoons. A big cattle festival is held during August.
\n\n\tBesides the picturesque falls, this place boasts of greenery and migratory birds. There is an Hydral power station nearby. The power plant was started in 1994 and completed (two units) in 1998. The power station has a capacity of 18 MW (9 MW each).
\n\n\tBest time to visit this falls is during January-February.Only road transport is possible. Private and Government transport is available to Chunchanakatte from K.R.Nagar.
\n\n\tNearest Railway Station: Mysore.
\n\n\tNearest Airport: Mysore Airport, Bangalore International Airport.
\n\n\tBy Road: From Bangalore 140 km, Mysore 54 km, K.R.Nagar 14 km.</string>

    <string name="water_kalhatti_giri_falls_desc">\tKalhatti Giri Falls (Kalahasti Falls) is in Chikmagalur district at Kallathipura in Karnataka.  The waterfall is in an elegant location and is a beautiful cascading waterfall amidst the luscious greenery. The waterfall from the Chandra Drona hills around 122 meters height above.
\n\n\tThe fall is in the front of Veerabhadreshwara temple dedicated to Lord Shiva. The Kemmangundi hill station is around 10km from the waterfall. The waterfall is surrounded by captivating valleys and gardens, which is indeed a visual treat to visitors.
\n\n\tIt is believed that Saint Agastya did pray here for a long time. The temple dedicated to Lord Shiva, the Veerabhadreshwara temple was supposed to be built during the Vijayanagara times.
\n\n\tThe temple contains three stone carvings of elephants at the entrance which depicts the Vijayanagara architecture. The cascading waterfall falls over these three elephants always. The people believe that the water is sacred and can cure many diseases.
\n\n\tLord Veerabhadrashwara temple celebrates the annual fair every March-April which is visited by many pilgrims and lasts for three days.
\n\n\tBy Road: Birur in Chikmagalur is the nearest station to the waterfalls. Birur is well connected to Bangalore and other places via Road. Bangalore is 245 km from Kalahtta Giri waterfalls and Mangalore is 150 km.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The nearest railway station is Birur. From Birur one can hire a taxi or auto rickshaw as it takes 30 mins. Birur is connected to Shimoga, Bangalore etc. by train.
\n\n\tBy Air: Mangalore is the nearest airport to Kalahatta Giri waterfalls around 180 km. From the airport one can take up buses or ca to reach the waterfall.
</string>

    <string name="water_sathodi_falls_desc">\tSathodi Falls is a wonderful and picturesque rectangular shaped waterfall in the Uttara Kannada region in Yellapur district. The place is less packed with tourists, but indeed a beautiful waterfall to sight. The water falls from a height of 15m and forms a pool beneath. The stream of water contains a jumble of rocks and sometimes impossible to approach Sathodi Falls.
\n\n\tIn between the bushes and the rocky terrain, there are small pathways leading to the waterfalls. The water flow is formed by the union of many other rivers that flow to Kallarmane Ghat, in Uttara Kannada region. The water that forms the waterfalls then flows into the River Kali through the Dam Kodasalli. The waterfall is found amidst the Ghats and the evergreen forests that truly bring out the marvelous beauty of the waterfall. Sathodi Falls is not very approachable because of the rocks.
\n\n\tSathodi Falls is a wonderful and picturesque rectangular shaped waterfall in the Uttara Kannada region in Yellapur district. The place is less packed with tourists, but indeed a beautiful waterfall to sight. The water falls from a height of 15m and forms a pool beneath. The stream of water contains a jumble of rocks and sometimes impossible to approach Sathodi Falls.
\n\n\tIn between the bushes and the rocky terrain, there are small pathways leading to the waterfalls. The water flow is formed by the union of many other rivers that flow to Kallarmane Ghat, in Uttara Kannada region. The water that forms the waterfalls then flows into the River Kali through the Dam Kodasalli. The waterfall is found amidst the Ghats and the evergreen forests that truly bring out the marvelous beauty of the waterfall. Sathodi Falls is not very approachable because of the rocks.
\n\n\tSathodi Falls is the embodiment of natural beauty that is admired by many. The rock formations around the waterfalls form a natural enclosure with the bountiful greenery and the clear and crystal water below. The waterfall has water all-around the year. Being fed by multiple tributaries the waterfall always has water. The water body formed below is ideal for a dip. One can enjoy the cool waters and swim through the clear water. The serene place is ideal for a picnic.
\n\n\tBy Road: Yellapur (32km) is the closest destination to Sathodi Falls. From Bangalore (423 km) one can hire a cab or even take up KSRTC buses to reach Yellapur and from Yellapur tourists can hire an auto or a cab to reach the waterfalls.
\n\n\tBy Air: Hubli (68km) is the nearest airport to Yellapur. Hubli is connected to major cities like Bangalore and Mysore. From Hubli, one can hire a taxi or take up a bus to reach Yellapur and then to Sathodi Falls.
\n\n\tBy Train: Hubli (68km) is the nearest railway station to Yellapur. From Yellapur one can take up a bus or taxi to reach the waterfall.
</string>

    <string name="water_sural_falls_desc">\tSural Falls is one of the most amazing natural sights in Karnataka. The beautiful waterfall is located at a distance of 32 km from Khanapur in the Belgaum district of Karnataka. Nestled amongst the greenery of the Western Ghats the picturesque waterfall is also known as ‘Venezuela of Karnataka. The waterfall is about 300 feet deep and presents an impressive sight all year round.
\n\n\tSural Falls is also one of the most famous trekking routes of Karnataka. The pristine beauty of the waterfall and the splendid forest cover makes it an ideal trekking destination.
\n\n\tSural Falls attracts visitors throughout the year for its splendid beauty. However, it holds special attraction for the trekkers and nature lovers. It is one of the most famous treks of the Kankumbi forest region. The trek begins at Kalsa in Karnataka. It runs through the rocky bed of Kalsa stream and crosses the majestic Kalsa waterfall before reaching the Sural Falls. The trek culminates on reaching the Sural Valley after crossing the picturesque waterfall.
\n\n\tThough the waterfall can be visited throughout the year, the best time to visit it is during the moderate monsoon. The deep waterfall becomes a lovely sight during the rainy season.
\n\n\tThe easiest way to reach Sural Falls is to reach Belgaum. Belgaum is easily accessible by several means of transport. The place can be reached by road, air and rail transport from various parts of the country.
\n\n\tBy Road: Belgaum has a very well connected road network. Four national highways pass through Belgaum and connect it to Maharashtra, Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu. Buses run by the North West Karnataka Road Transport Corporation (NWKRTC) connect Belgaum to other corners of the state. There are a few private buses that carry passengers to Belgaum from other cities and towns of Karnataka.
\n\n\tBy Air: The Belgaum Airport has been serving the city for many decades now. There are flights connecting Belgaum to Bangalore.
\n\n\tBy Train: Belgaum has one of the oldest railway stations in the region. The rail network connects Belgaum to several other places within and outside Karnataka. There are trains that connect Belgaum to Mysore, Bangalore, Pune, Goa, Mumbai, New Delhi, Chennai and several other places.
</string>

    <string name="water_vibhooti_falls_desc">\tVibhooti Falls is one of the many waterfalls in the Western Ghats. Surrounded by large rocks and limestone deposits, the waterfall is a picturesque spot. The water flows in steps that make it the ideal refuge spot for hot summers.
\n\n\tSet about 50 kilometers from Sirsi in North Kanara, the waterfall gets its name from the limestone rock found in the area. Vibhooti also translates to mean ash. According to local legends, the waterfall was formed when ashes from the burning of Basmasur had washed away. It is also known as the Mabgi Falls because of its proximity to a village by the same name.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit the waterfall is between October and March. At this time the water levels are at their highest and gush over the rocks.
\n\n\tBy Road: The Vibhooti Falls are about 400kms away from Bangalore and 50kms from Sirsi. KSRTC buses and private taxis ply regularly between Sirsi and the Vaddi cross. From here, the Waterfall is a short walk away.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Sirsi is the closest railway station to the Vibhooti Falls. The station is around 44 kilometers.
\n\n\tBy Air: At a distance of 252km, the Mangalore International Airport is the closest airport.
</string>

    <string name="water_unchalli_falls_desc">\tThe picturesque Unchalli Falls close by Uttara Kannada is famous for its Unchalli (Lushington) Falls was discovered by J.D. Lushington in 1845, a district collector of the British Government. Aghanashini river creates this water cascade which screams down from a height of about 450 feet.
\n\n\tUnchalli falls is near Yellapur (19 km) in Uttara Kannada. This is also known as Mini Niagara or  Keppa Falls is another name for its unique sound. Cascading from a height of 170 feet, it is famous for its spread and shape. This falls must be visited in July-August when it will be in full bloom.
\n\n\tTrekking 5 km from the Heggarne village along the dense forests can be an exciting experience. The steep mountain slopes and tracks,  deep gorges, chilly breeze and the amazing flora and the rare avian species accompany you until you reach the roaring Unchali Falls plummeting down.
\n\n\tBy Road: Siddapura Taluk in North Kanara by road or From Bangalore 400 kms, Sirsi 25 kms.
\n\n\tBy Train: Nearest railway station Sirsi town.
\n\n\tBy Air: Nearest Airport Goa Dabolim Airport.</string>

    <string name="water_almatti_dam_desc">\tThe Almatti Dam is in a Bijapur, a small town Northern Karnataka,  and is built across the Krishna river. The construction was done in 2005, so it is a relatively new dam. It is the main reservoir of the Upper Krishna Irrigation Project and it uses Kaplan Turbines.
\n\n\tWater is released into the Narayanpur reservoir once it uses it for power generation and serves the irrigation requirements.  The height was increased by 10 meters in this dam after the Supreme Court ordered to do so.
\n\n\tThere are about seven terrace gardens that have been built as a picnic spot in Almatti dam area. Musical fountains, stagnant fountains, boating facilities etc. have been set up here for people who wish to visit it. This makes it a great tourist attraction. There is a garden named ‘Rock Hill situated on one of side of this Dam. It also has an artificial forest with ceramic wild animals.
</string>

    <string name="water_tungabhadra_dam_desc">\tThe Tungabhadra Dam or TB Dam also is known as Pampa Sagar, is a reservoir constructed across the Tungabhadra River a tributary of the Krishna River. The dam Located almost 20 kilometers south-west of Hampi town, in Munirabad, Koppal district in the town Hospet in Karnataka. Tungabhadra Dam looks extremely beautiful at the sunset with water showing you how it cools the suns hotness and the Dams green lights start engulfing the darkness again.
\n\n\tConstruction began in 1949 and completed by 1953 the Dam total length is 2,449 m (8,035 ft) and height is 49.50 m (162 ft) from the deepest foundation with total Spillway capacity 650,000 cusecs. It has been built by cement and granite. Left of it two barrages have been con¬structed (one earthen and another of stone and surkhi). The reservoir spreads over 378 sq. km. of area with a storage capacity of 4 lakh hectares.
\n\n\tThe dam serves multiple functions as it controls irrigation, electricity generation, flood control and much more. Today it is a joint project between the states of Andhra Pradesh and Karnataka, and serves purposes of functionality and attracts tourists from across India as well. For those visiting for tourism, the views from atop this reservoir are simply magnificent, and a simple walk along the river is sure to please even the toughest critics. A hydroelectric project of the dam is famous and become a new lifeline of State of Karnataka.
\n\n\tPower houses-three powerhouses have been constructed under the project. First of these lies on the left side at Munirabad (Karnataka) with an installed capacity of 27 MW. The second powerhouse at Hospet has eight generating units of 9 m w each (total capacity 72 MW). The third powerhouse has been built near Hampi along the canal with an installed capacity of 27 MW. This total of 126 MW of electricity is utilized in irrigation and development of small and cottage industries.
\n\n\tTungabhadra High-Level Canal with 196 km length provides irrigation to 1.82 lakh hec¬tares of land in Bellary and Anantapur districts. Tungabhadra project is mainly an irrigation project which has helped in augmenting the area under cotton, groundnut, rice, sugarcane, jowar, and other crops.
</string>

    <string name="water_krs_dam_desc">\tThe Krishna Raja Sagara Dam, popularly known as KRS Dam, is built on the river Kaveri and its tributaries, Hemavathi and Lakshmana Theertha. The KRS Dam and the ornamental garden, Brindavan Gardens, attached to the dam are one of the most visited tourist spots in Mysore. The dam was planned and built over a hundred years ago with traditional materials and techniques. Maharaja Nalwadi Krishnaraja Wadiyar IV had the dam constructed to help the people of the kingdom during a severe drought. Planned by Sir M Visvesvaraya, the chief engineer of Mysore, KRS Dam was the first dam to install automated crest gates. The dam is still a major source of drinking water for people and provides irrigation in Mandya, Mysore and Bangalore.
\n\n\tThe construction of the Krishna Raja Sagar Dam, which would provide drinking water and be a source of irrigation, started in November 1911. Over 10,000 workers were employed for the construction of KRS dam in the Kannambadi village. According to the initial plan, the gravity dam was to be 194-feet high with the capacity to hold 41,500,000,000 cu ft (1.18 km3) of water. But this plan had to be dropped and the structure that stands today is 131 feet high with a total capacity to hold 1,368,847,000 m3 of water.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit KRS Dam is during or after the monsoon season (June to August). Due to heavy rainfall, the water level of the dam increases and sometimes the water gushes out of the gates as they automatically open on reaching 124 feet.
\n\n\tLocated just 24 km away from Mysore, KRS Dam can be easily visited through city buses. These buses from the city bus stand are available to drop one directly near KRS Dam. If you are coming from the railway station, you can either take the auto-rickshaws or state-owned buses. It will take a few hours to reach the KRS dam.
\n\n\tIt is 24 km from Mysore. It is 143.5 km away from Bangalore. It is 480.3 km away from Chennai. It is located 2.2 km from Venugopala Swamy Temple.
</string>

    <string name="water_hidkal_dam_desc">\tRaja Lakhamagouda dam, also known as Hidkal dam, is a dam constructed across the Ghataprabha River in the Krishna River basin. It is situated at Hidkal village in Hukkeri Taluk of Belagavi district in North Karnataka, India.
\n\n\tThe dam with the height of 62.48 metres and 10 Vertical Crest Gates, impounds a large reservoir with a gross surface area of 63.38 Square kilometres, and storage capacity of 51.16 Tmcft.
\n\n\tIt is an earthen and masonry dam which caters to the Irrigation needs for over 8,20,000 acres, and Hydel power generation.
\n\n\tIt is constructed as a part of the Ghataprabha Irrigation project which was completed in three phases and finished in 2009. The dam is named after Raja Lakhamagouda Sardesai, philanthropist and Zamindar of Vantamuri.
</string>
    <string name="title_activity_splash">SplashActivity</string>
    <!--
    This string is used for square devices and overridden by hello_world in
    values-round/strings.xml for round devices.
    -->
    <string name="hello_world">Hello Square World!</string>

</resources>