<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Travel Guide</string>

    <string name="implementation_on_fragment_listener"> must implement OnFragmentInteractionListener</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="transaction_name" translatable="false">places</string>
    <string name="transaction_title_name" translatable="false">placeTitle</string>


    // Beaches Description
    <string name="beaches_gokarna_beach_desc">\tGokarna Beaches are the chief tourist attractions in the holy town of Gokarna. The name itself has been derived from Go (holy cow) and Karna (ears); hence, it has considerable mythological reverence as well.
\n\n\tPart of a largely Hindu domain, the tourists also pay homage to the famous Mahabaleswara temple, which is a renowned Shiva temple (a major Hindu deity), Maha Ganapathy temple, the Uma Maheshwari temples, and a host of other well-know temples for which this tourist spot is also famous.
\n\n\tGokarna is remotely populated with its nearest connection being Goa to its north and the city of Bangalore is located roughly around 275 miles to its east.
\n\n\tFor those looking at convenient air-travel, Dabolim in Goa is by far the nearest airport. From Dabolim, travel enthusiasts can either opt for train services or simply hire a cab to reach Gokarna in close to 4 hours.
\n\n\tOther nearby cities on international maps can be located in Madgaon also in Goa and Mangalore. For all the first timers, this tourist spot offers warm and pleasant weather conditions with an average Celsius temperature of around 30 degrees.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_karwar_beach_desc">\tKarwar, situated on the banks of river Kali, is the administrative headquarters of Uttara Kannada district in Karnataka. It is a beautiful sea side town, which is located on the Goa-Karnataka border and 519 km from Bangalore. Situated on the western coast, this scenic place is worth a visit.
\n\n\tKarwar gets it name from the word “Karwad” as the British had trouble pronouncing it during the colonial times. In 1862, British made this place their head quarters. Karwar was the sea trade center from the Arabian Sea and Arabs, Dutch, Portuguese, French and British have traded here.
\n\n\tIn Arabic, Karwar was called “Baithkhol “ meaning bay of safety. Ibn battuta passed through this tract. Many Indian commodities were exported to foreign countries were brought from the Deccan by routes as this port was considered safe during all seasons. The port of Karwar has five islands, Anjidiv, Kudumgad, Dev gad, Mogral and Shamshigudda protecting the port from heavy winds.</string>

    <string name="beaches_kaup_beach_udupi_desc">\tKaup Beach is one of the major beaches in the city of Mangalore. With its tropical climate and bevy of attractions that beckon tourists from across the country, Mangaluru is a port city that promises to keep uplifting your spirits every minute you spend in this city.
\n\n\tKaup or Kapu as the place is known in the local Tulu language is a village town located between Udupi and Mangaluru in the state of Karnataka. The region is predominantly known for one of the most serene and pristine beaches that you can find. Owing to the greenery surrounding the beach on all sides, tourists make a bee-line towards this place for a quick weekend trip away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
\n\n\tAlthough Kaup hasn’t been explored on a full-fledged level, the beach attracts many tourists and there have instances of films being shot in the beach and the surrounding areas as well. Kaup beach is famously known to house an old lighthouse that was apparently built in the year 1901. The lighthouse is open for visitors during certain periods of time in the course of the day. It offers a delightful view of the entire beach and seashore that will surely take your breath away.
\n\n\tBesides the lighthouse, Kaup also has ruins of Jain Basadis that line across the stretch of sand, and these are definitely worth a visit. Kaup is the base for two Hindu temples dedicated to the Goddess Mariamman. The best time to visit Kaup Beach is from October to December.
\n\n\tThis beach is also popular with students who come from Manipal, a student town. The beach also has small shacks and eateries where one can sample a bit of the local cuisine.</string>

    <string name="beaches_malpe_beach_udupi_desc">\tMalpe Beach in Karnataka is one of the unexplored beaches in India. Located at a distance of 66 kms from Mangalore and about 6 kms from Udupi, the Malpe Beach is an undefiled virgin beach. The beach has a never-ending coastline, which is surrounded by three rocky islands on the western side. Earlier, Malpe was a port on the coast of Karnataka which is now an ideal destination for a holiday away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
\n\n\tMalpe is the first Indian beach with a 24/7 WiFi. It is also an important port and a fishing harbor in the state of Karnataka. Being the largest port in Karnataka, Malpe has a considerable population engaged in fisheries and tile manufacturing.
\n\n\tThe Malpe Beach has a pleasant weather and clean white sand which makes it ideal for a variety of water sports activities. It is a hidden treasure that lies in the State of Karnataka. The beach attracts water lovers to explore this virgin beach and indulge in some exciting activities. This beautiful beach is lined with palm trees and covered with a blue sky that provides a perfect picture for nature lovers. The beach is one of a kind, you can lie down and enjoy the sunset or indulge in the water sports activities that will set your adrenaline pumping! There are a variety of resorts and restaurants located on the beach which give you a breathtaking view and also provide a remarkable experience.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit Malpe beach is between October to January when the weather is pleasant and the skies are clear. Avoid the monsoons and the hot summer months.</string>

    <string name="beaches_om_beach_gokarna_desc">\tGokarna is famous for its beaches. The scenic beauty of the beaches encapsulated by the luscious greenery on one side bordering the western Ghats is a mind-blowing sight to watch for. The peaceful beaches are tourists delight. Every year thousands of tourists visit Gokarna for pilgrim as well as to soak themselves on these beaches.  Om beach is popular beach providing boating facilities to tourists.
\n\n\tOm Beach is shaped as two semi crescents joined together forming the shape of Om (Hindu Symbol) hence the name Om beach. Tourists can enjoy the banana boat, surfing, jet skiing etc. on this beach. The beach has a breathtaking view of the sunset.  For someone who loves the beach, Om beach is a must visit. The long stretch of white sandy beach adjoining the rocky terrain is excellent and appealing to the eyes.
\n\n\tThe beach is not always crowded yet for those who love to spend their precious lone time can find the place intimidating. The various sports and entertainment activities keep the people engaged here on the beach. The beach is perfect to indulge in parasailing, and other adventure sports to chill the vacation time.</string>

    <string name="beaches_padubidri_beach_desc">\tThe Padubidri beach is located in the Udupi district of Karnataka. This beach lies within the small town of Padubidri, which is famous for the Dakkebali ritual held once in two years.
\n\n\tA huge portion of the Padubidri population comprises of the Tuluva ethnic group.   The National Highway 17 (NH 17) passes through this little town and is situated along the Udupi –Mangalore route.
\n\n\tThe Padubidri beach is the perfect destination for the person who is looking for fun and adventure at a quiet seaside. Though not crowded like the more popular beaches along the coastline of Karnataka Padubidri beach is known for water sports and adventure rides.
\n\n\nThe beach is clean and well kept. This is also a perfect place for individuals and families who look forward to a pleasant evening watching the incredible sunset. </string>

    <string name="beaches_sasihithlu_beach_mangalore_desc">\tAround 22 km away from Mangalore is the remarkable Sasihithlu Beach. It is located just two km before NITK Surathkal, Mukka. The beach has stunning white sand adding to the beauty of it and is indeed a picturesque location to admire. The blueish sea bordered with this white sand looks immensely enthralling like the Milky Way.
\n\n\tThe cool breeze and the silent waves are truly splendid and relaxing. The soothing waves caress the white sand in a calm and serene way providing a soothing relief. The island of Munda surrounded by the rivers Shambhavi and Nandini on one side and the Arabian Sea on the other side making the place an outstanding spot for tourists.
\n\n\tThe virgin beach is hidden away from the crowd making it an idyllic place to enjoy and rekindle the joy of being a kid again. Sasihithlu Bach is around 6km from Mukka on the NH 66 Road. It is adjacent to the scenic confluence of the backwaters of Shambhavi and Nandini that adds up the enchanting beauty. This stunning beach is near the Sasihithlu village and one must walk through the village and an array of acacia trees to reach the beach.
\n\n\tSasihithulu Beach is a profound location that is gearing up the publicity for hosting the Karnataka Surfing Festival and India Open of Surfing. The competition and surfing festival witness hundreds of surfers surfing and battling through the waves to win the prize money. The three-day festival is hosted on the marvelous beach with innumerable activities to witness including various live performances, food festival, kite surfing tournaments, paddle up race etc. are on the cards.  The competition is held for under 17, junior boys, senior men, and master’s men.</string>

    // Hill Stations Description
    <string name="hills_kudremukh_desc">\tPopular and named after a mountainside that resembles a horse face, Kudremukh is famous for its biodiversity and scenic beauty. A popular hill-station among the Bangalore crowd, Kudremukh is actually a hill range in the Chikmagalur district of Karnataka. Kudremukh Peak is a paradise for trekkers and naturists alike, with its mountainous paths and floral and faunal diversity.
\n\n\tWith its rolling meadows, grasslands and dense forests, this place is a biodiversity hotspot. Kudremukh is an enchanting place to visit, still retaining much of its natural beauty despite persistent threats from various sources to its ecology.  Varaha Parvatha, another mountain range nearby at a height of 1458m above sea level is a part of the UNESCO World Heritage Site.</string>

    <string name="hills_madikeri_desc">\tGenerally covered as a part of trips to Coorg, Madikeri is a hill town in Karnataka with vast coffee plantations, lush forests and misty hills, all culminating into a breathtaking view. Located in Kodagu District around 6 hours from Bengaluru, Madikeri is a perfect weekend getaway. There is no pollution, no noise to hurt your ears and the cool breeze that accompanies you throughout makes your trip memorable.
\n\n\tThe most famous place of Madikeri is Rajas Seat- a famous viewpoint from where you can grab all the striking beauty of Madikeri at one go. Madikeri fort and various water cascades are among the other must-visits of the place. Spend a couple of days in the beautiful homestays and Airbnb for a rejuvenating experience.
\n\n\tMadikeri, apart from being a refreshing summer retreat, is also famous for its coffee plantations, which are one of its kind in India. No wonder why Madikeri is also famous as 'Karnataka's Coffee Capital.' Renowned for its coffee plantations, this is one of the best places for coffee lovers. To get the real feel you can stay at one of the homestays situated on the coffee estates. You can also take Plantation Tours and help out in berry picking on the fields.</string>

    <string name="hills_agumbe_desc"> </string>
    <string name="hills_nandi_desc"> </string>
    <string name="hills_shivaganga_desc"> </string>
    <string name="hills_savanadurga_desc"> </string>

    // Monuments Description
    <string name="monumnets_golgumbaj_desc"> </string>
    <string name="monumnets_mysore_palace_desc"> </string>
    <string name="monumnets_vidanasouda_desc"> </string>
    <string name="monumnets_church_desc"> </string>
    <string name="monumnets_menabasid_desc"> </string>
    <string name="monumnets_bidar_fort_desc"> </string>

    // Religious Description
    <string name="rel_koodalasangama_desc"> </string>
    <string name="rel_iskon_blg_desc"> </string>
    <string name="rel_murudeshwara_desc"> </string>
    <string name="rel_sri_krishna_udupi_desc"> </string>
    <string name="rel_darmasthala_desc"> </string>
    <string name="rel_kukke_subramanya_desc"> </string>
    <string name="rel_chamundeshwari_desc"> </string>

    // Gardens Description
    <string name="gard_alamatti_desc"> </string>
    <string name="gard_hosapet_desc"> </string>
    <string name="gard_lalbag_desc"> </string>
    <string name="gard_cubbon_desc"> </string>
    <string name="gard_mysore_desc"> </string>
    <string name="gard_dandeli_desc"> </string>

    // Water Falls Description
    <string name="water_Joga_falls_desc"> </string>
    <string name="water_gokak_falls_desc"> </string>
    <string name="water_godachin_malaki_desc"> </string>
    <string name="water_krs_desc"> </string>
    <string name="water_alamatti_desc"> </string>

</resources>