<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Travel Guide</string>

    <string name="implementation_on_fragment_listener"> must implement OnFragmentInteractionListener</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="transaction_name" translatable="false">places</string>
    <string name="transaction_title_name" translatable="false">placeTitle</string>


    // Beaches Description
    <string name="beaches_gokarna_beach_desc">\tGokarna Beaches are the chief tourist attractions in the holy town of Gokarna. The name itself has been derived from Go (holy cow) and Karna (ears); hence, it has considerable mythological reverence as well.
\n\n\tPart of a largely Hindu domain, the tourists also pay homage to the famous Mahabaleswara temple, which is a renowned Shiva temple (a major Hindu deity), Maha Ganapathy temple, the Uma Maheshwari temples, and a host of other well-know temples for which this tourist spot is also famous.
\n\n\tGokarna is remotely populated with its nearest connection being Goa to its north and the city of Bangalore is located roughly around 275 miles to its east.
\n\n\tFor those looking at convenient air-travel, Dabolim in Goa is by far the nearest airport. From Dabolim, travel enthusiasts can either opt for train services or simply hire a cab to reach Gokarna in close to 4 hours.
\n\n\tOther nearby cities on international maps can be located in Madgaon also in Goa and Mangalore. For all the first timers, this tourist spot offers warm and pleasant weather conditions with an average Celsius temperature of around 30 degrees.
</string>

    <string name="beaches_karwar_beach_desc">\tKarwar, situated on the banks of river Kali, is the administrative headquarters of Uttara Kannada district in Karnataka. It is a beautiful sea side town, which is located on the Goa-Karnataka border and 519 km from Bangalore. Situated on the western coast, this scenic place is worth a visit.
\n\n\tKarwar gets it name from the word “Karwad” as the British had trouble pronouncing it during the colonial times. In 1862, British made this place their head quarters. Karwar was the sea trade center from the Arabian Sea and Arabs, Dutch, Portuguese, French and British have traded here.
\n\n\tIn Arabic, Karwar was called “Baithkhol “ meaning bay of safety. Ibn battuta passed through this tract. Many Indian commodities were exported to foreign countries were brought from the Deccan by routes as this port was considered safe during all seasons. The port of Karwar has five islands, Anjidiv, Kudumgad, Dev gad, Mogral and Shamshigudda protecting the port from heavy winds.</string>

    <string name="beaches_kaup_beach_udupi_desc">\tKaup Beach is one of the major beaches in the city of Mangalore. With its tropical climate and bevy of attractions that beckon tourists from across the country, Mangaluru is a port city that promises to keep uplifting your spirits every minute you spend in this city.
\n\n\tKaup or Kapu as the place is known in the local Tulu language is a village town located between Udupi and Mangaluru in the state of Karnataka. The region is predominantly known for one of the most serene and pristine beaches that you can find. Owing to the greenery surrounding the beach on all sides, tourists make a bee-line towards this place for a quick weekend trip away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
\n\n\tAlthough Kaup hasnt been explored on a full-fledged level, the beach attracts many tourists and there have instances of films being shot in the beach and the surrounding areas as well. Kaup beach is famously known to house an old lighthouse that was apparently built in the year 1901. The lighthouse is open for visitors during certain periods of time in the course of the day. It offers a delightful view of the entire beach and seashore that will surely take your breath away.
\n\n\tBesides the lighthouse, Kaup also has ruins of Jain Basadis that line across the stretch of sand, and these are definitely worth a visit. Kaup is the base for two Hindu temples dedicated to the Goddess Mariamman. The best time to visit Kaup Beach is from October to December.
\n\n\tThis beach is also popular with students who come from Manipal, a student town. The beach also has small shacks and eateries where one can sample a bit of the local cuisine.</string>

    <string name="beaches_malpe_beach_udupi_desc">\tMalpe Beach in Karnataka is one of the unexplored beaches in India. Located at a distance of 66 kms from Mangalore and about 6 kms from Udupi, the Malpe Beach is an undefiled virgin beach. The beach has a never-ending coastline, which is surrounded by three rocky islands on the western side. Earlier, Malpe was a port on the coast of Karnataka which is now an ideal destination for a holiday away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
\n\n\tMalpe is the first Indian beach with a 24/7 WiFi. It is also an important port and a fishing harbor in the state of Karnataka. Being the largest port in Karnataka, Malpe has a considerable population engaged in fisheries and tile manufacturing.
\n\n\tThe Malpe Beach has a pleasant weather and clean white sand which makes it ideal for a variety of water sports activities. It is a hidden treasure that lies in the State of Karnataka. The beach attracts water lovers to explore this virgin beach and indulge in some exciting activities. This beautiful beach is lined with palm trees and covered with a blue sky that provides a perfect picture for nature lovers. The beach is one of a kind, you can lie down and enjoy the sunset or indulge in the water sports activities that will set your adrenaline pumping! There are a variety of resorts and restaurants located on the beach which give you a breathtaking view and also provide a remarkable experience.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit Malpe beach is between October to January when the weather is pleasant and the skies are clear. Avoid the monsoons and the hot summer months.</string>

    <string name="beaches_om_beach_gokarna_desc">\tGokarna is famous for its beaches. The scenic beauty of the beaches encapsulated by the luscious greenery on one side bordering the western Ghats is a mind-blowing sight to watch for. The peaceful beaches are tourists delight. Every year thousands of tourists visit Gokarna for pilgrim as well as to soak themselves on these beaches.  Om beach is popular beach providing boating facilities to tourists.
\n\n\tOm Beach is shaped as two semi crescents joined together forming the shape of Om (Hindu Symbol) hence the name Om beach. Tourists can enjoy the banana boat, surfing, jet skiing etc. on this beach. The beach has a breathtaking view of the sunset.  For someone who loves the beach, Om beach is a must visit. The long stretch of white sandy beach adjoining the rocky terrain is excellent and appealing to the eyes.
\n\n\tThe beach is not always crowded yet for those who love to spend their precious lone time can find the place intimidating. The various sports and entertainment activities keep the people engaged here on the beach. The beach is perfect to indulge in parasailing, and other adventure sports to chill the vacation time.</string>

    <string name="beaches_padubidri_beach_desc">\tThe Padubidri beach is located in the Udupi district of Karnataka. This beach lies within the small town of Padubidri, which is famous for the Dakkebali ritual held once in two years.
\n\n\tA huge portion of the Padubidri population comprises of the Tuluva ethnic group.   The National Highway 17 (NH 17) passes through this little town and is situated along the Udupi –Mangalore route.
\n\n\tThe Padubidri beach is the perfect destination for the person who is looking for fun and adventure at a quiet seaside. Though not crowded like the more popular beaches along the coastline of Karnataka Padubidri beach is known for water sports and adventure rides.
\n\n\tThe beach is clean and well kept. This is also a perfect place for individuals and families who look forward to a pleasant evening watching the incredible sunset. </string>

    <string name="beaches_sasihithlu_beach_mangalore_desc">\tAround 22 km away from Mangalore is the remarkable Sasihithlu Beach. It is located just two km before NITK Surathkal, Mukka. The beach has stunning white sand adding to the beauty of it and is indeed a picturesque location to admire. The blueish sea bordered with this white sand looks immensely enthralling like the Milky Way.
\n\n\tThe cool breeze and the silent waves are truly splendid and relaxing. The soothing waves caress the white sand in a calm and serene way providing a soothing relief. The island of Munda surrounded by the rivers Shambhavi and Nandini on one side and the Arabian Sea on the other side making the place an outstanding spot for tourists.
\n\n\tThe virgin beach is hidden away from the crowd making it an idyllic place to enjoy and rekindle the joy of being a kid again. Sasihithlu Bach is around 6km from Mukka on the NH 66 Road. It is adjacent to the scenic confluence of the backwaters of Shambhavi and Nandini that adds up the enchanting beauty. This stunning beach is near the Sasihithlu village and one must walk through the village and an array of acacia trees to reach the beach.
\n\n\tSasihithulu Beach is a profound location that is gearing up the publicity for hosting the Karnataka Surfing Festival and India Open of Surfing. The competition and surfing festival witness hundreds of surfers surfing and battling through the waves to win the prize money. The three-day festival is hosted on the marvelous beach with innumerable activities to witness including various live performances, food festival, kite surfing tournaments, paddle up race etc. are on the cards.  The competition is held for under 17, junior boys, senior men, and masters men.</string>

    // Hill Stations Description
    <string name="hills_kudremukh_desc">\tPopular and named after a mountainside that resembles a horse face, Kudremukh is famous for its biodiversity and scenic beauty. A popular hill-station among the Bangalore crowd, Kudremukh is actually a hill range in the Chikmagalur district of Karnataka. Kudremukh Peak is a paradise for trekkers and naturists alike, with its mountainous paths and floral and faunal diversity.
\n\n\tWith its rolling meadows, grasslands and dense forests, this place is a biodiversity hotspot. Kudremukh is an enchanting place to visit, still retaining much of its natural beauty despite persistent threats from various sources to its ecology.  Varaha Parvatha, another mountain range nearby at a height of 1458m above sea level is a part of the UNESCO World Heritage Site.</string>

    <string name="hills_madikeri_desc">\tGenerally covered as a part of trips to Coorg, Madikeri is a hill town in Karnataka with vast coffee plantations, lush forests and misty hills, all culminating into a breathtaking view. Located in Kodagu District around 6 hours from Bengaluru, Madikeri is a perfect weekend getaway. There is no pollution, no noise to hurt your ears and the cool breeze that accompanies you throughout makes your trip memorable.
\n\n\tThe most famous place of Madikeri is Rajas Seat- a famous viewpoint from where you can grab all the striking beauty of Madikeri at one go. Madikeri fort and various water cascades are among the other must-visits of the place. Spend a couple of days in the beautiful homestays and Airbnb for a rejuvenating experience.
\n\n\tMadikeri, apart from being a refreshing summer retreat, is also famous for its coffee plantations, which are one of its kind in India. No wonder why Madikeri is also famous as Karnataka Coffee Capital. Renowned for its coffee plantations, this is one of the best places for coffee lovers. To get the real feel you can stay at one of the homestays situated on the coffee estates. You can also take Plantation Tours and help out in berry picking on the fields.</string>

    <string name="hills_agumbe_desc">\tLocated in the Shimoga district of Karnataka, Agumbe is a small village often referred to as the Cherrapunji of South India. This biodiversity rich region has the highest rainfall in south India and the second highest annual rainfall in India.
\n\n\tAgumbe is an enriching experience as this hill station is blessed with picturesque beauty and trekking trails. It is one of the last surviving lowland rainforests. Agumbe served as the setting for Indias very famous fictional town Malgudi in the TV serial Malgudi Days.
\n\n\tIt is home to some rare species of medicinal plants like Myristica, Listsaea, Garcinia, Diospyros, Eugenia and more, hence it got the nickname "Hasiru Honnu" which means green is gold. Being home to an extensive rainforest and the wide variety of flora and fauna, Agumbe houses the Agumbe Rainforest Research Station.
\n\n\tThis is Indias oldest weather station which exclusively monitors any changes made in the rainforest areas. Interestingly, Agumbe is also called as the "Cobra Capital" because of the high number of Cobras found here. Agumbe provides great options for trekking, beckoning the adventure enthusiasts to visit this offbeat destination hidden in the lap of nature.</string>

    <string name="hills_nandhi_hills_desc">\tLocated around 60 kilometres away from Bangalore, Nandi Hills is one such tourist spot that has gradually been discovered by visitors over the years and has now become a well-known weekend getaway.
\n\n\tFeaturing beautifully carved arches and majestic pillars with intricately painted walls and ceilings, Nandi Hills is scattered with shrines and monument and is surrounded by mesmerizing views, making this place no less than a hidden paradise.
\n\n\tSituated at a height of 4851 feet above sea level, you can see a convoy of weekenders from Bangalore during early hours catching the glimpse of sunrise.</string>

    <string name="hills_shivagange_hills_desc">\tShivagange, a hillock situated 56 km from Bangalore, is a combination of temples and scenic beauty that makes it both a pilgrimage as well as an adventure spot. From a distance, the hillock looks like a Shiva Linga, with a spring flowing nearby thats locally called Ganga, thereby naming it Shivaganga.
\n\n\tIt is also given the name Dakshina Kashi (Kashi of the south) since its home to various temples (Gangadhareshwara temple, Olakala Teertha, Nandi Statue, Patala Gange, etc.) The stone carving of Nandi ( the bull) is another primary attraction.
\n\n\tThe hilly feature of the place attracts a lot of adventure sports seekers, providing them opportunities for trekking and rock climbing. All in all, it is a popular getaway for travellers with both religious and adventurous inclinations</string>

    <string name="hills_savandurga_hills_desc">\tSituated 60 kms to the west of Bangalore, Savandurga, considered to be one of the largest single rock formations in the whole of Asia. It comprises of two hills, Billigudda (white hill) and Karigudda (black hill) and has a temple situated at the foothill and a pond nearby. Most trekkers choose Billigudda due to its gentler slopes. The weekend travellers from Bangalore frequent it for trekking, camping and rock climbing.
\n\n\tArkavathi River flows nearby and moves towards Manchanabele Dam. Savandurga hills make for a tranquil and picturesque trek and overlook a beautiful lotus pond. Its one of the top places for slab climbing in the world and a lot of climbers and adventure seekers visit here often.
\n\n\tAnother popular activity here is bird watching. The avifauna here is magnificent and enthusiasts can spot the endangered yellow-throated bulbuls. Leopards and sloth bears are also spotted here.</string>

    // Monuments Description
    <string name="monumnets_gol_gumbaz_desc">\tThe erstwhile capital of the Adil Shahi dynasty, Bijapur or Vijaypur remains as quaint with Gol Gumbaz gazing at the sky as the echoes of its timelessness reverberate through the air. The resting place of Mohammed Adil Shah and his wives, mistress, daughter and grandson, Gol Gumbaz is among the greatest examples of the Adil Shahi architecture with one of the biggest domes in the world.
\n\n\tBuilt in 1656 it took 30 years to complete the construction of Gol Gumbaz. The mausoleum was designed by Yaqut of Dabul. Situated in the northern Karnataka, Gol Gumbaz marks the splendour of Adil Shahi rule in the Southern India. The seventh ruler of the Adil Shahi empire, Mohammed Adil Shah started the construction of the tomb right after he became the Sultan in 1626. He wanted the mausoleum to be bigger and grander compared to the memorial of his father, Ibrahim Adil Shah. Although the construction of Gol Gumbaz started during the reign of Mohammed Adil, it got disrupted due to the sudden demise of the Sultan.
\n\n\tStyled on the Dravidian architecture amalgamating the Islamic influences, the very name Gol Gumbaz stems from ‘Gola Gombadh or Gol Gomata translating to a circular dome. Made of dark grey basalt stone, its chamber is among the biggest in the world measuring 18,000 sq ft and the whispering gallery allowing people to hear their most hushed tones courtesy the acoustics of the space. It is said that you can hear a word echo for about 12 times across the other end of the dome. The 144 ft high roof with a 156 ft cube on either side beneath has eight arches traversing the two squares interlocking together that work as the base for the dome. There are four octagonal towers placed at each corner comprising a staircase. And each tower has a gallery on the top floor. The podium sits pretty in the centre hall with steps on the two sides.
\n\n\tThe precinct of Gol Gumbaz comprises a mosque, garden, tavern and a museum. A cenotaph graces the podium in the middle separating the main grave underneath. The entrance to the mausoleum will greet you with a piece of meteorite which is said to have been fallen during the rule of Sultan and is believed to safeguard the tomb from lightning.
\n\n\tGol Gumbaz Situated in Bijapur in Karnataka, it takes around 10 hours to reach Gol Gumbaz from the capital city, Bangalore. Hampi is 214 km from Bijapur while Badami is 122 km. Bijapur has no airport and to visit Gol Gumbaz you will have to get down at the Belgaum Airport which is 200 km from the site. Or you could take a Bangalore to Bijapur train which will be a journey of 668 km.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_mysore_palace_desc">\tThe history of Mysore palace goes back to 14th century when the first structure was laid out. It is said that the very first Mysore Palace of Wodeyars, royal family of Mysore, was built with wood which unfortunately was struck by lightning in the year of 1638. Hence, a new palace with many added features, extensive pavilions and buildings was built reconstructed by Kantirava Narasaraja Wodeyar.
\n\n\tThe present building of Mysore Palace was completed in 1912. Mysore Palace mesmerizes everyone with its magnificent architecture. Known as Indo-Saracenic, a beautiful blend of Hindu, Islamic, Rajput, and Gothic architectural style which the palace represents has been alluring watchers since time immemorial.
\n\n\tPrivate Durbar (Ambavilasa Palace) is another place to see at Mysore Palace. Used by the Kings for private meetings, it also presents a spectacular architectural beauty with mesmerizing interiors. Beautifully carved rosewood doorway ornamented with ivory, hall decorated with stained glass ceilings, golden columns, captivating chandeliers with floral motifs, pietra dura mosaic floor makes this one of the most beautiful rooms of the palace.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_vidhana_soudha_desc">\tInfluenced by the House of Commons in London, the Vidhana Soudha is spread over 60 acres of land. It is popularly known as the building that houses the State Legislature Assembly and the Secretariat of Karnataka. The foundation stone of Vidhana Soudha was laid down by the first Prime Minister of India, Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru, in 1951.
\n\n\tIt has been described by many dignitaries in many different ways over the years. Inaugurated on October 10, 1956, Vidhana Soudha is the original seat of power in the state of Karnataka. The construction of such a building was due to the immense amount of nationalist sentiments that were growing amongst people soon after India gained its independence. During that time, the administrative offices were based out of Attara Kacheri, built by the British in 1868.
\n\n\tIt is due to this that plans were made for Indias own structure of legislature. However, the plan was mooted during K.C. Reddys tenure, who was the first Chief Minister of Karnataka. Regardless, soon after that, Nehru laid its foundation stone down, followed by Hanumanthaiah, who completed the construction of the Vidhana Soudha.
\n\n\tHanumanthaiah was Reddys successor and wanted to shed light to the nationalist sentiments. And so, he asked B.R. Manickram, the chief architect of the project to build the structure right opposite to the Attara Kacheri, that too at a slight elevation. Ultimately, the house of the legislature and secretariat was built, spreading over 5,00,000 square feet, with a total cost of INR 1.84 crore at that time.
\n\n\tVidhana Soudha is located around 34.8 kilometres from the Bangalore Airport. The best way to reach this iconic structure from the airport is by taking the public bus service by BMTC to Ulsoor, which takes around an hour and a half. This is also the cheapest mode of transportation to Vidhana Soudha from the airport.</string>

    <string name="monumnets_philomena_church_desc">\tWith the fame of being one of the largest churches in India, this majestic church captivates everyone with its architectural excellence. It also boasts of being the second largest church in Asia. Dedicated to Saint Philomena, St. Philomenas Church is not only known for its architectural beauty and religious significance; it stands as an exemplary of secular viewpoint and the religious harmony which existed in Mysore. This can be seen from the fact that this church was built by Mysore ruler for the European residents in the city.
\n\n\tBuilt in 1840, earlier it used to be called as the St. Joseph Chavez, which was later changed to its present name. Initially a small church, it gained its present form in 1933 during the reign of Maharaja Krishnaraja Wodeyar IV. In 1843, Mysore King Mummadi Krishnaraja Wodeyar built the church so as to cater to the needs of the European people who were residing in Mysore then. However, with the increase in the number of European residents in the city a need for bigger church aroused.
\n\n\tYou can visit the church till 6 in evening as the timings of St. Philomenas Church are from 05.00 am to 06.00 pm. It is always better to visit in evening as then you can watch the church is being illuminated. Every Sunday and on festival, special masses are organised while everyday masses are conducted in morning and evenings. On 11th August, annual feast is organised at the church.Photography is not allowed inside the church hall.
\n\n\tThis church is situated about 2 km away from the Mysore Palace. Quite close to the city bus stand with a distance of only 3 km between them and hence St. Philomenas Church is easily accessible. Located on the Ashoka Road of Mysore, it can be easily accessed by road. Tourists can either hire a taxi or just take an auto rickshaw to the church.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_mena_basadi_desc">\tThe Badami cave temples are a complex of Hindu and Jain cave temples located in Badami, a town in the Bagalkot district in northern part of Karnataka, India. The caves are important examples of Indian rock-cut architecture, especially Badami Chalukya architecture, and the earliest date from the 6th century. Badami was previously known as Vataapi Badami, the capital of the early Chalukya dynasty, which ruled much of Karnataka from the 6th to the 8th century. Badami is situated on the west bank of a man-made lake ringed by an earthen wall with stone steps it is surrounded on the north and south by forts built in later times.
\n\n\tThe Badami cave temples represent some of the earliest known examples of Hindu temples in the Deccan region. They along with the temples in Aihole transformed the Malaprabha River valley into a cradle of temple architecture that influenced the components of later Hindu temples elsewhere in India.
\n\n\tBadami, also referred to as Vatapi, Vatapipura, Vatapinagari and Agastya Tirtha in historical texts, the capital of Chalukya dynasty in the 6th century, is at the exit point of a ravine between two steep mountain cliffs. Four cave temples in the escarpment of the hill to the south-east of the town were carved into the cliffs monolithic stone face. The escarpment is above a man-made lake called Agastya Teertha, created by an earthen dam faced with stone steps. To the west end of this cliff, at its lowest point, is the first cave temple.The largest and highest cave is Cave 3, which is further to the east on the northern face of the hill.The fourth cave, Cave 4, is a few steps down further east.
\n\n\tThe Badami cave temples are located in the town of Badami in the north-central part of Karnataka, India. The temples are about 88 miles (142 km) east of Belagavi, and 87 miles (140 km) northwest of Hampi. The Malaprabha River is 3 miles (4.8 km) away. The cave temples are 14 miles (23 km) from the UNESCO world heritage site Pattadakal and 22 miles (35 km) from Aihole – another site with over a hundred ancient and early medieval era Hindu, Jain and Buddhist monuments.
</string>

    <string name="monumnets_bidar_fort_desc">\tAmongst the most formidable forts of the country, it is situated in the eastern part of the town and has within it ruins of palaces, mosques and other buildings which had been built of trap rock. Stone and mortar were used to build the fort-walls. The fort is entered from the south-east by a zigzag passage protected by three gateways. The entrance gate has a lofty dome, the interior of which had been painted in bright colours.
\n\n\tBidar was the capital of Bahmani Kingdom in the 14th century. Bidar fort was built by Ahmad Shah Wali Bahman. Bidar Fort was renovated in the 15th century by Sultan Ahmad Shah-I as he shifted his capital from Kalaburagi (Gulbarga) to Bidar.
\n\n\tBidar Fort is open daily from 9 AM till 5 PM.During summer peak temperatures in Bidar may reach upwards of 40 degree Celsius. Plan your visit with adequate water, an umbrella for cover and sunscreen.
\n\n\tBidar Fort is 700 kms from Bengaluru. Recently opened Bidar Airport is the closest airport (11 kms from Bidar Fort) which has once a day flight from Bengaluru. Hyderabad airport is the next best option, 150 kms from Bidar. Bidar city railway station is 3 kms from Bidar Fort. Buses and trains are available from Bengaluru to reach Bidar.</string>

    // Religious Description
    <string name="rel_kudala_sangama_desc">\tKudala Sangama (Kudalasangama Koodalsangama Koodalasangama) is in Bagalkot District of Karnataka. It is a famous pilgrim place for Veerashaivas. Here is the confluence of two big rivers Krishna and Malaprabha. The holy samadhi, Aikya Mantapa is situated here. The Mantapa is under water, but is well protected. There is a temple dedicated to Lord Sangameswara, worshipped in the form of a ling. The temple is an ancient monument built in the Chalukyan style architecture. Distance between Kudala Sangama and Bengaluru, Karnataka is 445.7 km and travel time is around 7 h 10 min via NH50 and NH48.
\n\n\tThis place is closely associated with the 12th century poet and social reformer Saint Basaveswara. Basavana Bagewadi is another important place in the locality. Bagalkot Railway Station and Belgaum Airport are the nearest railhead and airport respectively.
\n\n\tA true visionary of his time and a revolutionary who started a new religion, Lingayatism (also known as Veershaivism), which literally means The brave followers of Shiva. Basavannas ultimate aim was to make this fundamental right available to each and everyone. Basavanna, keeping welfare as the ultimate aim, expedited programmes to take religion to the people by preaching and writing religious literature in Kannada. His samadhi is at Kudalasangama.
\n\n\tKudalasangama Pin code is 587118 and postal head office is Hungund. Kudalasangama STD code is 08351. Nearest railway station to Kudalasangama is Almatti which is 15 km away. Distance from Kudala Sangama to Bagalkot, Karnataka is 52.3 km and travelling takes around 1 h 13 min via NH367.
</string>

    <string name="rel_iskon_bangalore_desc">\tIskon located in the Rajaji Nagar in Bangalore, and a venture of the International Society of Krishna Consciousness, ISKCON Temple in Bangalore is a shrine to Lord Krishna. This splendid architecture was first erected by Sri Madhu Pandit Das and inaugurated in the year 1997 by the then President of India, Shankar Dayal Sharma.
\n\n\tIt houses a number of prayer halls, dedicated to Sri Sri Radha Krishnachandra, Sri Sri Krishna Balarama, Sri Sri Nitai Gauranga, Sri Srinivasa Govinda and Sri Prahlada Narasimha.
\n\n\tThe International Society for Krishna Consciousness was initiated in the year 1976 by Krishna devotees from across the world. The ISKCON Temple in Bangalore was first established in 1998 under the Karnataka Societies Registration Act, 1960.
\n\n\tThe construction of the temple began in 1990, and around 600 skilled artisans were employed for the purpose. The construction finally ended in the year 1997.  On the same year, the Temple was inaugurated by the ninth President of India- Shankar Dayal Sharma.
</string>

    <string name="rel_murdeshwara_desc">\tMurudeshwara is a holy city dedicated to Lord Shiva, situated in the southern state of Karnataka, on the coast of the Arabian Sea. This city mainly prides itself on having the second tallest sculpture of Lord Shiva in the whole world.
\n\n\tMurudeshwara is easily accessible by bus, train and by air. The nearest airport is Mangalore airport, which is 133km away from the city. All the trains that connect Mangalore and Mumbai pass through the Murudeshwar Railway Station, which makes it conveniently accessible by frequent trains. Other nearby cities like Kochi, Bangalore and Mumbai are connected to Murudeshwara through very efficient bus service.
\n\n\tThe romantic sunsets on the Murudeshwar Beach are truly something worth witnessing when you are in the area. The beaches of the Arabian Sea such as the Aligadda Beach and Murudeshwar Beach allow tourists to enjoy water sports and other adventures along their shores. A unique activity you can enjoy in Murudeshwar Beach is scuba-diving, which is sure to leave you with lifelong memories. One must definitely visit the majestic statue of Lord Shiva that towers over the city at a height of 123 feet. A visit to the Murudeshwar Temple and Raja Gopura is also a spiritually rewarding experience for visitors.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit Murudeshwar is between October and May when the city comes alive with fairs, events and festivals. The festival of Mahashivaratri is performed here with great spirit and fervour during February and March and is a spectacle worth witnessing. You can choose from a multitude of hotels and accommodations for a comfortable stay when you are visiting here.
</string>

    <string name="rel_sri_krishna_udupi_desc">\tUdupi is a wonderful holiday destination in Karnataka located about 60 km away from Mangalore. One of the unique things about this city is that it is surrounded by the Western ghats on one side and the Arabian Sea on the other. After Bangalore and Mangalore, Udupi is the most important city in Karnataka.
\n\n\tUdupi is famous for its scenic beauty, mouth watering cuisines, pristine beaches and untouched forests. One of the best things to do in Udupi is explore the wonderful green forests and get a glimpse of some of its rare inmates. The intricately carved temples are visited by devotees and history buffs all year round. Udupi has a rich cultural heritage with a history that is over 700 years old.
\n\n\tUdupi has some of the most beautiful places to visit in Karnataka such as the famous Krishna temple which is visited by devotees all year round. Other popular places to visit here are St. Marys Island, Bramhvar, Barkur, Maple Beach, Kudlu Falls and Anantheshwar Temple.
\n\n\tUdupi city is not only famous for having some good temples and beaches, but you can also do some fun activities in this city. You can try the banana boats on Maple beach or ride the speed boats and enjoy a trip to St Marys island. Apart from boating, you can also do trekking, river rafting, water sports, pilgrimage, and many other outdoor activities. Udupi is also a great place to shop for Kanjeevaram sarees and other silken goods.
</string>

    <string name="rel_darmasthala_manjunatha_desc">\tShri Kshetra Dharmasthala, the land of righteousness and piety, is one of south Indias most renowned religious landmarks with a history as old as 800 years. Manjunatheshwara, the chief deity of the spiritual abode, has taken the form of a shivalinga and made immaculate, the temple town of Dharmasthala since and forever. Lord Manjunatheshwara, is being worshipped in a very unusual yet exceptionally inordinate manner in Shree kshetra dharmasthala, as this Shaiva temple is beseeched by Vaishnava priests and administered by Jain descendants.
\n\n\tDharmasthala, the abode of dharma, is the quintessence of humanity and faith. As the name suggests, the word dharma in its truest sense means righteousness, it is the embodiment of the worlds most divine emotions in spite of ones cast, creed or religion.
\n\n\tAnnappa swamy betta located 1.5 km west of the new bus stand and half a kilometre from the Shri Manjunatha temple, in the southeast direction is the hill of Annappa Betta, which is also known as Badinede Betta; this shrine is dedicated to Shri Annappa swamy and is home to the shrines of the four Dharma Daivas. A peep through the window of the inside of a dwelling, one can see a swing, believed to be used by one of the Daivas Generally the hill is visited, after having visited the main temple. Entry of children and women is restricted to this hill owing to the legend and lore of the temple.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kukke_subramanya_desc">\tSri Kukke Subramanya shrine in Dakshina Kannada district of Karnataka is one place almost every Hindu devotee in the Southern part of India would be familiar with.  And not just being familiar, many would either have visited or would have planned to visit the temple at least once in a lifetime for the powers Lord Subramanya here is known to possess and bless a devotee with. Come, lets learn about all that the shrine is known for and more.
\n\n\tThe Kukke Subramanya Temple is dedicated to Lord Subramanya, Son of Lord Shiva. According to legends, Lord Subramanya is considered the Deva Senapathi – the commander of the army of the lords and is worshipped as the lord of snakes.
\n\n\tThe temple Sri Kukke Subramanya is located in the Subramanya town of Sullia Taluk in Dakshina Kannada district. Easily accessible by rail and road, this small town is located about 105 km from Mangaluru while the temple is situated amidst a scenic location thats relatively unexplored and neat in comparison to a lot of other pilgrimage venues.
</string>

    <string name="rel_chamundeshwari_mysore_desc">\tIn India, just as a persons name usually has a symbolic meaning, names given to places also have a meaning behind them. Chamundi Hills in Karnataka are named after the Goddess Chamundeshwari.
\n\n\tThe hills lie at a height of about 1000 meters above sea level and are 13 km east of Mysore. The Chamundeshwari Temple dedicated to the Goddess after whom the hills are named is the highlight of this place.
\n\n\tAccording to popular legends, many years ago, a buffalo demon named Mahishasura was wreaking havoc in heaven and earth.  He had been gifted a boon by Brahma that he could be killed by no man.
\n\n\tFor this reason, Mahishasura was slowly winning every battle he started. The Gods found a loophole to Brahmas boon and goddess Durga was given divine powers to make her stronger than Mahishasura.
\n\n\tGoddess Chamundeshwari is a form of Durga. With her new powers and a lion as her vehicle, she fought Mahishasura atop a hill for ten days and finally killed him.
\n\n\tIn her honor, the hill was named as Chamundi Hill. This day is celebrated throughout India as Dasara and symbolizes the victory of good over evil.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kotilingeshwara_temple_desc">\tThe Kotilingeshwara Temple lies in a very small village named Kammasandra in the Kolar district. The temple is extremely famous because of the largest and the tallest Shivalinga present in Asia. More than 2 lac devotees visit this temple every year.
\n\n\tMaha Shivaratri is a special occasion and a large number of devotees make it a point to be there on this auspicious day. The temple can be easily reached from the gold fields of Kolar.
\n\n\tThe Shivalinga is 33 mts and is the tallest in the World. It has an accompanying Basava statue which is 11 mts tall and is surrounded by a large number of Shivalingas spread across the area. The project involves an establishment of one crore shivalingas hence it is named Kotilingeshwara and currently, there are about a hundred lakh shivalingas.
\n\n\tThis temple has been constructed by Swami Sambha Shiva Murthy in the year 1980. The first linga was installed in 1980 and since then there have been many lingas present in the temple. There is also a huge and tall Nandi installed beside the linga. The Nandi is 11 mt tall and sits over a huge platform.
\n\n\tWithin the premises of the temple, there are about eleven other temples for different deities. The first of them includes the temple of Lord Vishnu, Lord Brahma, and Lord Maheshwara temples. This is followed by a temple of Lord Kotilingeshwara.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport to Kolar is located at Bangalore.  From the airport, travelers can hire cabs or rely on public transport to reach Kolar.
\n\n\tBy Rail: There is a well-connected rail network from Bangalore, Mangalore, Hassan, Kolar and Hubli.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you want to reach the temple by road, you need to head through Kolar. Kolar is at a distance of 2.5 hours from Bangalore.
</string>

    <string name="rel_sringeri_sharda_peetham_desc">\tThe town is also known as Sringeri Sharda Peetham and it has a 1200 year- old temple located there. It is believed that Adi Shankaracharya chose the site to stay and teach his disciples and impressed with his place, he stayed here for twelve years. He then also established mathas in North India, East India, and West India. Adi Shankaracharya has constructed four temples in all the four directions – these include Kere Anjaneya Temple in the West, Kala Bhairava Temple in the East, Durgamba Temple in the South and Kalikamba Temple in the North.
\n\n\tSringeri is a town located in the Chikkamangaluru district in the state of Karnataka. The hill town is situated on the banks of the River Tunga and is located at a distance of 107 km from Mangalore and 336 km from Bangalore. It can be easily reached from Mangalore through Karkala.
\n\n\tSringeri holds significance in Karnataka due to the first matha, which was established by Adi Shankaracharya. The first of the four peetha was established here. Located amidst the Western Ghats, the name of Sringeri is derived from Rishyashringa-giri which is a nearby hill and is believed to have contained the rich heritage of Rishi Vibhandaka and his son Rishyashringa.
\n\n\tSringeri is well known as a learning center due to the many temples and maths. Many students come down here to learn Vedic philosophy. A variety of options for accommodation are available at Sringeri.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport is Mangalore International Airport at a distance of 105 kms.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The city Shimoga which is at a distance of 95 kms from Sringeri is well connected to Bangalore through the rail route. Sringeri is at a distance of 86 kms from Chikkamagaluru which is connected to Bangalore through a rail line via Kadur.
\n\n\tBy Road: The town can be reached from Mangalore or Chikkamagaluru by a well-connected road network. Udupi is also at a distance of 80 kms. Various private and KSRTC buses ply from Bangalore as well as Sringeri to Shimoga.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kalasa_temple_desc">\tKalasa, the temple town of Karnataka, is a must-visit. There are many temple towns in Karnataka, associated with events from centuries ago, providing a glimpse into the spiritual soul of the region.
\n\n\tThese revered sites also showcase the architectural heritage of Southern India which boasts so many styles and design philosophies, representing the many dynasties and cultures that have inhabited the land. One of these temple towns is Kalasa, located in the picturesque Chikkamagaluru district in Karnataka close to the famous peak of Kudremukh.
\n\n\tSitting on the banks of the River Bhadra, the main attraction of Kalasa town is the Kalaseshwara Temple, dedicated to Lord Shiva. The intricately carved main tower of the temple is one of the defining features of the town as pilgrims from all over the region come to offer their prayers throughout the day. The town is surrounded by the scenic Western Ghats, from where its lifeline, the Bhadra originates.
\n\n\tThe legend behind Kalasa is steeped in some of the most important events of Hindu mythology. It is believed that when Lord Shiva and Goddess Parvathi married in the Himalayas, the attendance of the entire pantheon of deities caused a change in the earths rotation.
\n\n\tLord Shiva requested the great sage Agasthya to travel south and balance the shift of the earth, promising him that he would be able to witness the wedding from where he resides. The town is believed to be the spot where Sage Agasthya resided during the wedding of Shiva and Parvathi. The marriage is celebrated by devotees to this date.
\n\n\tBy Air: Mangalores Bajpe airport is closest to the town, around 115 kilometres away. The Mysore airport is around 175 kilometres away from the town. The rest of the journey is by road.
\n\n\tBy Train: The closest train station to the town is in Bantawala, 114 kilometres away.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you are landing in Mangalore, then the road trip north via the NH 169 and SH 66 is around 115 kilometres and would take close to 3 hours. From Bangalore, the place is a 6-hour road trip via NH75. The 310 kilometres route passes through the town of Hassan. The trip by road from Bantwal railway station via the NH 169 and SH 66 would take close to 3 hours.
</string>

    <string name="rel_kollur_mookambika_desc">\tKollur located in the Kondapur Taluk in District Udupi, Karnataka, is a small temple town. Situated in the Western Ghat foothills, the town is famous for its Mookambika Temple, a popular Hindu pilgrimage. Also known as Kollapura, the town is 38 kilometers from Kudapur Town. Situated on the banks River Sauparnika, the place is encircled by dense forest and is in the shape of a Sri Chakra.
\n\n\tThe town is one of the seven mukti places or pilgrimage centers created by Lord Parashurama. The remaining six pilgrimages are located in Kodeshwara, Gokarna, Udupi, Kumbasi, Sankaranarayanan and Subrahmanya. As per a popular belief, penance was performed on this holy place by Saints in ancient times.
\n\n\tMookambika Temple, one of the major temples in the town, is dedicated to supreme goddess Devi Durga and is a significant place of Shakti worship. The goddess is depicted here in the form of a Jyothirlinga, implying the confluence of Both Shiva and Shakti.
\n\n\tThere are many legends associated with the temple. A demon named Mookasuran, residing in this area wanted to gain powers using his penance. Goddess Parvati was worried to know this and killed Mookasuran with her Chakra on Shukla Ashtami. Since then Goddess Parvati is also known as Mookambika Devi.
\n\n\tBy Air: The nearest airport to the town is Bajpe Airport in Mangalore, which is nearly 106 kilometres away and the best way to reach here. Hubli Airport is the second nearest airport located nearly 170 kilometres away.
\n\n\tBy Train: If you plan to come to the temple town by train, you can take a train till Bijoor Railway Station or till Byndoor Mookambika Road Railway Station. Both the railway stations are located nearly 20 kilometres away from here.
\n\n\tBy Road: If you plan to come to the town by road, you can easily drive down from Mangalore, Bangalore, Mysore and Udupi. You can even take KSRTC buses plying regularly to Kollur from these cities.
</string>

    <string name="rel_goravanahalli_mahalakshmi_desc">\tWhen it comes to tourism, Karnataka is the fourth most popular holiday destination in India. One of the reasons, this state is so popular is because of its ornate temples like the Sri Mahalakshmi Temple in Goravanahalli. As the name suggests, this temple is dedicated to Goddess Mahalakshmi, the wife of Lord Vishnu and the Goddess of prosperity and wealth.
\n\n\tThe main idol of Goddess Mahalakshmi in the temple is believed to be self-manifested. According to local historians, in the early 1900s, a villager named Abbayya came into possession of this idol. He worshipped the idol at home and was blessed with wealth and prosperity. His home soon came to be known as Lakshmi Nivas in honor of his charity work. Abbayya brother’s Thotadappa also worked alongside Abbayya and worshipped the Goddess Mahalakshmi. One night the Goddess visited him in his dreams and asked him to build her a temple. Thus Thotadappa built a temple for the Goddess and began worshipping the idol in this shrine. After Thotadappa’s death, Chowdavya began performing the poojas for Goddess Mahalakshmi.
\n\n\tThe Sri Mahalakshmi Temple in Goravanahalli is a beautiful example of the typical South Indian architecture in the 1900s. The temple features a large, multicolored Gopuram with smaller arches on both sides. The temple also has verandahs on either side.  The main deity is housed in the Garbhagriha or the sanctum sanctorum. Other deities such as the Nag Dev and Marikamba are also housed in the temple.
\n\n\nThe temple is open to the public all through the year. Tuesdays and Friday are considered especially auspicious. If you would like to attend the Pooja, Abhisheka and Kumkuma Archane are performed at 8 am to 9.30am and the Maha Mangalarathi is performed at 9:30 am, 12:30 pm and at 7:30 pm. The temple is closed between 12.30pm and 5.30pm. Lakshadeepotsava is the most important festival at this temple.
\n\n\tBy Air: The Bangalore International Airport caters to domestic and international tourists and is a mere 80 kms from the temple.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The closest railways station is located 36 kms from the temple at Tumkur. A number of trains stop here on a daily basis including the Jan Shatabdi Express for Hubli, the Ranichennama Express and the Golgumbaz Express.
\n\n\tBy Road: KSRTC and Private Buses ply regularly between Bangalore and Gorvanahalli.</string>

    <string name="rel_siddaganga_mutt_desc">\tSree Siddaganga Mutt is an ancient and one of a kind Gurukul, situated in Tumkur, amidst the beautiful and serene landscape. It is about 63 km from Bangalore. The mutt’s aim is to provide service to the needy and to the poor, and this has been successfully carried out.
\n\n\tThe Sree Siddaganga Mutt offers education to more than 8000 poor children, between the age five to 16 years, with free food and shelter and is exempted from discrimination, and is open to children of all faiths and communities. The mutt also has a school for the blind with more than 100 blind children and offers free education, food and independent hostel facility.
\n\n\tOne of the befitting things we can see in the mutt is the annual prayers of the students of the mutt. All these students participate in the prayers without any disparity of caste or creed. The prayers are held both in the mornings as well as in the evenings, during which time the swami is present and guides the students.
\n\n\tSree Siddaganga Mutt is an ancient and one of a kind Gurukul, situated in Tumkur, amidst the beautiful and serene landscape. It is about 63 km from Bangalore. The mutt’s aim is to provide service to the needy and to the poor, and this has been successfully carried out.
\n\n\tSree-shivakumara-swamiji-dr-abdul-kalamThe Sree Siddaganga Mutt offers education to more than 8000 poor children, between the age five to 16 years, with free food and shelter and is exempted from discrimination, and is open to children of all faiths and communities. The mutt also has a school for the blind with more than 100 blind children and offers free education, food and independent hostel facility.
\n\n\tOne of the befitting things we can see in the mutt is the annual prayers of the students of the mutt. All these students participate in the prayers without any disparity of caste or creed. The prayers are held both in the mornings as well as in the evenings, during which time the swami is present and guides the students.
\n\n\tThe Sree Siddaganga Mutt was established in the 15th Century A.D. by the Sri Gosala Siddeswara Swamiji, who belongs to the Shunya Simhasana, a spiritual academy from the days of social reformer Basaweshwara. The present head of the mutt is Dr. Sree Sree Sree Shivakumara Swamiji, who is now 104 years old. He is the driving force in this ashram.
\n\n\tHe was born in Veerapura near Magadi Taluk. He took full responsibility of the mutt in the year 1941. He is also the founder of the Sree Siddaganga Educational Society. The tireless efforts of the swami have resulted in the development of free boarding for the children to its present size.
\n\n\tThe most economic route for reaching the Siddaganga Mutt is to avail local transport facilities. There are plenty of buses and taxis plying from Tumkur. Travelling in KSRTC bus from Bangalore to Tumkur will take about two hours in a car. Strolling around the ashram, meeting the swami and seeing the discipline in the mutt will definitely be a unique experience for everyone visiting the mutt. The mutt and the temples within can be visited anytime during the year, as the weather is quite pleasant.
</string>

    <string name="rel_badami_banashankari_desc">\tBanashankari Amma Temple is a famous temple located in Cholachagudd near Badami, in the Bagalkot district of Karnataka. This is a temple dedicated to Goddess Parvati, the consort of Lord Shiva.
\n\n\tThe Banashankari Amma Temple was originally built by the Chalukyas during the 7th century. The Goddess Banashankari was their family deity. According to an inscription, this image of the Banashankari Amma was installed by Jagadekamalla I in 630 AD. This temple was later renovated by the Marathas in the 18th century. Its modern structure now reflects the Vijayanagara style of architecture more than the original Chalukya style.
\n\n\tThe Skanda Purana says that an Asura named Durgamasura lived in this region. He used to harass the people and made their life unbearable. The Devas were moved by their plight and prayed for a way to kill the Demon. Goddess Parvati answered their prayers. She came down to earth as Shakambari and killed Durgamasura after a fierce battle. Shakambari stayed on in the region to protect the people. She came to be known as Banashankari or Vanashankari. Vana means forest in Sanskrit, and Shankari means the consort of Lord Shankara. As the temple was situated near a forest, she was called Vanashankari, which later became Banashankari in the local language.
\n\n\tThis temple is situated just five kilometers from Badami, another famous religious and tourist spot. It is easy to reach Badami by bus from any part of Karnataka. Badami also has a railway station. The nearest airport is located in the city of Belgaum.
</string>

    <string name="rel_godachi_veerabadra_temple_desc">\tGodachi is a small village in the Ramdurg Taluq of Karnataka. This place is located in the Belgaum district and it has many beautiful temples including the Shri Veerabhadra temple. A famous fair is held here every year.
\n\n\tGodachi is a small village famous for the Godach Fair or Jatre held during the months of November-December every year. The Godachi Jatre is held in honor of Shri Veerabhadra, the prime deity in the main temple here – the Veerabhadra temple.
\n\n\tVeerabhadra was created by Lord Shiva to destroy Daksha’s Yagna. The Veerabhadra temple is a in a combined style of Chalukya and Vijayanagara Architecture. The doorway is built in the Chalukyan style, while the Garbhagraha or the sanctum reflects Vijayanagara Style of temple building.
\n\n\tGodachi is 12 km away from the Taluq headquarters Ramdurg. The nearest railway station to Ramdurg is the Badami railway station.
\n\n\tGodachi Jatre or fair is held in November or December, during the month of Karthik in the Hindu calendar. Traditionally, temple festivals and fairs in India have not only been religious celebrations, they also served as social and commercial gatherings and Godachi Jatre is also one such occasion.
</string>

    <string name="rel_savadatti_yellamma_desc">\tThe Yellamma Devi Temple is located in Saundatti taluq, five kilometers away from Saundatti town. Saundatti itself is 70 km away from Belgaum city.
\n\n\tThe Yellamma Devi temple is located on top of a hill near Saundatti. Saundatti is an ancient town which was the first capital of the Ratta dynasty. The Renuka Devi Temple, or Yellamma Devi Temple (as it is more popularly known), is the most famous pilgrimage spot in Saundatti.
\n\n\tThe Yellamma Temple attracts people from all over Karnataka and neighboring states. During the Yellamma Jatre, especially the one held during the month of Margasira, the number of attendees normally crosses 10 lakhs. The Jatre is also known for the practice of dedicating girls to the Devadasi system.
\n\n\tYellamma Devi is associated with Renuka, the wife of Jamadhagni and the mother of Parashurama, whose story is told in the Puranas. Here, she is worshipped as Renuka Devi or Yellamma Devi.
\n\n\tYellamma Devi is also identified with the Goddess Kali. Kali is known as the punisher who destroys evil-doers, but she is also the kind mother who showers love and blessings on her devotees. It is in this aspect that she is worshipped here. A Jain inscription in the temple, in Sanskrit and Kannada, refers to the Rashtrakuta kings Krishna and Vikramadithya.
\n\n\tThis temple was constructed in 1514 by Bommappa Nayak. It is built in a combination of Chalukyan and Rashtrakuta styles. There are smaller temples for Ganesha, Mallikarjuna, Parashurama, Eknaath and Siddheshwara in the temple courtyard. The Government now takes care of the temple management.
\n\n\tHubli and Belgaum are the nearest airports, while Dharwad is the nearest railway station. Saundatti is connected to these places by KSRTC buses.
</string>

    // Gardens Description
    <string name="gard_alamatti_garden_desc">\tLav Kush Garden is one of the most beautiful gardens at Almatti. They are beautifully maintained and depict huge sculptures which are made by using cement and steel of lav Kush and Krishna. There is natural pavement along the paths with waterfalls and water channels alongside. The Garden has a beautiful lawn, hedges, flower beds, ornamental plants and shrubs.
\n\n\tIn Front of the Sita Mata Temple are two ponds which are believed to never dry up and always have water in them ( also known as Kush Kanda).
\n\n\tThe garden attracts children by viewing different childhood activities of Lava and Kush like playing in their cradle with mother Sita, taking education with their Gurus etc.
\n\n\tThe garden has a gorgeous view point and panoramic view of the Almatti Dam.Lav Kush Garden is open daily from 6 AM to 7 PM. Entry is free during early morning and late evening 6 to 9 AM and 6 to 7 PM. A nominal fee applies during the day time.
\n\n\tLav Kush Garden is located 6 kms from the Almatti Dam. Lalbagh can be accessed using private vehicles/taxis to reach Lav Kush Garden.Almatti Dam, Badami Cave Temples, Fort Bijapur are some of the other interesting spots to explore near Lav Kush Garden.
</string>

    <string name="gard_hospet_garden_desc">\tHospet, being a tourist center, is flocked by crowds of people from all over India as well as abroad. The Department of tourism of Karnataka ensures the development and well maintenance of recreational parks and gardens. If you plan a trip to Hospet, you must not miss visiting the beautiful parks and gardens there. There are also excellent wildlife spots in and around Hospet which would be a delight for wildlife enthusiasts.
\n\n\tHospet is home to many wildlife sanctuaries because of its natural environment and wide range of forests. If you are a wildlife lover, there is plenty of wildlife to be watched in Hospet and its surrounding areas.
\n\n\tThe Daroji Bear Sanctuary provides room for various sloth bears to live freely in their natural habitat. Daroji Sloth Bear Sanctuary is located near Kamalapur which is just 12 km from Hospet. This area near Kamalapur has been the abode of bears since centuries and it has been declared as the Daroji Sloth Bear Sanctuary.
\n\n\tThe Daroji Sloth Bear sanctuary also serves as a home for hyenas, pangolins, wild boars, jackals, black-naped hares, porcupines, and leopards. Bird spotting is also very popular here and you can spot endemic bird species like painted spur fowl and yellow-throated bulbuls. You can also find dry land bird species such as sand grouse, quails, sirkeer malkohas and stone-curlews in this sanctuary. The opening hours of the sanctuary are from 9.30am to 6pm and the entrance fee is Rs.25. It is a good idea for you to visit this sanctuary during July to March as it is the best time for sighting wildlife. However, sloth bears can be sighted all through the year during all months, including extremely hot summer months.
\n\n\tOther popular places good for sighting wildlife are Muneer park, T.B Dam zoo and Chakra Vana park.
</string>

    <string name="gard_lalbag_bangalore_desc">\tLalbagh is one of the oldest botanical gardens in India and is also a major tourist attraction in South India. Located in South Bengaluru, the Lalbagh Botanical Garden is not only one of the largest botanical gardens in India, but also the first of its kind, with planned routes, glasshouses and ornamental flowers growing throughout the property.
\n\n\tThe garden itself is spread over an area of 240 acres and its construction was commissioned by the famous ruler Hyder Ali. It was finally completed by his son- Tipu Sultan- who designed the gardens keeping in mind the beautiful gardens of Sira in Tumkur District in Karnataka.
\n\n\tLalbagh is home to exotic flowers that were imported by the Sultan from countries like France, Persia, Arabia, Afghanistan, etc. Therefore, flowers that were previously never seen in India were first witnessed in this historical garden. Trees that were imported by Tipu Sultan from all over the world can still be found growing here.
\n\n\tThe bi-annual flower show at the Lalbagh Botanical Garden is a spectacle to behold. People travel from far and wide from India and even from abroad to witness millions of flowers, thousands of plants and the incredible artistry that goes into making the figurines and flower structures.
\n\n\tThe show takes place twice a year- once during January in the same week as the Indian Republic Day, and another time in August, during Independence Day. Each year, a different theme is chosen and flower arrangements are made according to the theme.
\n\n\tPlants and flowers are imported from all over the world and over 20 lakh flowers are used each year to make semi-permanent structures in various characteristic shapes and designs. The show takes place inside the striking Glass House which is located on the premises of the Botanical Gardens and goes on from 9:00 am in the morning until 6:00 pm in the evening.
\n\n\tLalbagh Botanical Garden is located at a distance of 38.8 km from Kempegowda International Airport in Bangalore. There are frequent bus routes that ferry between the two places. You can also book a taxi or hire a car which will take you to Lalbagh after a short 45-minute drive through the city of Bangalore.
\n\nThe best time to visit the Lalbagh Botanical Gardens is during winter, which lasts from November to March in Bangalore. Even though the gardens remain open throughout the year, it can get pretty stuffy and hot during summer.
</string>

    <string name="gard_cubbon_park_desc">\tAn oasis of green amidst a buzzing urbanscape, Cubbon Park is a scenic tourist attraction in the IT city of Bangalore. The park with a thriving ecosystem with more than 6000 trees, is justly regarded as the ‘lungs of the city. Besides being home to multitudes of vibrant flora and birdlife, Cubbon Park is also where you will find a handful of the citys most alluring structures including the Attara Kacheri, Seshadri Iyer Memorial Hall, and the grand State Archeological Museum.
\n\n\tThere is a wealth of historical and archaeological specimens preserved in these buildings, touching upon important turning points from the countrys past. Its as enjoyable to leaf through the pages of history inside these museums as it is to take a relaxing walk or a jog in the park along the picturesque tree-lined avenues. There is one other attraction in the park that tourists of every temperament are bound to enjoy— the huge Cubbon Park Aquarium, also famous as the Bangalore Aquarium.
\n\n\tAmong a diversity of vibrant water life in this aquarium, you can find the majestic-looking Siamese Fighting Fish, a variety of gouramis, predators like red tail shark and more. Its absolutely captivating to walk inside the aquarium, as if you have stepped inside the aquamarine belly of the sea— certainly a big highlight for nature enthusiasts!
\n\n\tCubbon Park should be the first place on your sightseeing tour in Bangalore, especially if you are in the company of kids. For the amusement of children, the park has a toy- train track passing through. Every 10-20 minute theres a biofuel-run locomotive on the line, ready to give visitors a memorable joy ride.
\n\n\tFind a KSRTC bus plying between the airport and M.G. Road or Kasturba Road. Alternatively, you can hire a cab to Kasturba Road from the airport. The closest access points to the park are- Hudson Circle, Ambedkar Veedhi, and State Central Library.
</string>

    <string name="gard_mysore_zoo_desc">\tShri Chamarajendra Zoological Gardens or more commonly known as Mysore Zoo is one of the oldest zoos in the world. Established in the year 1892 by the Royals of the Mysore, this Zoological Gardens was formed from a part of Maharaja Chamaraja Wodeyars summer palace area.
\n\n\tLocated within an area of 157 acres (64 hectares), Mysore Zoo is the second most visited place in Mysore after Mysore Palace. It is currently an abode to 1,450 specimens of animals and birds consisting of 168 species belonging to more than 25 countries.
\n\n\tThe Zoological Gardens is proud to have a collecting of big cats like Cheetah, Jaguar, Tiger, Lion and small cats like Leopard Cat, Jungle Cat, Common Palm Civet and Small Indian Civet. It is the only zoo in India to exhibit a Gorilla. Other Primates include Baboon, Capuchin Monkey, and Marmoset, a variety of Lemur, Chimpanzee and common Indian Langur.
\n\n\tThe Zoological Garden is also abode to large mammals like Elephants belonging to both Asiatic and African region, Black and White African Rhino, Gaur and Hippopotamus.
\n\n\tThe Zoological Gardens is also proud to own flightless birds like Emu, Rhea, Ostrich, and Cassowary. There is also a huge collection of Terrestrial birds, aquatic birds, deers, antelopes, ducks, and reptiles.
</string>

    <string name="gard_dandeli_national_park_desc">\tDandeli, a small sleepy town in the western ghats of North-West India in the state of Karnataka is really proud of beholding the magnanimous wild land under the tiger project.
\n\n\tThe Dandeli Wildlife Sanctuary what the name of the reserve is; actually locating in Uttarkannada district of Karnataka which is abundantly rich in wide varieties of flora and fauna. Being spread over an area of 834.16 sq.km, this reserve is reputed as the largest sanctuary in Karnataka. The sanctuary is also counted amongst the most attractive tourist spots in Karnataka.
\n\n\tNumerous tourists from Karnataka and all over the India come and visit the sanctuaries every year to witness the wildlife while having jungle safari, or from a boat. The calm and blissful serenity all across the reserve with a diversified varieties of floras and faunas are the added attraction to the area.
\n\n\tThe formation of Dandeli National Park is actually a joint venture with the adjoining Anshi National Park and together they were granted the status of Project Tiger Reserve. In the year January 2007, the area was together named as Ansheli Dandeli Tiger Reserve by including the area of 340 sq km. Today, the area of Dandeli National Park by adjoining the areas of Anshi National Park together with six other adjacent protected areas in the states of Goa and Maharashtra forms the most uninterrupted protected forest area of over 2,200 sq km.
\n\n\tThe area of Dandeli that exhibits the wide ranges of flora attraction is actually plush with the southern evergreen forest. The tourists can find wide ranges of plant life, magical herbs, and shrubs. Dominant species are Mango, Jamun, Hirda, Behda, Bamboo, Shrub, Teak, Jamba, Ficus, Herbs, Climber, Grass, and Fern can also be visible here to complement the captivating landscapes.
\n\n\tBy Air : Belgaum (110 km,), Hubli (75 km,) and Goa (150 km.), Bangalore (3481 km.)
\n\n\tBy Rail : Alnavar (32 km.) Londa (48 km.), Dharwad (57 km.), Karwar (117 km.) and Hubli
\n\n\tBy Road : Dandeli is well connected to Bangalore, Mumbai, Goa, Belgaum, Karwar and Dharwad and Hubli by road. Several buses ply to Dandeli every day. Pick up and drop facility from closest destination is available on request.
</string>

    // Water Falls Description
    <string name="water_jog_falls_desc">\tOne of the highest waterfalls in India Jog Falls is one of the major attractions in Karnataka. Created on Sharavathi River, Jog Falls is also known by alternative names of Gerusoppe Falls, Gersoppa Falls and Jogada Gundi.
\n\n\tJog is located in Shimoga District of Karnataka, 30 km away from Sagara, 104 km from Shimoga, and 379 km away from Bangalore.
\n\n\tJog Falls is formed by the Sharavathi River, gushing down from a height of 253 meters. The river originates at Ambuthirtha in Thirthahalli taluk, flows north-west through the Western Ghats forming the Jog Falls before joining the Arabian Sea at Honavar.
\n\n\tFor a Tour to Jog Falls, the best time to visit is between the months of August and December.
\n\n\tBy Air:The nearest airport is at Bangalore.
\n\n\tBy Rail :You can take a train to Sagara from Bangalore, from where you can get into buses to Jog.
\n\n\tBy Road: You can reach Jog Falls directly by availing of buses to Jog from Bangalore. Alternatively, from Bangalore you can take a bus to Sagara, from where local bus to Jog is available.
</string>

    <string name="water_gokak_falls_desc">\tGokak falls is a waterfall known for its beauty. It is at a distance of 60 Kms from Belgaum and 10 kms from Gokak town. Located right on the main road is a celebrated tourist center in the district. This falls has a height of about 170 feet.
\n\n\tThe river Ghataprabha after winding a course of a long route takes a leap of 52 meters, over a rocky bed 170 feet down. The falls is famous for its spread and shape.Except in width and colour of the water, the general features of the fall, its height, shape and rapidity above are much like those of ” Niagara”.
\n\n\tThe waterfall is horse shoe shaped at the crest, with a flood breadth of 177 metres (580 ft). During rainy season the thick reddish brown water sweeps far over the brink of the cliff with a dull roar that can be heard from some distance.
\n\n\tElectricity was generated here for the first time in the country in 1887. The generating station can be reached on the ropeway. Recommended only for the extra courageous! A walk down either bank of the rocky gorge rewards you with ancient Chalukyan monuments waiting to be explored.
\n\n\tGokak gets its name due to the Goki trees found in abundance in these areas. July to September is the best season to visit the place.
\n\n\tIt is 10 kms from Gokak falls there is a village named Godachinamalki a trek of 2 Kms from here takes you  to a beautiful falls the stream flows in a slow rhythm until the first drop of about 70 feet as one treks to the spot, one comes across a long line of tiny falls that add up to make the big jump.
\n\n\tThe area being a rocky bed facilitates the creation of numerous lovely cascades to give the look of a royal bath in a palace complex.
\n\n\tThe main falls dips again a little further by another 50 feet before joining the Ghataprabha. This is truly rejuvenating falls, unspoilt and devoid of noisy crowds.
</string>

    <string name="water_godchina_malki_falls_desc">\tThe Godachinmalki Falls is a waterfall located on Markandeya river in Belgaum district, Gokak Taluk, Karnataka, India. It is 15 kilometers away from Gokak and 40 kms from Belgaum. It is located in a deep green valley.
\n\n\tGodachinmalki falls, also known as Markandeya falls, is located in a rugged valley, which is approachable from Godachinamalaki village by walking as well as by vehicle through an irregular forest route for about 2 kilometers and there are two routes to reach the falls from Godachinamalki, one is vai Malebail road by crossing bridge at godachinamalki and another one is vai Gurusiddeshwar Temple(Hatti Siddeshwar). It can also be reached from Nirvaneshwara Matha near Yogikolla, only by foot.
\n\n\tTo reach Godachinamalki Falls from Belgaum vai Ankalagi, Pachhapur and Mavanur, frequent bus facility is available from Belgaum and Gokak and nearest railway station is Pachhapur, which is about 8 kilometers and good train facility is available from Belgaum to Miraj, all most all trains stops in Pachhapur railway station . There are actually two falls formed here. The Markandeya river takes a first fall from a height of about 25 metres and flows into a rocky valley. After a short distance from the rocky valley, it takes the second fall from a height of about 20 metres. Within 10 km distance Gokak falls is located from Godachinamalki vai Melmanahatti and Maradimath. Later Markandeya river joins Ghataprabha river near Gokak. Within a 6 km radius there are two dams; one built across Ghataprabha river (Hidkal dam) and another one (Shirur Dam) across Markandeya river.
\n\n\tBest time for visiting this place is during the month of July-October (Rainy Season). There is no entry fees. There are no specific timings, a daytime visit in recommended.
</string>

    <string name="water_abbey_falls_desc">\tIf your idea of enjoying the monsoon is dancing in the rain, you ought to do so in the most natural setting possible. Being amidst the lush green environs of the scenic Abbey Falls can only add to the spectacle of monsoon and make you literally dance in joy. As one of Karnatakas amazing natural attractions, Abbey Falls in Coorg is a destination that you just cannot miss exploring during the monsoon. But this doesnt mean that its not worth visiting in the other seasons. After all, as they say, a thing of beauty is a joy forever.
\n\n\tNestled near Madikeri, Abbey Falls stands surrounded by a blanket of greenery. It is also known as Abbi Falls. To reach the waterfall, you will have to drive up to its entrance and then cover a short distance on foot.
\n\n\tAs you make your way to the waterfall, you will be greeted by lush plantations of spice and coffee. The roar of the water along with the aroma of the plantations is a delight in itself. The brilliant view of the waterfall from the hanging bridge running opposite to the waterfall is a sight to cherish. Guarded by tall trees with pepper vines for a company, Abbey Falls sparkles as if a stream of white pearls is running down a green wall at a great speed. But if you happen to be standing on the hanging bridge right after the monsoons, the voluminous waterfall will leave you soaked by its spray of water.
\n\n\tA number of small streams come together to form the sizzling cascade at Abbey Falls. The cascade gushes down a height of 70 feet to form a pool below that joins the River Cauvery. During the monsoon season, as the streams widen and the level of water increases, the rush down the cascade becomes thicker and lovelier to watch.
\n\n\tSince the Abbey Falls is at its peak form during the monsoon season, it is the best time to experience its beauty. So, July to October is the ideal time to plan a trip to the Abbey Falls. But if you want to avoid the rains, you can plan your trip at any time of the year.
\n\n\tIf you are planning to spend a couple of hours at the spot, you need to carry some light food items with you. There is no food stall located near the Abbey Falls. But on the way to the waterfall, you will come across a few roadside stalls selling tea, water, and snacks.
</string>

    <string name="water_barachukki_falls_desc">\tBarachukki and Gaganachukki are two waterfalls situated near the island town of Shivanasamudra in the Mandya district of Karnataka.
\n\n\tThe waterfalls are created by river Cauvery that runs down a 75 metre gorge before it divides into two branches that flow around the island of Shivanasamudra. The two branches (eastern and western branches) flow through deep ravines on either side of the island before plunging in two different places a few kilometres apart to form the Barachukki and Gaganachukki waterfalls.
\n\n\tThe waterfalls are located at a distance of about 139 km from Bangalore and about 60 km from Mysore.
\n\n\tThe eastern branch of the waterfall is known as Barachukki while the western branch is known as Gaganachukki. Barachukki and Gaganachukki waterfalls are together known as the Shivanasamudra Falls.
\n\n\tShivanasamudra literally means Shivas Sea. These two waterfalls are considered to be among the best 100 waterfalls of the world.
</string>

    <string name="water_benne_hole_falls_desc">\tBenne Hole Falls is one of the most spectacular waterfalls in North Karnataka. North Karnataka is said to have a number of waterfalls and one such picturesque waterfall is Benne Hole waterfalls. The name Benne Hole is because of the white creamy look of the waterfall. In Kannada, Benne is butter and hole refer to big stream, hence the name.
\n\n\tThe waterfall is formed by the tributary of the river Aghanashini, which flows through the dense forests of the Devimane Ghats region in the Western Ghats. The waterfall falls from a height of 200ft forming an alluring treat to ones eye.
\n\n\tBenne Hole Falls is known for trekking and the 2km trek to the top of falls is both arduous and a herculean task. One has to be adept and know the intricacies of trekking to reach the top. The view from the top of the falls is breathtaking and worth the hardships faced during the trek. Along with trekking, the tourist also can look out for some exotic birds. Some of the exotic birds found in Benne Hole waterfall area are grey jungle fowl, wooly necked stork, jungle owlet, coppersmith barbet, orange minivet, black headed oriole, common kestrel and plum-headed parakeet.
\n\n\tThe waterfall is located at about 26 kms from Sirsi. One has to first reach a village called Kasage, which is about 21 kms from Sirsi and from there the falls are about 5 kms away. The first 3 kms can be covered by jeep and next 2 kms by walk.
    </string>

    <string name="water_chunchanakatte_falls_desc">\tChunchanakatte Falls is part of the river Kaveri, Krishnaraja Nagar taluk of Mysore district. It is famous for the Kodanda Rama temple on the banks. It is believed that Goddess Sita took a bath in this holy waters at Dhanuskoti thus rendering a turmeric tinge to the water.
\n\n\tBrahma Rathotsava (car festival) is held on January 15th of every year. A holy dip in the river could be considered but one must take caution of the high current during monsoons. A big cattle festival is held during August.
\n\n\tBesides the picturesque falls, this place boasts of greenery and migratory birds. There is an Hydral power station nearby. The power plant was started in 1994 and completed (two units) in 1998. The power station has a capacity of 18 MW (9 MW each).
\n\n\tBest time to visit this falls is during January-February.Only road transport is possible. Private and Government transport is available to Chunchanakatte from K.R.Nagar.
\n\n\tNearest Railway Station: Mysore.
\n\n\tNearest Airport: Mysore Airport, Bangalore International Airport.
\n\n\tBy Road: From Bangalore 140 km, Mysore 54 km, K.R.Nagar 14 km.</string>

    <string name="water_kalhatti_giri_falls_desc">\tKalhatti Giri Falls (Kalahasti Falls) is in Chikmagalur district at Kallathipura in Karnataka.  The waterfall is in an elegant location and is a beautiful cascading waterfall amidst the luscious greenery. The waterfall from the Chandra Drona hills around 122 meters height above.
\n\n\tThe fall is in the front of Veerabhadreshwara temple dedicated to Lord Shiva. The Kemmangundi hill station is around 10km from the waterfall. The waterfall is surrounded by captivating valleys and gardens, which is indeed a visual treat to visitors.
\n\n\tIt is believed that Saint Agastya did pray here for a long time. The temple dedicated to Lord Shiva, the Veerabhadreshwara temple was supposed to be built during the Vijayanagara times.
\n\n\tThe temple contains three stone carvings of elephants at the entrance which depicts the Vijayanagara architecture. The cascading waterfall falls over these three elephants always. The people believe that the water is sacred and can cure many diseases.
\n\n\tLord Veerabhadrashwara temple celebrates the annual fair every March-April which is visited by many pilgrims and lasts for three days.
\n\n\tBy Road: Birur in Chikmagalur is the nearest station to the waterfalls. Birur is well connected to Bangalore and other places via Road. Bangalore is 245 km from Kalahtta Giri waterfalls and Mangalore is 150 km.
\n\n\tBy Rail: The nearest railway station is Birur. From Birur one can hire a taxi or auto rickshaw as it takes 30 mins. Birur is connected to Shimoga, Bangalore etc. by train.
\n\n\tBy Air: Mangalore is the nearest airport to Kalahatta Giri waterfalls around 180 km. From the airport one can take up buses or ca to reach the waterfall.
</string>

    <string name="water_sathodi_falls_desc">\tSathodi Falls is a wonderful and picturesque rectangular shaped waterfall in the Uttara Kannada region in Yellapur district. The place is less packed with tourists, but indeed a beautiful waterfall to sight. The water falls from a height of 15m and forms a pool beneath. The stream of water contains a jumble of rocks and sometimes impossible to approach Sathodi Falls.
\n\n\tIn between the bushes and the rocky terrain, there are small pathways leading to the waterfalls. The water flow is formed by the union of many other rivers that flow to Kallarmane Ghat, in Uttara Kannada region. The water that forms the waterfalls then flows into the River Kali through the Dam Kodasalli. The waterfall is found amidst the Ghats and the evergreen forests that truly bring out the marvelous beauty of the waterfall. Sathodi Falls is not very approachable because of the rocks.
\n\n\tSathodi Falls is a wonderful and picturesque rectangular shaped waterfall in the Uttara Kannada region in Yellapur district. The place is less packed with tourists, but indeed a beautiful waterfall to sight. The water falls from a height of 15m and forms a pool beneath. The stream of water contains a jumble of rocks and sometimes impossible to approach Sathodi Falls.
\n\n\tIn between the bushes and the rocky terrain, there are small pathways leading to the waterfalls. The water flow is formed by the union of many other rivers that flow to Kallarmane Ghat, in Uttara Kannada region. The water that forms the waterfalls then flows into the River Kali through the Dam Kodasalli. The waterfall is found amidst the Ghats and the evergreen forests that truly bring out the marvelous beauty of the waterfall. Sathodi Falls is not very approachable because of the rocks.
\n\n\tSathodi Falls is the embodiment of natural beauty that is admired by many. The rock formations around the waterfalls form a natural enclosure with the bountiful greenery and the clear and crystal water below. The waterfall has water all-around the year. Being fed by multiple tributaries the waterfall always has water. The water body formed below is ideal for a dip. One can enjoy the cool waters and swim through the clear water. The serene place is ideal for a picnic.
\n\n\tBy Road: Yellapur (32km) is the closest destination to Sathodi Falls. From Bangalore (423 km) one can hire a cab or even take up KSRTC buses to reach Yellapur and from Yellapur tourists can hire an auto or a cab to reach the waterfalls.
\n\n\tBy Air: Hubli (68km) is the nearest airport to Yellapur. Hubli is connected to major cities like Bangalore and Mysore. From Hubli, one can hire a taxi or take up a bus to reach Yellapur and then to Sathodi Falls.
\n\n\tBy Train: Hubli (68km) is the nearest railway station to Yellapur. From Yellapur one can take up a bus or taxi to reach the waterfall.
</string>

    <string name="water_sural_falls_desc">\tSural Falls is one of the most amazing natural sights in Karnataka. The beautiful waterfall is located at a distance of 32 km from Khanapur in the Belgaum district of Karnataka. Nestled amongst the greenery of the Western Ghats the picturesque waterfall is also known as ‘Venezuela of Karnataka. The waterfall is about 300 feet deep and presents an impressive sight all year round.
\n\n\tSural Falls is also one of the most famous trekking routes of Karnataka. The pristine beauty of the waterfall and the splendid forest cover makes it an ideal trekking destination.
\n\n\tSural Falls attracts visitors throughout the year for its splendid beauty. However, it holds special attraction for the trekkers and nature lovers. It is one of the most famous treks of the Kankumbi forest region. The trek begins at Kalsa in Karnataka. It runs through the rocky bed of Kalsa stream and crosses the majestic Kalsa waterfall before reaching the Sural Falls. The trek culminates on reaching the Sural Valley after crossing the picturesque waterfall.
\n\n\tThough the waterfall can be visited throughout the year, the best time to visit it is during the moderate monsoon. The deep waterfall becomes a lovely sight during the rainy season.
\n\n\tThe easiest way to reach Sural Falls is to reach Belgaum. Belgaum is easily accessible by several means of transport. The place can be reached by road, air and rail transport from various parts of the country.
\n\n\tBy Road: Belgaum has a very well connected road network. Four national highways pass through Belgaum and connect it to Maharashtra, Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu. Buses run by the North West Karnataka Road Transport Corporation (NWKRTC) connect Belgaum to other corners of the state. There are a few private buses that carry passengers to Belgaum from other cities and towns of Karnataka.
\n\n\tBy Air: The Belgaum Airport has been serving the city for many decades now. There are flights connecting Belgaum to Bangalore.
\n\n\tBy Train: Belgaum has one of the oldest railway stations in the region. The rail network connects Belgaum to several other places within and outside Karnataka. There are trains that connect Belgaum to Mysore, Bangalore, Pune, Goa, Mumbai, New Delhi, Chennai and several other places.
</string>

    <string name="water_vibhooti_falls_desc">\tVibhooti Falls is one of the many waterfalls in the Western Ghats. Surrounded by large rocks and limestone deposits, the waterfall is a picturesque spot. The water flows in steps that make it the ideal refuge spot for hot summers.
\n\n\tSet about 50 kilometers from Sirsi in North Kanara, the waterfall gets its name from the limestone rock found in the area. Vibhooti also translates to mean ash. According to local legends, the waterfall was formed when ashes from the burning of Basmasur had washed away. It is also known as the Mabgi Falls because of its proximity to a village by the same name.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit the waterfall is between October and March. At this time the water levels are at their highest and gush over the rocks.
\n\n\tBy Road: The Vibhooti Falls are about 400kms away from Bangalore and 50kms from Sirsi. KSRTC buses and private taxis ply regularly between Sirsi and the Vaddi cross. From here, the Waterfall is a short walk away.
\n\n\tBy Rail: Sirsi is the closest railway station to the Vibhooti Falls. The station is around 44 kilometers.
\n\n\tBy Air: At a distance of 252km, the Mangalore International Airport is the closest airport.
</string>

    <string name="water_unchalli_falls_desc">\tThe picturesque Unchalli Falls close by Uttara Kannada is famous for its Unchalli (Lushington) Falls was discovered by J.D. Lushington in 1845, a district collector of the British Government. Aghanashini river creates this water cascade which screams down from a height of about 450 feet.
\n\n\tUnchalli falls is near Yellapur (19 km) in Uttara Kannada. This is also known as Mini Niagara or  Keppa Falls is another name for its unique sound. Cascading from a height of 170 feet, it is famous for its spread and shape. This falls must be visited in July-August when it will be in full bloom.
\n\n\tTrekking 5 km from the Heggarne village along the dense forests can be an exciting experience. The steep mountain slopes and tracks,  deep gorges, chilly breeze and the amazing flora and the rare avian species accompany you until you reach the roaring Unchali Falls plummeting down.
\n\n\tBy Road: Siddapura Taluk in North Kanara by road or From Bangalore 400 kms, Sirsi 25 kms.
\n\n\tBy Train: Nearest railway station Sirsi town.
\n\n\tBy Air: Nearest Airport Goa Dabolim Airport.</string>

    <string name="water_almatti_dam_desc">\tThe Almatti Dam is in a Bijapur, a small town Northern Karnataka,  and is built across the Krishna river. The construction was done in 2005, so it is a relatively new dam. It is the main reservoir of the Upper Krishna Irrigation Project and it uses Kaplan Turbines.
\n\n\tWater is released into the Narayanpur reservoir once it uses it for power generation and serves the irrigation requirements.  The height was increased by 10 meters in this dam after the Supreme Court ordered to do so.
\n\n\tThere are about seven terrace gardens that have been built as a picnic spot in Almatti dam area. Musical fountains, stagnant fountains, boating facilities etc. have been set up here for people who wish to visit it. This makes it a great tourist attraction. There is a garden named ‘Rock Hill situated on one of side of this Dam. It also has an artificial forest with ceramic wild animals.
</string>

    <string name="water_tungabhadra_dam_desc">\tThe Tungabhadra Dam or TB Dam also is known as Pampa Sagar, is a reservoir constructed across the Tungabhadra River a tributary of the Krishna River. The dam Located almost 20 kilometers south-west of Hampi town, in Munirabad, Koppal district in the town Hospet in Karnataka. Tungabhadra Dam looks extremely beautiful at the sunset with water showing you how it cools the suns hotness and the Dams green lights start engulfing the darkness again.
\n\n\tConstruction began in 1949 and completed by 1953 the Dam total length is 2,449 m (8,035 ft) and height is 49.50 m (162 ft) from the deepest foundation with total Spillway capacity 650,000 cusecs. It has been built by cement and granite. Left of it two barrages have been con¬structed (one earthen and another of stone and surkhi). The reservoir spreads over 378 sq. km. of area with a storage capacity of 4 lakh hectares.
\n\n\tThe dam serves multiple functions as it controls irrigation, electricity generation, flood control and much more. Today it is a joint project between the states of Andhra Pradesh and Karnataka, and serves purposes of functionality and attracts tourists from across India as well. For those visiting for tourism, the views from atop this reservoir are simply magnificent, and a simple walk along the river is sure to please even the toughest critics. A hydroelectric project of the dam is famous and become a new lifeline of State of Karnataka.
\n\n\tPower houses-three powerhouses have been constructed under the project. First of these lies on the left side at Munirabad (Karnataka) with an installed capacity of 27 MW. The second powerhouse at Hospet has eight generating units of 9 m w each (total capacity 72 MW). The third powerhouse has been built near Hampi along the canal with an installed capacity of 27 MW. This total of 126 MW of electricity is utilized in irrigation and development of small and cottage industries.
\n\n\tTungabhadra High-Level Canal with 196 km length provides irrigation to 1.82 lakh hec¬tares of land in Bellary and Anantapur districts. Tungabhadra project is mainly an irrigation project which has helped in augmenting the area under cotton, groundnut, rice, sugarcane, jowar, and other crops.
</string>

    <string name="water_krs_dam_desc">\tThe Krishna Raja Sagara Dam, popularly known as KRS Dam, is built on the river Kaveri and its tributaries, Hemavathi and Lakshmana Theertha. The KRS Dam and the ornamental garden, Brindavan Gardens, attached to the dam are one of the most visited tourist spots in Mysore. The dam was planned and built over a hundred years ago with traditional materials and techniques. Maharaja Nalwadi Krishnaraja Wadiyar IV had the dam constructed to help the people of the kingdom during a severe drought. Planned by Sir M Visvesvaraya, the chief engineer of Mysore, KRS Dam was the first dam to install automated crest gates. The dam is still a major source of drinking water for people and provides irrigation in Mandya, Mysore and Bangalore.
\n\n\tThe construction of the Krishna Raja Sagar Dam, which would provide drinking water and be a source of irrigation, started in November 1911. Over 10,000 workers were employed for the construction of KRS dam in the Kannambadi village. According to the initial plan, the gravity dam was to be 194-feet high with the capacity to hold 41,500,000,000 cu ft (1.18 km3) of water. But this plan had to be dropped and the structure that stands today is 131 feet high with a total capacity to hold 1,368,847,000 m3 of water.
\n\n\tThe best time to visit KRS Dam is during or after the monsoon season (June to August). Due to heavy rainfall, the water level of the dam increases and sometimes the water gushes out of the gates as they automatically open on reaching 124 feet.
\n\n\tLocated just 24 km away from Mysore, KRS Dam can be easily visited through city buses. These buses from the city bus stand are available to drop one directly near KRS Dam. If you are coming from the railway station, you can either take the auto-rickshaws or state-owned buses. It will take a few hours to reach the KRS dam.
\n\n\tIt is 24 km from Mysore. It is 143.5 km away from Bangalore. It is 480.3 km away from Chennai. It is located 2.2 km from Venugopala Swamy Temple.
</string>

    <string name="water_hidkal_dam_desc">\tRaja Lakhamagouda dam, also known as Hidkal dam, is a dam constructed across the Ghataprabha River in the Krishna River basin. It is situated at Hidkal village in Hukkeri Taluk of Belagavi district in North Karnataka, India.
\n\n\tThe dam with the height of 62.48 metres and 10 Vertical Crest Gates, impounds a large reservoir with a gross surface area of 63.38 Square kilometres, and storage capacity of 51.16 Tmcft.
\n\n\tIt is an earthen and masonry dam which caters to the Irrigation needs for over 8,20,000 acres, and Hydel power generation.
\n\n\tIt is constructed as a part of the Ghataprabha Irrigation project which was completed in three phases and finished in 2009. The dam is named after Raja Lakhamagouda Sardesai, philanthropist and Zamindar of Vantamuri.
</string>

</resources>